Happy Watching
words prediction reminder.
A prediction .
" Sparta will fall "
"All Greeks will fall . "
" And Persian Fire will destroy Athens . "
" Because Athens is
heap of stones , wood, cloth and ashes. "
" As the dust , the city is also
will be gone by the wind. "
" Only people of Athens will be safe."
" And the fate of the world is in their hands. "
" And only the great ocean liner
can save them. "
" Wooden Ships ...."
" ... And the blood wave Warrior . "
300 : THE RESURRECTION OF AN EMPIRE
Leonidas , my husband ....
Leonidas , King of you ....
Leonidas and 300 Warrior suicide has died.
Greek Men and women can not afford
repay the sacrifice of the Spartans .
War is not their field.
But Leonidas will sacrifice for them .
Greek Demi promise of success .
it is our enemies who receive
freedom from the fire of war .
coming King Darius had
grab our land .
Ten years ago when we were all young ....
Before the bitterness of this war
forcing our children to become fighters ....
Ten years ago ,
This war started ....
.... like any other battle .
the fight.
Marathon.
Persian King Darius ....
.... annoyed with Greek independence .
He came to Greece to conquer us .
He landed at Marathon.
Joint army of more than
total defense greece , 3 compared with 1 .
When dawn , Athens Team despair
do the unprecedented - thought ...
They attacked .
They attacked Team Persian fatigue ....
When they color=#FFFF00>  mooring
after months - months sailing in the ocean .
They attack before the Persian managed to build brand
and dividing the weapon on their team .
Who planners to this great strategy
A greek warrior who
not so known .
He is known as ....
Themistokles .
He has given attack
surprise over the Persian troops .
All hope to win has arrived.
Thousands Persian fighters dead .
Only the loss of hundreds of Greek fighters .
all for one idea ,
Greek independence ....
Experiment Athens called " Democracy " .
Does the idea should be pursued ?
Is it worth all this sacrifice ?
Themistokles let
Darius to decide.
turmoil ....
Emerging  a chance .
Themistokles exploit .
An advantage of the echo
for hundreds of years .
An advantage of the lifting
subordinate status of hero ....
.... To be a source of political power in Athens .
No
An advantage of
has made Themistokles as legends.
But while praise and
success came to him ....
Themistokles understand in his heart
that he had made ??a mistake .
Prince Darius, Xerxes will
determine the fate of them .
Themistokles realizes that he must kill the child.
large error will haunt him forever .
light Themistokles
fire battle the Persians ....
ended with the team
bring fire into the heart of the Greek people .
When the wise king
lay waiting for death ....
Whole Counsel General and the best
called to his side .
But nothing is more powerful than
Naval commander , Artemisia .
violence covered by her beauty.
Her beauty is comparable to
loyalty to the King .
Darius loves the Artemisia
compared with other officials ....
Because he has given
many victories on the battlefield.
Artemisia is best fighters ....
never owned even by
own son , Xerxes .
're very good , my daughter ....
Princess ....
.... dear .
Dad.
Xerxes .
Do you repeat your father's fault .
Forget everything about Greece .
The gods are
capable of defeating them .
The gods  .
For seven days of mourning Xerxes ....
.... clouded by grief .
On day eight , Artemisia whisper
seeds of hatred that possess him.
is not your father's words are a reminder ....
Unless color=#FFFF00>
Only god can beat the Greeks ?
You'll be the king of the gods.
Artemisia gathered monks , witches ....
astrologers from across the Imperial territories .
They rub the young King ....
Cimmerian ancient ingredient .
and send it to the desert ....
When he encounters suffering,
heat and thirst ....
He found a cave meditating .
Xerxes has come to evil
with an empty soul ....
Where damned creatures inhabit
at the corner of the human heart .
And in the Darkness ...
He surrendered completely ....
to strength so bad .
So melt , until no more
Xerxes the humanity in themselves .
smoldering eyes light up like a rock .
He has been refined throughout.
Xerxes reborn as a god .
Artemisia  not believe anyone.
kegalapan Night ....
Palace has been cleared of all allies of Xerxes .
Everyone belief ....
Everyone who has raised her ....
All advisers who once helped him ....
.... has been a victim of terror.
And when the king of the gods stand
in front of people ....
Artemisia saw
success of the game.
To be successful ....
sake of revenge ...
.... War
War
War has come to Greece ...
comprising millions of very strong fighter .
Themistokles  That task ,
Heroes battle of Marathon ....
to finish
what he started.
quiet!
We must persuade Xerxes
Cowards !
Athens city coward!
- shut up !
- You have to close your mouth!
I will kill you!
Ones to Sparta
hell with the well-built muscular fighters
- Quiet !
- Quiet for Heroes Marathon
This color="#FFFF00">
Shut all !
By Themistokles
upcoming Persian attacks
From the north and south .
We should negotiate for a ceasefire.
Yes ! Yes ! we should consult
Consult with tyranny ?
Give me examples of the benefits for the country.
He's right.
We must unite .
Friend countrymen ....
We can only assess future
of our suffering in the past.
Many of you here
have fought with me in Marathon ....
For those who have
experience how cruel sense of a war ....
So you know how
establish true peace .
Do not be fooled!
Xerxes, Darius Prince
a crafty person .
Here, Now ....
We have to make choices.
We fight for Greek or not ?
Argos ....
Corinth ....
Megara ....
Athens .
Even color=#FFFF00> <font Spartans will not be able
against Persia alone .
We must come together as One Nation
One Nation .
or we will be destroyed by
desire ourselves.
Point ship we need
in defense of Greece .
Themistokles need more ships
of our city .
She also require our children to fight.
How to Sparta
Submit all ships
we have toward the northern shores of Euboea .
I would go to for help
from the great state of Sparta .
Still no news from
you send messengers to Sparta.
King Leonidas may
offended on tawaranmu .
Maybe I who should progress
To Sparta and destroy it.
Remember ....
When a King who loved like me ....
Many things can be achieved .
They will bow to my power.
Athens sought to combine strength .
That's nothing more than a bunch of small ships.
Having dominated the waters ,
will i bring the whole team to the mainland .
I will remind the Greek coward that
we have not forgotten their humiliation .
Each and feed his horse.
I'd better go alone.
Sparta color=#FFFF00>
Sparta Policy .
Themistokles .
your policy serpent .
What made you go into this South
I want to find Leonidas to remind
Persian troops who are moving here.
're late .
Bearing Persian message
conditions apply to Leonidas .
Deals symbolic of the state.
Sparta
Know this well - good .
Sparta .... That is the best time
best performance that should be remembered ....
the time ....
When he fought wholeheartedly
Sparta liberation ....
And fall on the battlefield ...
In Victory !
Now ....
Who was willing to die on the side of our king
Themistokles .
You have come from afar to
witness a real man practice .
Queen Gorgo .
should not train them
living on the side of the king ?
new era has arrived, Gorgo .
Soon they will be
Mystical and rise up against tyranny .
That sounds like a threat .
not.
An opportunity to join with the rest of
Greece and fight the tyranny of the lo .. , ..
Unless you associate with Xerxes and Leonidas .
no partner .
Xerxes messenger carriers have ....
He color=#FFFF00> <font rude and disrespectful ,
he did not know that ....
threat to Thebes and Athens
not occur here .
This birthplace of the world's best warriors .
place where the king
fought tooth and nail by all citizens.
Xerxes messenger carriers do not understand that
This place is not like other Greek cities .
This Sparta.
was clear for messenger
Sparta would not bow .
very clear .
Now , Leonidas talks
the oracle about his war plans .
Festival carnea one - the only thing that can stop us .
course oracle
recommend that we fight.
Means I have come just in time.
I lead the Fleet
association representing Greece .
I want to Sparta to join with me.
Point Kapalmu , Gorgo .
I will make sure that Xerxes
never crosses the Aegean .
You will never be able to ship Sparta.
We're not interested in Greek society .
That's your dream , Themistokles ,
Not our dream .
What I care about nothing but independence Sparta.
sheperd will send you out .
Funny if you're proud of kemerdekaanmu
in this separation .
Independence wisely ....
been chosen to fight for it .
My queen .
Are Spartans will join in our war
Looks like Persian  offer something
can not be rejected by the Spartans .
What is it?
beautiful death .
They say that you are a prisoner of the bravest .
They said you were a prostitute from the Northeast .
You're not that smart.
your Commander Greeks.
Just like me .
You color=#FFFF00> <font Persian warrior by
command of a Greek woman
Yes, Brother, I'm of Greek descent ...
And Greek blood flow in nadiku .
But my heart ....
.... Owned Persia.
few hours away ....
Greek fleet would helter - poranda .
What our god king
The Spartans were feared and
Nothing to fear .
Only King Leonidas and 300
personal warrior going into battle .
They would lose a moment.
you.
Do you agree ?
They will all perish .
Keyakinanmu gave me a very deep impression .
Very strange for Caregivers ship ....
not lose sight
when I asked him .
Maybe just irreverent nature .
But hands can not lie .
can reveal imperfections Hand
and defects in character .
You see, not enough hands rough
to work on this ship .
I know all my carriers .
Can you tell me,
why I did not recognize you ?
Excuse me, Commander .
Let me introduce myself.
Catch spies .
Coward .
storm here soon.
This is just bad weather Greece .
Themistokles .
Enter color=#FFFF00>
Calisto .
What we discuss here can not be duplicated.
case anywhere .
my Prince never made ??war ....
But you can believe it.
right.
Tell me.
A leading Greek Women
entire fleet of Xerxes heading south.
Artemisia .
I recognize it.
Artemisia color=#FFFF00> <font a trained killer
with a fleet of exceptional ability ....
thirst for revenge He .
Apparently color=#FFFF00> <font whole family killed
by the Greek government .
I've heard that story .
At that time, the government
not forgive anyone.
According to Acts , they were raped repeatedly
and kill the entire family.
Then they destroy it.
After years - years
detained by Greek Ship son ....
He dumped and left to die ....
Then he discovered in agony
by a Persian messenger .
Artemisia swore he would return to Greece ....
When he can see the destruction.
She was treated , given clothes and a trained
the best warriors the Persians ....
As none can match the
ability of fencing .
great King Darius was impressed by his loyalty.
And he immediately led his own army .
He has sold his soul to death.
It is said
I sold my soul to the Greek .
What do you think ?
- I ?
- Yes .
You color=#FFFF00>
I'm ready to fight .
I love it.
She reminded me of you.
- We need a team as much as possible .
- He's still young.
Many younger children are able to defend
our country , Dad.
Enough
're leaders and we will not discuss them further .
Themistokles , I've
learn about your plans .. , ..
And daratku team will arrive on the second day .
troops are needed.
I can ensure it .
And there's bad news .
Leonidas moved north towards the gates of hell .
Bad news ? With a team of sparta
at the gates of hell ...
we have ensured victory .
If he leads the team.
between predictor and carnea ....
Leonidas moving
Thermopylae with only 300 soldiers.
Defence between Athens and maximum destruction ..
Only Leonidas and 300 Spartan soldiers .
seasoned warrior I'll find them .
Sorting chain of command
between volunteers.
Good .
need time to teach strategies
on these farmers .
We gave them food ...
and awareness.
Anything else?
been nice if they could account
brandish swords .
sacred to me.
sucks
dad know you're here ?
No, sir .
And also shield the sword
That 's atukku .
My mother gave it to me  this morning.
When he bless you ?
Yes , sir.
He even sharpen your sword .
father complete surprise
for our enemies tomorrow .
I choose to fight here .
Now .
Welcome Kapalku .
're going to fight there.
Yes , sir.
number of ships we have 50 .
Persian fleet amounted to nearly thousands of Ships.
we ship handful .
Ships color=#FFFF00> <font we not stay
Persian fleet of giant ships .
We have the advantage , speed and cunning .
another city just to send some ships .
course , the rest will be sent to Athens.
We got reports of a small fleet of Persia ....
.... Congratulations from storms across the Straits .
If the weather is good , we attack them after dawn .
early Greek victory .
The gods give us the opportunity to ....
Persian Maim and strengthen the spirit of Greece.
Removal seductive .
We set the rules of the battle plan .
As the sun sank today,
we headed for the main Persian fleet .
We attack them in open water
without limitation the battlefield.
assault ship with thousands of
Our fleet now same name by committing suicide .
That fits with my plans .
Look at their Marine forces .
their fleet only a small threat .
I need reps, Artaphernes .
Anyone who can prove
greatness will be wakilku .
Bandari General to lead the first attack .
Bandari
Commander .
I invite you color=#FFFF00> <font lead
Our first attack .
guarantee what I can
you will give me victory
I will win or die .
Good .
And what arahanmu
shame greek team
and destroy their ship .
They all will I destroy .
Brothers .
Realize color=#FFFF00>
Look deep into your soul .
Today will test your courage .
Even in the middle of the battle ....
You need a reason to keep fighting ....
If you think going to give up ....
's only one thing you have to do ....
By looking good man who fought at your side .
This "excuse " to fight .
This color=#FFFF00>
bond that can not be separated ....
stronger with great battles .
You never this close compared with
those who fight with you.
no more noble reason ....
Besides fighting for their
willing to sacrifice for you .
Strive color=#FFFF00>
Fight for your brothers in arms
Fight for your family
Above all, strive for the Greek
Yes
There is only one reason to keep
when the battle began.
What is it?
Do not killed on the first day .
That goes for all of you.
strong Persian ships in the front ....
But the middle weak
We color=#FFFF00>
Now!
Attack !
Crush them !
Archer , now!
back!
Now!
Crush them !
enemy Scouts are so creative .
their defensive circle
no room for us to attack .
We lost .
No, you're a loser .
Backward.
Let them win today .
I'm tired of kekalahanmu , Bandari .
these cuts will not be kubiarkan melambatku .
I trust you .
sword will be ready tomorrow morning.
Good, tomorrow you will be fighting with your father.
is not too bad for a bunch of farmers.
And poet and sculptor sculpture .
group never trained ....
able to defeat the enemy called great .
We need full strength
to battle tomorrow .
How much longer can we stop them ?
If my plans work ....
long enough for Sparta
want to join the Greek .
all !
Who wants to drink wine with me?
Report .
We are still calculating losses.
You have to understand, this is very difficult,
Sea conditions and darkness ....
hard earned ....
The report color=#FFFF00>
75 Shipwreck .
30 damaged but can be repaired .
20 ships to return after a few
weeks to be repaired in a safe berth .
the Greek fleet commander named Themistokles .
Yes , she Gen. Athens .
Apparently she did not stand a great king Darius .
Themistokles great notoriety on the battlefield.
More than can be
I convey to you.
Do you feel ridiculous ?
Are Winning is so hard to be reaped ?
Kekecewaanmu night stands to reason .
frustration.
frustration is not about defeat .
Total Ship damaged and boy
no means dead to me , no.
frustration ....
.... are they .
But I stood between 10 000 troops ..
.... I'm still alone .
I'm looking for someone to mendampingiku .
Who can I trust.
Tell me , General Kashani .
Are you that person?
you will achieve your victory
when this day is over .
I'll sure.
I hope so .
Fast Forward
Now !
Never lose them !
Greek fleet back.
He managed fishing rods
to the place he wanted.
Kashani great tactician .
I say about Themistokles .
Stone Edge
Stop ! Stop !
Stop !
Prepare yourselves!
What are you doing here ?
Responsibility man
protect family and country.
Who said that to you ?
My father color=#FFFF00>
You see how her elegant
Themistokles launched siasatnya
Why is it so hard for the victory achieved ?
- How to fix it my way ?
- Shut up .
You 'll send a message to me .
Now they will fear us !
Now they would be afraid of the Greek soldiers
He's right !
Fear Greek army
Fear sword
armor
Fear on love
the country greece
top of that ....
Fear of Independence
Yes
You do not scold the young .
He was under Komandoku .
anger kulimpahkan only my enemies .
Themistokles .
Artemisia ship docked in neutral waters .
He wants to meet with Themistokles .
How can you guarantee that
she will return safely ?
Win , A - the only honor for Artemisia now ....
When he saw the fleet you
shattered ...
sink to the bottom of the Aegean
and he can see you ....
Glued color=#FFFF00>
... when you're immersed in water depth .
Why do not you say since the beginning of
...
Welcome aboard sederhanaku .
We are honored by Your presence .
Kapalmu and yourself ....
.... deep enough to hurt .
You praise .
Follow along with us , a lot of things to be discussed .
you believe that the descendants of the Greek gods ?
I have heard that myth .
How about you?
whether there is god of seed
tenteraku say so and
based on a two-day battle ....
fabulosity in you following me there .
Now who praised
my carriers Son also said , you are the
Darius destroyed in Marathon.
Many horrific incident happened on that day.
It happened ten years ago ....
And the story of the war
often exaggerated - enlarge.
That move sure you remember .
I will do everything to defend Greece .
And I do anything to destroy it.
For a greek hero who died ,
You must kill a thousand Persian warriors .
Each ship kutenggelamkan ....
You have to sink a hundred Kapalku .
I can bear
defeat for weeks - weeks.
the months - months if necessary.
Total color=#FFFF00>
And I took kapalmu
valuable with the sword .
Also I shall seize the Greek independence .
You ask me to give up?
No.
I offer the opportunity to avoid
suffering and join with me.
I need a commander like you.
Look color=#FFFF00>
unruly ship .
Sparta Leonidas with 300 soldiers .
An insult ,
strongest government in the world ....
Facing such a small team .
I do not blame you , Themistokles .
're battling blood as Poseidon
nadimu flow .
No, I blame the Greek .
fussy bureaucrats working group
protect their political hideaway ....
With send you here to die .
And you choose to keep fighting .
There must be something ....
.... What ?
family in the state of Athens ....
.... The support you .
love is so strong .
Actually , I have no time for family .
I spent my whole life
with love sejatiku ....
.... Greek Fleet .
One - the only thing that I care about ....
prepare it to beat you .
It makes me happy ....
Knowing that you come this far for me ....
Forgetting color=#FFFF00>
By a promise that more satisfying .
Satisfaction with swords and meat ....
Death and life .
Anger ...
.... And sweat muscled .
true happiness ....
And the pain from within.
every night and Ahir back
with me every morning ....
Like when you hunuskan sword
to the heart of the enemy .
're fighting for liberation .
I offer independence without
consequence or responsibility .
Join with me ....
.... In my side .
breathe with me
as - if it were the last time.
Join with me ....
No.
're not gods.
You're a human being .
Be - careful with your sword .
You're not going to die tonight.
Guardian
rid of this vermin from kapalku
How ?
What have you learned?
Do Artemisia can be defeated ?
we encounter more ....
He will attack full force .
...
Survive ! Last!
Kerahkan my personal team .
- Retreat!
- Back up!
Themistokles !
In water
Archers ! To the deck , now!
Archer , onto the deck of the ship , now!
Hurry !
right side !
Arrow
Keep fighting, son .
Keep fighting !
Dig color=#FFFF00>
At the top!
Leave Ship
Death innocent .
responsible .
Themistokles saw the bodies of his men ....
Sink to the bottom of the Aegean with blood.
Do they sacrifice the egoannya
Or to make amends
her past in Marathon ?
How many warriors safe
if Themistokles kill Xerxes young
not convinced even himself .
My Friends .
We face the worst odds .
Together - equal .
Hear me, Themistokles .
You gotta fight ....
With double the strength tomorrow morning .
We will fight to work together .
No, son .
You gotta fight for both of us .
What did he say?
I'll tell when it's time , son.
calm .
body Temanilah father.
How many times do we have to
face a tragedy like this ?
much needed .
We sacrificed the lives of many young fighters .
you think I'm having fun with all this ?
Witness last breath of my friends
All widowed due to my decision ....
All children who grow up without a dad ....
.... it's all a result of my decision .
This color=#FFFF00>
So easy to spend a great soldier ....
Leaving color=#FFFF00> <font tenteraku see
best warriors of Sparta.
Take them untukmelalui
body - this body .
Let them see the effect
if against the king of the gods .
King Leonidas with
300 brave soldiers die ....
It is the best Greek warrior .
There will be no bold rebels
against our team .
Nothing could
Speeding stop Kekaisaranku .
Majesty.
you , take the sword of the deceased king of Athens .
Let them know that
I will come to them.
Let them know ....
Athens ...
they are very beautiful city ....
will vanish from history .
Themistokles
I bring a message of Thermopylae , that
Leonidas had been betrayed by the handicapped .
The Spartans have been attacked repeatedly .
Hell Gate has collapsed.
incredible sacrifice .
Now Greece has a Martyr .
Daxos ...
Spread the word about the gates of hell ....
to all cities, to all the villages .
Let color=#FFFF00>
But they 're dead.
They all .
Sacrifice Spartans will be our union .
go .
Move around the ship and
Our team at the hiding place of Salamis .
And you?
I'll pass the news from Daxos to Athens .
I was told that the defect is responsible
the defeat at the gates of hell .
He betrayed his country ....
Leaving color=#FFFF00>
And Persian convert to gold .
What is your name ....
traitor ....
Ephialtes of Trachis .
Should I wash this noble sword with blood.
're entitled to do .
Rupaku was not good at all.
What I had done, too bad .
Suppose your post .
I beg thee ....
and around Athens !
King of the gods will destroy this city !
What do you mean ?
Quiet all of you!
great sacrifice of Leonidas and the Spartans
not defeat.
That wonderful victory .
bold action and simple ....
will inspire
every city and unify the Greek
for one purpose ....
fight our common enemy !
And you ....
Bring this message to the king of the gods you.
We will deploy
Our ships are still there ...
and finish this battle in the bay of Salamis .
There will be a lot of death and destruction.
Yes , it's true.
Themistokles .
I came to talk to the Queen.
reminder to you, the Athens ...
You should be ready to face what is waiting for you.
I commiserate .
I can not change what has
Leonidas happened ....
But his sacrifice will not be forgotten .
Do not talk to me about sacrifice ....
and explain mean come, Athens .
I ask for help all over the navy Sparta.
All team and ship
can you lend .
Do pengorbananku not enough to
Greek peryatuan wish come on
Should I give the sword to my son ?
Our son
What would memuaskanmu
What pengorbananku by
ambitions were not enough, Themistokles
A king .
husband , father , brother .
Spartans will not give any support .
's yours.
treated vengeance.
words can be used as predictors of the memorial .
"All Greeks will fall "
" And Persian Fire will destroy Athens '
" Because Athens is
heap of stones , wood, cloth and ashes. "
" As the dust , the city is also
will be gone by the wind. "
" Only people of Athens will be safe."
" And the fate of the world
is in their hands. "
" Only people of Athens will be safe."
" And only the great wooden ship can
save them .
" Wooden Ships ... "
" .... and the mighty waves of blood . "
act stupid because we oppose .
Leonidas and his team
god will not stay .
Themistokles just cowards who do not use .
And now ....
Navy sad is not eligible
get our attention .
If "Coward " wants to join with me ....
We can help you color=#FFFF00>
my King .
servant carrying a message .
Greek Fleet  not have a defense ....
.... in the Bay of Salamis .
You just have to destroy them .
Who led the fleet
Themistokles from Athens .
Themistokles dead.
He's still alive .
I myself saw it.
Prepare color=#FFFF00>
We must attack it .
advice for you ....
Send us a team of researchers to
sure it is not a trap .
You dare to question my decision ?
he is the king of the gods.
Leonidas I, who defeated .
and I will destroy Athens .
I am your king !
Killing Leonidas and his army
just make them into martyrs .
When you destroy Athens ...
Just be like you smash
one - only the most valuable in the country.
I'm going to attack the Greek ....
With the entire fleet .
Artemisia .
Enough
Do not forget who
placing the crown on your head .
my King .
Sit and watch your gold throne
This battle in a safe place ...
.... which I have prepared for you .
In the distance there ....
We will witness the destruction of Athens .
Alone, we will face monsters
bring suffering to our state.
I pray Sparta
will help us this morning .
Maybe they feel
have enough help .
You disappoint us all .
- It's your fault , Themistokles .
- Without Sparta , we all just farmers.
We should negotiate with the Persian
as long as there is still a chance .
You're all right .
Yes , we brought the ship difficult to handle .
And, yes , we are just farmers.
We color=#FFFF00>
We are too young ....
Forced into adult male
through sacrifice and battle .
I play a dangerous game ....
And I'm lost !
If you want to leave me ....
Leaving your land ...
I would not blame you .
You are free to go.
you remain an independent person .
right.
Let's fight together - the same ...
and drove their ship
from Greek territory .
Today we have the honor
determine our story .
story will be told ....
For millennia.
Let's make our last defense ...
Get into the annals of history.
Let us show ....
That we choose to die
in the struggle ....
Instead of living in kebudak - infantilism
There is only one thing
you should know today .
Do not killed .
not.
Last Orders father.
He said to me ,
You deserve to be a leader .
Well, brother , I do not have
Another tactic or strategy .
This will be our last war .
We have a long battle with
how can I remember .
No more blessed
besides hanging sword .
- Parsiapan the kuperlukan ?
- Some of the lower deck .
Good .
you sure you want to do this?
Yes .
Without leadership Artemisia ,
Persian naval helpless .
We are not going to be able to approach it .
I will approach it ....
end all this .
no room for our ship back.
I know .
Today, the last Greek ship will be destroyed.
Do not for a chance at them .
Do not let them give up .
Today we will dance
in the body of the Greek team .
Today we will make
Greek knees.
Today I will tread
Themistokles neck with my legs.
Everything !
Ready to crush !
Getting close fight
Attack !
father saw pertempuranmu
Fight tooth and nail !
Wins You Win !
I did not come here as a spectator
Now!
Let them send us to hell !
Come on !
You offer independence without
consequence or responsibility .
Do you accept my offer ?
my answer is still no .
're battling more powerful than love.
Give up to me.
Or Meet ajalmu .
Who can you opponent besides me?
Nothing can match your leadership .
I'd rather die a free man
than live as slaves .
Moreover ye prisoners .
It started as a whisper .
A promise .
soft Gusts dance among the links ....
move over the death of 10 000 soldiers.
blew through her hair
and soft hand of her .
Gusts and promise turn into the wind.
wind blowing across Greece ....
Bringing the message delivered
Time - time of our Independence goddess ....
And how wise force
Leonidas kneel in front of him .
Wind That , my friends,
wind sacrifice.
Wind independence .
Wind color=#FFFF00>
Wind Judgment.
You're surrounded.
The entire Greek color=#FFFF00>
Delphi, Thebes , Olympia , Arcadia ....
and Sparta.
If die fetch me today, I'm ready ...
I can not lose my sword .
There is still time for you to escape.
killing is an act of depressing.
around armadamu dis Command
and surrender to me.
Surrender
THE ENDING ... ...