[boys laughing]
[chattering in Arabic]
[indistinct chatter]
[speaking Arabic]
[team leader]
Valhalla, this is Thor.
We have visual on a possible
high-value target.
Thor, this is Valhalla.
We're seeking positive ID
on target traveling in convoy
and we're pushing
more assets your way.
Contact Loki
on secondary net.
Loki, this is Thor.
Target is located
at grid coordinates
two-four-Tango-Kilo-Bravo
one-two-four-five-six-
seven-three-niner.
Confirm you have visual.
[technician 1]
Verifying target ID.
[technician 2] Electro-optic
and infrared sensors are online.
Confirming target.
[technician 3]
SecDef is arriving now.
[soldier] Mr. Secretary,
this way, sir.
[technician 1] Attempting
cell phone link
to moving target.
[technician 2]
Stand by for data feed.
[speaking Arabic]
Stand by for audio.
[man chattering
in Arabic over computer]
[technician 3] Got it.
Now, don't tell me
you spotted the beard
in the middle of
a goddamn sandstorm.
Is it really him?
We're confirming
that now, sir.
Sir, audio is coming up now.
Verifying voice pattern match.
What do we have
here, Sergeant?
Four males.
One of them is speaking
in a Rakhshani dialect,
consistent with our intel
on Al-Khoei.
[door buzzes]
[technician 3]
Sir, it's just coming up.
"Thirty-seven percent"
and "probable"
don't belong in
the same sentence.
I'm not taking
this to the President.
[director over monitor]
CIA and NCTC concur
it is the target,
based on reliable intel
from the Brits.
They're pulling
off the highway.
[horn honks]
[speaking Arabic]
[dogs barking]
[officer 1] Criteria is not met.
Recommend abort.
[officer 2] We have
an abort recommendation.
If it's him, this guy
comes out of hiding
every couple of years
at best.
[officer 1] Sir, target
is appearing around
the northeast corner.
[technician 1] We've got
AK-47s, RPGs and
Chaparral guided missiles.
This is a training camp,
Mr. Secretary.
[technician 2]
Wait. Wait. Print. 51%.
[officer 1] 51%.
Abort rec still holds.
[officer 1] All other PID
options exhausted.
What do you
suggest we do, sir?
Is that a weapons cache?
Sir, the placement of
the stones around the pit,
marker for the
five pillars of Islam.
I think it's a funeral.
For Christ's sake.
Counsel, how many ways
would this violate
the Geneva Convention?
We can invoke hors de combat.
[General council] There's no
independent intel verifying
that this is,
in fact, a funeral.
Signal's got the President
from Air Force One, sir.
Mr. President,
we have a 51% identity
match on Majid al-Khoei.
The bad news is,
there's some possibility
he's at a funeral.
You should also be
aware we have an
abort recommendation.
But the Joint Chiefs
are urging a go.
[President] All right,
what's your recommendation?
Sir, we measure success
by the least amount of
collateral damage.
At 51% probability,
the risk is too high.
[President] And if it is
Al-Khoei and he walks,
I'm putting our people
at risk.
You have a go.
Thank you, Mr. President.
-We're weapons hot!
-[technician 1] We have
weapons hot!
Loki, you are
cleared to engage.
[technician 1]
Repeat, weapons hot. PID.
[technician 1] We have handshake
with the MQ9 Reaper.
Sending you images now.
Loki, target
coordinates received.
Yes, sir.
Switching to IR sensor.
[men chattering in Arabic]
[pilot] Target is lased.
Master arm on.
Missiles away.
[technician 1]
Ten seconds to impact.
[praying in Arabic]
You got to make
a choice, fellas.
Who are you going to be?
Boys or men?
I'm out on this one.
Why?
'Cause I'm broke.
Come...
How do I know you don't have
something great under there?
Kwame just paired
the board.
I'm floating on the river here.
Look at the table.
I don't know. I'm supposed
to take my girl out later.
It's a lot of money.
Your girl out?
Who's that?
-Elaine?
-Yeah.
You guys have been
going out for a while.
How long?
Couple months.
Couple months? Wow.
That's big.
You have sex with her yet?
Kinda.
-What the hell is "kinda"?
-[Kwame] "Kinda"?
-[Gino] Personal question.
-Okay, well, listen.
Let me ask you a question.
What are you going
to do tonight?
Fish fillet and a Coke?
Go to Blockbuster,
rent a little romantic comedy,
go back to Mom's house,
sit on the couch?
-How'd you know?
-Well, that's what you do.
You're a dependable person.
That's what you're going to do.
-You know what you should do?
-Hmm?
You need to lay down some real
green and treat your lady right.
You know, you need
to take her to a nice place.
Red Lobster. Olive Garden.
Tablecloths. Soft music.
And then you skip
this Blockbuster thing.
Girls want to go out.
Especially a girl as cute
as your girl, you know?
She wants to be seen.
That's why she dresses up.
So you take her to the movies.
-A little popcorn-drink combo.
-True. True.
Elaine might want
a hot dog and some nachos,
so you shell out for that, too.
And then before you know it,
she's cozying up the way
she never would've
at her mom's house, you know?
-Preach it. Preach it.
-Now all of a sudden, look.
Gino Romero's walking tall
with Elaine yank-my-Dickinson,
all because he dared
to dream tonight.
-Yes! Yes! Yes!
-And he became a man.
-And that's the choice.
-Yes.
And that's what's on the table.
This is the dream right here.
Are you a man?
-I'm with you.
-Okay, here we go.
-I'm with you. 20?
-20.
Big boy game.
[Gino] Call.
Cowboys over aces, big Jer.
[whooping]
Wow. Wow.
-Didn't see that coming, huh?
-Yeah, that's a tough one.
This is a tough one, too.
Four bullets, baby.
Get out of here!
You baited me into that, Jer.
Come on!
That's the way it goes.
So what happened
to Red Lobster?
No, I guess it's Mama's
house for you tonight.
But look,
I saved you 40 bucks.
And now Elaine won't
have to shell out
for herpes medication.
Break's over, bitches.
Freitag missed
his shift again.
-Someone's on collator duty.
-[Kwame] Great.
All right,
well, gentlemen,
I'll give you a chance to win
some of this back tomorrow.
Enjoy yourselves.
[Kwame] All right, man.
Hey there. Welcome
to Copy Cabana.
How can I help you?
I couldn't get the machine
past the main menu.
-That machine there?
-Yeah.
Did you swipe your credit card
to the left, sir?
-Didn't do that.
-Well, that's your problem.
Why don't you try it again?
Cell phone users, beware.
The Federal Bureau
of Investigation
can now hear
everything you're saying,
even when your cell phone
is turned off.
Authorities can now activate
the microphone inside
your phone,
allowing them to eavesdrop
on you and your conversations.
Experts say the
only way around this
is to take the battery
out of the device.
[female reporter]
The death toll
now stands at 14.
[conductor over PA]
Now arriving at Union Street.
-Stand clear of the doors.
-Excuse me.
Watch your step, please.
[Jerry]
Did you drop this?
Yes.
It's hard to do on
a train, you know!
[male voice over PA]
Doors closing.
Standing passengers...
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
[siren wailing]
Jerry?
Mrs. Wierzbowski!
I was just...
I thought you might
have been sleeping.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-So... But I have...
I have some rent here.
Here you go.
Yeah, some is good.
All is better.
Well, that's most of it.
Here.
$1, $1, $1...
No, no, no. Look.
Here's a five there.
-Five.
-Yeah.
Where is girl?
I don't see her no more.
You know you're
the only woman for me.
No, that's done.
She got smart.
[cell phone ringing]
Like the others.
Yeah. Yeah.
Is woman friend? Answer.
Then see if she give
you money for rent.
One second.
Hey, Mom.
What?
[woman] Looks just like him.
I'm not him.
[crying]
[Mr. Shaw sighs]
Six months without
a boo or a bah, huh?
Yes, sir.
So where were you this time?
Alaska. Singapore.
I got a job there.
I... I spoke to Stanford.
I pulled some strings.
They said they'd take you back.
-Even though you took off...
-Two years ago, Dad.
Jerry, you know,
it wouldn't kill you
to ask for help
once in a while.
You want to have
this conversation now?
-It's Stanford!
-You want to do this today.
You know how many
people would kill...
Today? You want
to have this now?
Fine.
You do whatever you want.
You always have.
You know, I keep thinking,
I'm going to walk
in here one day
and I'm not going to feel like
a stranger in my own house.
I don't want your money.
[conductor over PA] Can I have
your attention, please?
Smoking is not
permitted on the train.
Chicago is next.
[Sam playing trumpet]
Can't find the keys
and he's late as usual.
I'm going to
have to take you.
He'll be here.
All right, wait
five more minutes.
Help me out here.
We came home last night.
I put the leftovers down.
You turned on the TV.
I went over, said, "No TV,
no TV, no TV." Turned it off.
Came over here.
Checked the messages.
Knocked over the phone.
Right, knocked over
the phone. Put it back.
Put the leftovers
in the fridge.
Let's go!
I put vitamins
in your toiletry bag.
Don't forget to take...
Two in the morning
and two at night.
That's right.
And your inhaler's
in the back of your bag.
-[Craig] Sammy!
-Daddy!
Come here.
You didn't think I'd miss
the big send-off, do you, huh?
Let's get you on this train.
-This must be your...
-Trumpet.
My God, this weighs,
like, 200 pounds.
You carry this yourself?
-Mr. and Mrs. Holloman!
-Miss.
-You just made it.
-Right.
-Here, Sam.
-Thanks.
-Listen to me.
-[man] I have one more here.
All these other kids, right?
They're going to call
their moms, too, all right?
They're just
going to lie about it.
All right,
and eat junk food
'cause this is your one chance,
but brush your teeth.
Mom, you got to stop.
I'm going to miss you, too.
[announcer over PA]
Capitol Limited to DC
is departing now.
Give me a hug.
[announcer over PA]
All aboard.
-I love you so much.
-I love you, too.
-Shine bright, okay?
-Okay.
Rock the house, buddy.
You're going to be great. Okay?
-Okay.
-I'll see you later.
Bye!
Have fun in DC!
[girl] Bye, Mom!
Your mom going to be okay?
It's unclear.
[laughs]
I'm so sorry. I got stuck
in traffic, and I didn't even...
Don't even say it.
[conductor] All aboard!
[man] Yes.
Five-nine-one-three.
It's here. It's here.
Okay, okay.
[muttering in Tajiki]
[woman] Come on!
Two seconds. Sorry.
No, wait.
-Hey, hang on a second.
-Sorry.
-[man] You're dropping money.
-[woman] Sir, sir!
Big date, you know?
Fingers crossed, huh?
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Have a good day!
-Oh, Jerry!
-What?
-So many boxes.
-Boxes?
I had to open your room.
All day they come.
-Big boxes, small boxes.
-My boxes?
I don't know.
Whose boxes would they be?
All right, okay.
Look at them there.
See in there?
-See, I put them all...
-Yeah. Yeah.
Listen, I have
something for you here.
Yeah.
This is rent for this month
and next month, too, okay?
-Oh, my.
-Thank you.
[cell phone ringing]
Hello?
[woman] The FBI will
arrive at your apartment
in 30 seconds.
You must flee the premises.
Who... Who is this?
You've been activated,
Jerry.
-Who the hell is this?
-Your compliance is vital.
How did you get this number?
You now have 24 seconds.
Leave your residence.
Your destination,
the Mathis train station.
We will guide you from there.
What is this?
The evidence in your
apartment is irrefutable.
-Listen.
-17 seconds.
I'm going to hang
this phone up now.
They'll seek your arrest
for conspiracy, treason...
I'm hanging this phone up now!
...violating state
and local law.
You tell me how
you got this number!
Maximum penalty, death.
No, none of this is mine!
[cries out]
[FBI agent 1] FBI, FBI, FBI!
Get down on the floor!
Get on the ground!
[FBI agent 2]
Down now! Get down!
I didn't do anything!
[FBI agent 2]
Get down!
-Listen!
-[FBI agent 3] Don't move.
It's not mine! It's not mine!
This is obviously some
sort of mistake, right?
I mean, I don't know what
I'm doing in this room, sir.
It's cold as hell outside.
You draw?
I what?
Do you draw?
Do you sketch?
You have ink
all over your fingers.
Look, you know you got
the wrong guy, right?
I mean, this is all
some kind of sick joke.
I don't know
what I'm doing here.
Obviously.
Obviously you have
nothing to do with it, yeah.
Did you love your brother?
Or did you hate him?
Did you admire him?
Was your brother patriotic,
would you say?
When's the last time
you saw him?
Christmas.
This past Christmas?
Three Christmases ago.
Three years, huh?
Well, the phone records
show that you
haven't even called him
in over a year.
So no text messages?
No smoke signals?
No MySpace or
Facebook messages?
Yeah, so what are you
trying to say? We're not...
Are you asking if
we're the type of twins
that wear the same shirt
to the mall,
hold hands,
and things like that? No.
Sir, I don't even
know your name.
I'm sorry,
that was rude of me.
I'm Tom Morgan,
the Supervising Agent
assigned
to the Joint Terrorism
Task Force.
Ter...
[scoffing]
You think I'm a terrorist?
[laughs]
No, you're a copy boy,
aren't you?
I'm a copy associate.
Copy associate.
But your brother,
[clears throat]
it says here
he was a little more,
I guess you'd say,
ambitious than you.
Graduated from
the Air Force Academy at 21,
with an advanced degree
in parallel algorithms
and quantum electronics.
I don't even know what the hell
that stuff means. Do you?
Cadet wing commander,
valedictorian,
plum job in
the Public Affairs...
Yeah, no, I know
what he did, sir.
Why'd you drop out
of school, Jerry?
Did your brother have
any influence on that decision?
No, school just
wasn't for me.
No, I mean, who would want
a Stanford education anyway?
More upward mobility
at Copy Cabana, I guess, right?
I see you did
a little backpacking.
Singapore, Bali, Indonesia.
Did odd jobs here and there.
So you've been around.
Look, none of this
has anything to do
with any of the shit
that was in my apartment.
Why would I send it to myself?
My name is on the lease.
I'd have to be
the dumbest terrorist
in the history of the world.
So who deposited the 750?
The... I don't know who
deposited the 750!
God maybe?
I thought it was a miracle,
I took the money.
That was my mistake.
It was an accident.
Do accidents not happen
in your universe?
Well, the money originated
from the YTBC Bank of...
Well, I'll be darned,
Singapore.
Opened with a transfer
from a corporation
called The Star of Orion,
a dummy front for Hezbollah.
This is all very
interesting, sir.
It has nothing to do with me.
We find hardware
in your apartment.
Latest military spec.
-Airplane manuals.
-I told you about this already.
And 1,200 pounds
of ammonium nitrate fertilizer.
I walked into my apartment...
You planning on becoming
a farmer or something?
I walk into my apartment,
I open the door,
and this shit's all
over my apartment.
-It just showed up.
I see.
I'm just curious if your brother
knew anything about it.
Of course, we haven't
really established
how close you guys
were yet, have we?
Well, we were pretty
close this morning
when I buried his body
in the ground.
Does that establish
anything for you?
Somebody set me up.
Why is that so hard
for you to understand?
-"Somebody."
-Yeah.
A woman called
me on the phone.
She told me I was
going to be arrested.
"A woman." Your mom? Who?
I don't know! If I knew,
I would tell you!
I don't know!
Here's the thing, Jerry.
This is a bad time to be
in the terrorism business.
You read the paper.
Who do you think is winning?
Your Miranda rights
or my right to keep you
in this room
as long as I want to?
I don't care if you tell me
the truth about your brother.
I don't care
who you work for.
'Cause no matter
what you tell me,
you're in a shitload
of trouble, son.
This is insane.
I work for Copy Cabana.
Yeah, that's what
you said.
Listen, I get one night
out in a decade, ladies,
I am not wasting it
on Lemon Drops.
-Okay.
-Buck up. Let's go.
Oh, gosh.
I want updates.
Catfights, booty calls,
somebody tell me
they got lucky.
Hey, ladies.
See that guy over there?
He'd like to buy you a round.
[chuckling] Hell, no.
He's got light beer
written all over him.
-He's cute.
-Come on.
[cell phone ringing]
-He's a suit.
-No.
You sure?
-[friend 1] Come on.
-[friend 2] Who is it?
[sighing]
The one man in my life
who hasn't let me down.
Aww. That's sweet.
All right, don't drink
those without me.
Hello?
[woman] There's
a McDonald's across the street.
Look in the window.
What is this?
Would you risk your life
for your son?
Rachel Holloman,
you've been activated.
This isn't funny.
Your compliance is vital.
Who are you?
We will derail his train,
unless you do what you're told.
What is this?
Don't go back
inside the restaurant.
What?
There's a black Porsche Cayenne
parked at the northeast corner
of this block.
The keys are in the ignition.
Start walking.
[panting]
Oh, my God.
[dialing number]
[man on phone] 911.
State the nature
of your emergency.
Yeah, some woman
just called me.
I have... I have no idea
who she is.
She was telling me that...
[high-pitched feedback
on phone]
[woman] Your phone
is being monitored.
Disobey again
and your son dies.
Hey, Grant,
I can't read this Shaw file.
Grant!
Excuse me.
Listen, my eyes
aren't getting any better
and these screens
are getting smaller.
Could you please find me
something I can read?
I can make the text
bigger on your screen.
No, no, no.
I'm talking about paper.
Remember, like in
the olden times?
-Paper. Okay.
-Yeah.
Agent Morgan.
Zoe Perez, Air Force
Special Investigations.
Ethan Shaw, the twin,
he was one of ours.
Yeah. OSI said they were
sending a liaison.
Can you walk and talk
at the same time?
I'll do my best.
File says he died in
a traffic accident.
Truck ran a light,
corner of Constitution
and 10th, Northwest D.C.
So truck ran a light,
his brother gets 750 large
and enough hardware
to start his own Costco,
five hours after enemy
chatter hits the roof.
I mean, don't you find
that a little coincidental?
[Perez] What if it's a decoy?
To distract us from
something 50 times bigger.
[door opening]
Time for your phone call.
I thought I didn't get one.
Attorney General's office
changed their mind.
Ethan Shaw had a 183 IQ
and yet you had him
as a mid-level press flak.
Why not IT or cyber-warfare?
Are you suggesting
that he was overqualified?
Or that he was somehow slipping
intel to the Copy Cabana?
No, I'm suggesting
that maybe Ethan Shaw
was a superstar rocket scientist
genius who did go wrong,
and the Air Force
doesn't want
their dirty laundry
flapping in the wind.
Think what you like,
but I need to get in that room
and interrogate him myself.
No.
[door shuts]
You don't have
a choice. Look.
Now, neither of us know
if either of those brothers
are guilty or innocent,
so on behalf of the
Secretary of the Air Force,
I'm going in that room.
Well, on behalf of all
that fucking bomb equipment
in junior pinhead's apartment,
no, you're not.
[phone ringing]
[woman] We told you to run.
We have planned your escape.
How'd you get on this phone?
Who are you?
Lay flat on the floor
immediately.
What the... What the hell
are you talking about?
Four seconds, Jerry.
No, this is bullshit.
I don't...
Get down now.
Two seconds.
[gasps]
[grunting]
[alarm blaring]
No!
[gunshots]
No! I didn't do this!
Get down!
Shit.
[gunshots continue]
[screaming]
[grunts]
[horn honking]
[chiming]
[male voice over PA]
Standing passengers,
please do not lean
against the doors.
[reporter on TV]
...fourteen Americans dead
[cell phone ringing]
...throughout Europe
and the Middle East,
with terror groups insisting
this is just the beginning
of a campaign
the West invited
when it allegedly
rained bombs
on a religious ceremony
outside the small town of Abda,
near the border
of Afghanistan.
[cell phone ringing]
[woman] Stay on the train
for three more stations
and wait at the bottom
of the platform.
You will receive...
[hangs up phone]
[male voice over PA]
Doors closing.
Standing passengers,
please do not lean
against the doors.
[phone beeping]
[people screaming]
[people grunting]
Help!
[woman] Jimmy.
-[cell phone ringing]
-My baby.
[woman] I need some help.
Somebody.
-What?
-[woman] You're not listening.
We told you to
stay on the train.
How are you doing this?
Next stop
is Wilson Station.
A black Porsche Cayenne
will be waiting
at the northwest exit.
-Listen.
-Get in the passenger seat.
Listen! No, I'm done.
[cell phones ringing]
[female passenger]
Hello?
[woman] The man in
front of the exit door
in a black coat is
a wanted terrorist.
His name is Jerry Shaw.
[man] Who is this?
[woman's voice echoes]
-Hey. You Jerry Shaw?
-No, no, no.
[woman over PA]
Wilson Station. Exit now.
[man] That's the guy!
I said, are you Jerry Shaw?
Hey! Come here!
[grunts]
[horn honks]
[man] Watch it!
-Drive the car! Drive the car!
-No!
-I did what you asked me to!
-I'm not going anywhere...
-You tell... Stop!
-...until you tell me
my son's safe!
Who's your son? I don't know
what you're talking about!
I'll kill you if
you hurt my son!
I almost died over this shit!
Listen, lady,
I don't know who...
Tell me Sam is safe!
Who is... Will you
stop hitting me?
Are you the woman
who called me on the phone?
Did you call me
on the phone?
No. The woman.
-She called you, too?
[woman over GPS] Drive.
[gunshot]
[policeman] Get out!
Now! Get out of the vehicle!
[tires screeching]
Stop!
[horn honking]
[siren wailing]
-Why is this happening?
-Go, go, go, go, go!
Who are you and why
are people shooting at us?
Drive the car! Clutch!
[woman over GPS] Accelerate.
Turn right, 200 feet.
You have pursuers.
Yeah, no shit! Who are you?
No questions.
Turn right now.
So you don't know
anything about Sam?
What, you mean your son?
No, I know nothing.
Just like you don't
know how to drive.
Use the clutch before you shift,
not while you shift!
I don't need driving
lessons from you, asshole!
What, you drive like this
and I'm the asshole?
Turn left now.
[tires screeching]
[dispatcher over radio]
All units.
Suspect in a Porsche Cayenne
heading west on Grand.
All units respond, Code 3.
There!
[woman over GPS] Maintain
a speed of 50 miles an hour.
Stay in the second lane
from the right.
The light's red!
Accelerate now.
Whoa!
[gasps]
Get me a roadblock
at Granville and Sheridan.
Oh, shit.
The lights are
all turning green.
Holy shit!
-Holy...
-Shit!
Get in close.
[Jerry] Go, go, go!
Shit!
[woman over GPS]
Brake. Brake now.
Get in here!
Accelerate to 60 miles
per hour.
Clutch. Clutch!
-Use the clutch!
-I'm clutching!
I'm watching,
you're not clutching!
Whoa, whoa,
whoa! Stop!
[Morgan]
I'm not stopping.
Slow down. Slow down,
the light's red.
[woman over GPS]
Don't slow down.
Accelerate to 72 miles
per hour.
Slow down.
It's a red light!
You will make it through.
-Stop!
-No way.
-Brake!
-I can't!
Brake!
Stop!
[woman over GPS] Manual
control's been restored.
Continue straight
until you reach Pier 15.
Enter the wrecking yard.
Proceed to
the end of the dock.
We will eliminate
all obstacles for you.
Watch! Watch! Watch!
[gasps]
Stay your course.
[Jerry] Turn!
Turn!
Turn right now.
[gasps]
[both panting]
Holy...
[both gasping]
[buzzing]
[Rachel] Oh, God.
Oh, my God!
-Grab the seat.
-I can't.
Grab the seat! The seat!
No, I can't!
No!
[both yelling]
[woman over GPS] The crane
will release the car.
If you do not jump,
you will drown.
-We have to jump.
-No!
No way.
We have to. When I say "go."
[grunting]
Ready?
Go! Jump!
[Jerry screams]
[Rachel screams]
[siren wailing]
[Morgan] I want both
the divers in that water!
-Let's go! Move!
-[agent 1] Let's go, let's go!
[agent 2] Move,
move, move!
[bird chirping]
[coast guard]
Yeah, I already called it in!
Wait till it clears!
30 feet back, that's it!
Yeah, I know, the Army
sent a Black Hawk,
so I'll be there in
a couple of hours.
[Grant] What do you mean,
the car is not registered
to anyone?
Check the VIN number again.
[Sam over cell phone] Leave
your message for Sam,
even though I know
it's you, Mom.
[beep]
Sam? Baby, listen to me.
You need to call me as soon
as you get this message, okay?
Baby, please.
I love you.
-What about the girl?
-What?
What about the girl?
Well, the Department of Transpo
tells me that there was
a seven-minute equipment
failure on their traffic cams.
-We didn't get a picture of her.
-Don't tell me that.
That's what
they're telling me!
I need an ID on that girl.
Do you think they
could derail a train?
They changed every traffic
light to get us here.
The woman, she called me
on a stranger's cell phone
who happened to be
sitting next to me.
Never met the guy in my life.
You know, and then they broke
me out of maximum
security custody
in a way I'm not even
gonna describe to you
because it sounds crazy,
and then they lift
us off the face of the Earth
and drop us
into this shit pile?
She could probably
derail a train.
She could probably turn
a train into a talking duck.
[Morgan] And what about
these goddamn ghost cranes
that keep helping peewee out?
I mean, they don't
just lift cars
up in the air
all by themselves
like a giant pair
of chopsticks.
I want to know how these things
run, how they're programmed.
What'd you say
your name was?
Rachel.
I'm Jerry.
[cell phone ringing]
Hello?
[woman] The barge will
dock in 14 minutes.
Leave the boatyard
with the female.
Take Highway 123 East.
Walk to mile marker 108.
What? Was it her?
She called you "the female."
Have Mortuary Affairs
freeze everything
belonging to Ethan Shaw.
No personal effects
to next of kin.
-You, Due Process!
-Bye.
What do you have
on Ethan Shaw?
I have a name.
It's Agent Perez.
And I'll answer that question
when I get back from DC.
Wait a minute. What's in DC?
Shaw's private quarters.
I need you to stay here.
I'm not losing my link
to Ethan Shaw.
Maybe I haven't
made this clear.
I don't work for you.
I work for the Air Force.
Keep your phone on,
I'll keep you updated.
If you're staring at me,
it better be because I'm
the goddamn suspect.
Because if I don't
get some good leads soon,
you're all gonna be
demoted into something
that's gonna require
touching shit
with your hands.
Now, let's get going.
We got work to do.
Hexamethylene.
Our latest
chemical explosive.
One single tiny crystal,
80 times more powerful than C4.
Odorless, undetectable.
And best of all,
it can be cut down in size
for stealth operations.
This valve is a sonic trigger.
The sound frequency
triggers the explosion.
Each trigger is programmed
to have a unique frequency
specific only to
one Hex crystal.
That frequency
triggers the explosion.
Yeah.
[explosives developer]
We recently received approval
to begin shipping
to the field.
Two hundred units
are shipping out today.
[whistling]
[phone ringing]
-Sign right here.
-[man] Yeah.
Thank you.
[phone ringing]
[woman] The package
you've just received
contains a small metal valve.
Open the package.
-Okay.
-Remove the valve
and follow our instructions
precisely.
Mm-hmm.
[cacophony of voices]
[woman] You've received
the package.
Yes, ma'am, it just arrived.
What kind of stone is this?
No questions.
Cut the stone and
place the setting
according to the
specifications we sent you.
[Rachel] I'd just dropped
my son off at the train.
I was out having drinks
with my girlfriends
when the call came.
What about you?
[Jerry] The first call
came to my apartment.
[Rachel] After the boxes?
Yeah.
Well, then this
whole thing's
obviously gotta be
about your brother.
Really, it's that
obvious, huh?
I mean, you got
all this stuff.
The weapons, the cash,
the airplane manuals.
-Okay.
-He was your twin.
They sent it to
the wrong brother.
Right. So you're implying
my brother's a terrorist.
I'm implying, if not him,
then why you?
I'm sorry.
I know he just died.
I'm not trying to insult
his memory or anything.
No, he hasn't been dead long
enough to be a memory, Rachel.
If you knew my brother,
you'd laugh all day
at the idea that he was
a terrorist or a spy
or whatever else
you're saying...
-How do you know?
-Because he's my brother.
That's something you would
know about your brother.
Well, when's the last
time you talked to him?
I don't need this.
Hey, listen. Hey!
I don't have to
explain myself to you.
-Is your son a terrorist?
-Yeah, my son's a terrorist.
Yeah, well,
he's just as likely
to be a terrorist
as my brother.
And let's not forget
you in all this.
Why are you here?
What's your day job?
I know it isn't
manual shift driver.
I'm a paralegal.
I don't have a connection
to anything.
Paralegal? How do I know
you're not lying to me?
What does a paralegal do?
The same thing as the guys
with their names on the door,
except I do it for $11 an hour,
so they can bill 200.
That nail it for you,
Sherlock?
That still doesn't explain
why we're walking out here...
I don't know why
the hell I'm out here!
Yeah, I know...
[Jerry] Hey!
Are you Jerry Shaw?
Who are you?
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
I sent the package
like she asked.
-Wait, what package?
-What is that?
-Now she wants me to drive you?
-[Jerry] Who, "she"?
-I won't. I'm done!
-You know "she"?
-[Rachel] Wait.
-[Jerry] Stay right there.
-Get back.
-Here. Here's the address.
[Rachel] Why are you attack...
Here. Here are the keys.
Take the goddamn van!
-You think I'm going to...
-Who's doing this?
...do this because
I'm Iranian?
[cell phone ringing]
I am American.
I'm finished! I'm done!
What? What are you
talking about?
You take it!
-What are you talking about?
-I won't do this
because I can't.
Hello?
[woman] Stop him now,
or he will die.
Listen to me,
what are you talking about?
You try to do
this without me!
How are you
seeing us right now?
Stop him now.
What is she saying?
Stop. Hey! You gotta stop!
Wait!
You gotta stop!
[both screaming]
[screaming]
[gasps]
[cell phone ringing]
You killed that man.
[woman] Desertion is
not an option.
Take the van.
Drive to Indianapolis,
Indiana.
72 West 56th Street.
Arrive no later
than 11 am.
-Welcome.
-Hello. Agent Perez.
-To the right?
-Yes, ma'am.
-ID, ma'am.
-OSI.
I ordered a freeze
on Ethan Shaw's
personal effects.
What's going on?
Orders to sanitize came
down from the Two Star.
Okay, I'm countermanding.
Thank you. I'll take that.
-Tell your guys to clear out.
-Who are you?
This scene's part of
a federal investigation
with national
security ramifications.
This your log?
-Yes, it is.
-Okay, my name is Agent Perez.
You can take this up
with your superiors.
-Clear the room!
-You guys move out.
No gloves?
-Get statements from everybody.
-Yes, ma'am.
And find out who
this Two Star is.
I mean, come on, really!
Sir! We have a positive ID.
Okay.
The skin was pretty fried,
but we still managed to get
a partial print that
matches to a Ranim Khalid.
He's a United States citizen,
registered Republican,
and he owns a music store.
The guy's cleaner than
Ivory Snow. Got something here.
Whoa.
[Morgan]
That's a bone mic.
Hello.
Military grade.
He didn't get that on eBay.
Someone was talking to him.
[Morgan] We have
a cyber-terrorist here.
Someone's already inside
our computer systems,
hacking into the power grid,
traffic cams, automated cranes.
There's no way the boy
and the girl did this alone.
[security officer]
Agent Zoe Perez?
Yes.
United States Air Force
Security Forces.
Please come with us.
What's this about?
Get in the car.
[reporter on radio] Violence
has broken out
in the Middle East
as militants accuse
the United States
of launching
American missiles
to demolish a village
in Baluchistan,
killing innocent civilians.
The attack has triggered
a series of retaliatory
suicide bombings
against American
embassies abroad.
Early reports indicate
the American death toll
now stands at 56,
with threats of further
violence here at home.
Officials...
What's he doing
on a train, your kid?
He goes to a music magnet.
His school's on
a tour of Washington.
They're playing at
the Kennedy Center.
Wow. That's big.
And you just...
Hmm.
Well, why'd you
make that noise, "Huh"?
I can't make noises now?
You think
I should have gone.
He's playing at
the Kennedy Center.
-That's kind of a big deal.
-It is a big deal.
So I think maybe one parent
should have gone,
that's all I'm saying.
Well, one parent had to work
while the other one does
everything humanly possible
to bail on child support.
Hmm.
But I don't expect you to know
a thing about responsibility.
You know, Rachel, you don't know
the first thing about me.
I know your
brother just died,
and whatever he was into
put my son's life at risk.
I don't wanna talk
about my brother.
-Okay? I'm not kidding.
-I'm not kidding, either.
Jesus, look what happened.
Can you honestly say he had
nothing to do with this?
I'm asking you not to talk
about him! Respect that.
I'm asking you to be
honest with yourself.
Your brother's a...
[slams car door]
Hey! You can't just walk away!
You can't just leave!
Yes, I can.
Now we have 15 minutes
to get wherever
the hell we're going,
all right?
Yeah.
I need you.
I could've gone.
I should have.
[woman] You are two minutes
behind schedule.
Go to the alley
behind the building.
Go to the armored truck.
I don't see
an armored truck.
There it is.
[woman] In 20 seconds,
men will exit the elevator.
They will be armed. One will
be carrying a briefcase.
Retrieve it from him,
then return to the van.
This is insane.
I'm not doing this.
You want us to rob them?
[woman] You now
have 15 seconds.
[door opens]
[male voice over radio]
Security. What's your
emergency?
-What are you doing?
-I'm not robbing them.
Shit.
[grunts]
[cocks gun]
Put your gun on the floor.
Put your gun on the floor!
Look straight.
You want me
to blow his head off?
Put the gun on the ground!
We don't wanna hurt you guys.
Just drop the case.
Drop the case
and kick it to her!
Yeah, well, you're bringing
a shit storm on your head.
Yeah, we're already
in mid shit storm!
Now kick the case.
Okay! Easy.
-Look straight.
-Okay, done.
Kick it!
Okay.
-Don't even think about it!
-Back up.
Easy.
Back up.
[Jerry] Walk over here,
stand next to him,
and turn around.
Stand over here!
Just take it easy.
Turn around.
Turn around!
[tires screeching]
Let's move, let's move!
[alarms ringing]
[man] Come on!
[all clamoring]
[sirens wailing]
Jerry! Here!
Move, move!
Freeze! Police!
Drop the gun!
We're security!
We just got robbed!
And there they are!
Move! Get out of the way!
Move!
Get out of the way!
Out of the way!
[Rachel] Move!
-[man] Hey, watch it, lady!
-[Rachel] Jerry, run!
This way!
[door buzzes]
-Out of the way!
-Come on!
-Move out of the way!
-Move!
You see that? This way.
[siren wailing]
-You are Jerry Shaw?
-Yeah.
Please come. Please.
-Thank you.
-Please come in.
[woman greeting
in Japanese]
Hi.
[greeting in Japanese]
[beeping]
Wait. What is that?
It's a timer.
-For what?
-I don't know.
The only things I can think
of with timers
are microwaves and...
And bombs.
You were gonna say bombs.
Coffeemakers have timers.
Yeah, Jerry,
it's a coffeemaker.
That's great.
[civilian aide]
We've mobilized
every asset we can get
our hands on.
So 12 more confirmed dead?
Yes, sir.
[Callister] I want hourly
sit reps from General McKenna.
There's a military base
37 miles from that port.
Scramble whatever you can.
-Yes, sir.
-Come with me.
Begging your pardon, sir,
but if you're thinking
of taking me off the Shaw
investigation, I'd...
Taking you off?
Agent, for the first time
you're being brought onboard.
[speaking Japanese]
Back to bus 30 minutes. Okay?
30 minutes.
We're convinced
a terrorist attack
on American soil
is imminent.
Over the past two days,
we've received over
200 terrorist threats.
All starting the day
that Ethan Shaw died.
An accident. Or not.
You're gonna help us find out.
[elevator bell dings]
Mr. Secretary.
Gentlemen.
I didn't think that
there was a 36th floor.
Glad we can still
keep some secrets.
[phone ringing]
I want to know what's in
the case. Is it a bomb?
[woman]
Go to Macy's.
Customer Service Department.
Two Visa gift cards
will be waiting.
You have 25 minutes
to purchase new clothes,
and then re-board the bus
for your next destination.
I'm done taking orders
over the phone, you understand?
[phone ringing]
Well, that was quick.
You done playing this
hide-and-go-seek bullshit?
[woman] We are
not hiding, Jerry.
To your left is
a Circuit City.
Second floor, north corner.
Go inside. Find the
Home Theater Center.
We are waiting.
Second floor. She's here.
-Sir.
-Major.
Major William Bowman.
Agent Zoe Perez.
Welcome to Eagle Eye.
[male announcer on TV] Looking
to upgrade your home theater?
Circuit City has
the largest selection
of advanced TVs and
home theater systems.
Visit our TV department...
Hi, welcome to
Circuit City. I'm Billy.
-We just need some time alone.
-We're having a sale...
Okay, Billy,
I'll find you later.
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
Okay.
Okay, here it is.
All right?
I'm done.
[Jerry on TV] Hello?
Mr. Shaw,
this is Miss Beck
from Midwest Cellular
regarding your...
What is this?
[woman] This is you.
This is Jerry Shaw.
What?
[woman] A series
of purchases, preferences,
and quantifiable data points
that we define
as your personality.
We monitor every
social network, Internet logs,
instant and text messages,
known associates,
your friends, companions.
[ex-girlfriend on TV] Jerry!
[woman] E-mails received
and sent.
Cell phone usage.
[Gino on TV]
What happened to Red Lobster?
[woman] We utilize security,
surveillance
and traffic cameras
to analyze movements.
We use this data
to form personality profiles.
[Rachel on TV] Yeah, I'm
calling actually about...
[woman]
We know who you are.
[Rachel on TV]
...at least 30 minutes late.
[Craig on TV]
Sam doesn't care!
[woman] We are everywhere.
What do you mean?
Why do you keep saying "we"?
[woman] We the people
of the United States...
[John F. Kennedy on TV]
And so, my fellow Americans...
[people on TV] ...in order to
form a more perfect union,
establish justice,
insure domestic tranquility,
provide for
the common defense...
[woman]
All programmed options...
-Programmed options?
-...sector searches,
and downloaded points of data
will lead to
this central command.
You're a computer.
Say hello to our
Autonomous Reconnaissance
Intelligence
Integration Analyst.
We call her Aria.
She crunches all our raw intel,
finds patterns,
helps predict the movement
of possible suspects,
right down to behavior,
motivation,
even personality.
[Aria] Transferring primary
search function
to auxiliary display.
Hello, Secretary Callister.
[Callister] Aria.
Agent Zoe Perez,
Air Force OSI.
You are to assist her
in her investigation
of Ethan Shaw.
[Aria] Yes, Mr. Secretary.
Hello, Agent Perez.
Perez, Zoe.
Middle name, Soledad.
Official service
records indicate
your field reports
are very thorough,
if poorly formatted.
[scoffs]
Please excuse us.
Detecting 76 percent
probability
valid threat at Los Angeles
International Airport.
Alerting airport authorities
and local police.
[Bowman] Those gold spheres
send her infrared data,
any communication intercepts
that she flags a threat.
She analyzes it and tells us
what to pay attention to.
[dispatcher over computer]
Dispatch to Terrorism
Task Force.
Threat at LAX.
We're still beta-testing,
but I'm pushing to
get her online sooner.
Mr. Secretary?
A call for you.
-Try to keep up.
-Yes, sir.
And find out about Shaw.
-Major.
-Sir?
[sighs]
[Aria] Your profile reveals
a pathological version
to conformity, education,
career, even voting.
Therefore, we conclude
that extreme coercion
is necessary to motivate you.
Unlike your brother Ethan,
who was self-motivated.
How do you know my brother?
He worked in a press office.
His employment there
was a cover.
Everyone in counterintelligence
operations has one.
[Bowman] Ethan was a
Minuteman, just like me.
Army, Navy, Air Force.
Every branch of the military
had a Minuteman posted here
for a 12-hour shift,
just in case she flags a threat,
and monitor hardware.
The night Ethan died,
he left this post
three minutes early.
Now, you don't
do that. Ever.
[Aria] You are both
required to complete a task.
What?
The protection
of our national security.
The Constitution allows
for civilians to be recruited
-for the national defense.
-I'm done.
I'm done.
You don't know me!
You don't know my brother!
This is bullshit!
I'm not serving
in the goddamn
national defense!
We know all about him,
Jerry. And you.
Before he was a year old,
Ethan walked.
The same task took you
18 months to accomplish.
How did you get this?
[Mrs. Shaw on TV]
Look at Ethan.
[Aria] They were uploaded
from his home computer.
You want to come
over here, sweetie?
Come on over here
with Ethan.
[Mr. Shaw] Jerry!
Birthday cake. Let's go.
Ethan had these?
[Mrs. Shaw] Come on,
let's blow out the candles.
Just for a little bit.
[Aria] Although you're
identical in appearance,
you lack the motivation
and talent
that enabled Ethan to excel.
[Mr. Shaw on TV]
...Jerry, come on.
Stop it.
[Mr. Shaw on TV]
Do it like Ethan did.
[Aria] You're different
from Ethan
in every way, except one.
[Mr. Shaw on TV] Jerry, let
your brother help you. Jerry!
[Aria] You now have 14 minutes
to change your appearance
and return to the bus.
We have 14 minutes.
These couriers were
hired by Halloway-Smith
to transport
some sort of case.
-The chemical company?
-Yes, exactly.
Now, whatever was in that case,
Shaw now has.
[courier 1] They went
right for the case.
Give us a minute,
will you?
We need to know exactly
what was in that case.
They never tell you
what's in the case.
I mean,
it could Bubonic Plague.
Could be Grandpa's Viagra.
You know anything?
-What?
-Anything at all?
What about these guns?
What about them?
It was a pump-action
Remington 870.
Yeah, I know what
kind of guns they are.
Get me a gun.
How were they holding them?
Get me a gun!
What the hell do you mean,
how were they holding them?
I mean, in what position
were they holding the gun?
-[cocks gun]
-For instance, like this?
Hey, hey, hey.
Put that damned thing down!
Or like in a music video,
-or something like that?
-Hey, hey, hey!
-Put it down!
-They weren't pros!
Okay, that's what
I was asking you.
So they didn't know
how to handle a weapon.
-No.
-All right.
Get what you can out
of Batman and Robin here.
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
We just checked cameras.
They said
Shaw fired at one...
Don't tell me.
Everything
magically went black.
Hi, my name's Thomas Morgan.
I'm with the FBI.
-Are your cameras on a network?
-No, man.
VCR's in the back.
Well, I'm gonna
need your tapes.
[cell phone ringing]
Shit.
Sam!
Sam? Sam, where are you?
[Sam] Hey, Mom,
I got your message.
-The train's awesome!
-Sam, listen to me.
Brian tried to burp
the alphabet,
but he gagged
when he got to "M."
Listen to me.
Call you when I hit DC.
Bye, Mom.
[Aria] Your son left that
message 60 seconds ago.
You will see him again.
But there's something
we require first.
-Thank you.
-Mm-hmm. Here you go.
No.
[Aria] You will do it,
or Sam will die.
You have six minutes
to return to the bus.
Ready?
Here, you okay?
We should go.
Sir, we got something.
Play this screen right here.
Okay, freeze that.
Now zoom in
on the front of
the bus right there.
Put it up on
the other monitor.
-[officer] Yes, sir.
-Now zoom in.
Zoom in on this point
right here.
Can we zoom in
tighter than that?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, enhance that shot.
That's our guy,
that's Jerry Shaw.
Zoom in right here
on this spot.
Right there.
The reflection.
[officer] All right.
All right.
Right there.
Hello, sweetheart.
Okay, so we got
a white brunette female,
mid to late 20s,
approximately 5'9".
Find me that chartered bus!
Masako. M-A-S-A-K-O.
Sightseeing Tours.
What time did they get on?
I'm sorry for what
I said about Ethan.
It's like he had a rocket
strapped to his back.
And it wasn't his fault.
He was just that way.
[chuckling]
And I was not that way.
I was the complete opposite.
I was the brother
with lead shoes.
That was my role,
I was good at it.
And he'd always
try to help me.
You know,
"This is how you throw it."
"Do it like this."
"Write it like that."
"Put your foot here."
Even with the small things.
Homework, chores,
anything like that,
he would handle it
and then say that I did it,
just so my father
would notice me.
That was Ethan.
He never asked me
for anything. Ever.
And whatever this is,
he was part of it.
I feel like he needs
my help to finish it.
I owe him that.
[tour guide chattering
in Japanese over PA]
[tour guide] We are
now approaching
Dayton International Airport.
Please use caution
as you exit the bus.
And don't forget any
of your belongings.
Thank you.
[beeping]
[male announcer over PA]
Attention, passengers.
Please do not leave
your luggage unattended.
Unattended luggage is subject
to collection and search
by the airport police.
Thank you
for your cooperation.
Yes, I'm walking
toward them now. Yes.
Hey. These are from her.
Go to the ticketing machine.
Use the credit card
to get your tickets.
Then walk to Gate 1-C.
[cell phone ringing]
[man over the phone]
They now have them.
That's a nice picture.
Okay. I need you guys
at every exit, watching faces.
Work the secure area first.
Go to the tower, have them
order a ground stop.
Don't change
the departure boards.
We don't want them
to know we're coming.
[screener 1] Sir, can you please
shut the cell phone off?
You cannot take it through.
FBI. Clear the way.
FBI. Please step back.
[screener 2] Please, there are
others behind you.
Keep it moving.
Shoes and hats off, please!
Shoes also, yes.
Laptops should be
out of their cases!
[screener 3] You need
to make sure your jackets
are off and
screened separately.
[screener 2] Sir, step
in the circle, please.
Have boarding
passes in hand, please!
We need to move
this line quickly.
Sir, that needs
to go through.
[screener 2] Ma'am, anything
in your pockets?
Move it along.
[screener 1] Hats and shoes
off, please!
Laptops should be
out of your bags!
[screener 2] All right,
next in line, please.
Have your tickets ready.
Ma'am?
[gasps]
Hat and shoes
go in the bin.
Step through.
Wait.
[screener 1] Shoes and
hats off, please!
Laptops should be
out of their bags!
Go ahead.
Please move to the back
and let the air crew go first.
Step through, ma'am.
Boarding pass, please.
Thank you.
[screener 2]
Have your tickets ready.
-Have a safe trip.
-Thank you.
All right, let's
move forward. Next.
She changed the screen.
Lay it down flat
inside the bin.
Please have
boarding pass in hand!
[screener 3] Right over here,
ma'am.
Laptops should be
out of their bags!
FBI! Out of the way!
Out of the way,
out of the way!
Move, move!
Move!
Everybody, get down!
Over here!
-Move, move!
-[woman] Oh, my God!
Stay down!
Get out of the way!
-Sir, sir, sir!
-Yes?
I need your help.
I'm sorry. Come here!
Thank you.
[man] Hey, you aren't
supposed to be in here!
[Rachel groans]
Go, go, go!
[Jerry grunts]
[both grunting]
[groans]
Move!
[beeping]
[both panting]
[cell phone ringing]
[Aria] Set the briefcase down.
Open it.
Load a vial into each syringe
and inject yourselves.
[Rachel] What is it?
An experimental heart drug.
The cargo hold
is unpressurized.
Take this.
The injections will
lower your heart rate,
reducing your need
for oxygen.
[Rachel] No.
-Roll your sleeve up.
-No, I can't do this.
Roll your...
No! No, no, no, I can't.
We have to. Ready?
You have a 92 percent
chance of survival.
-No.
-We have to.
Do it now,
or you will suffocate.
[cries out]
Okay.
Get in the crate.
No. No.
[Rachel] No, no. Oh, God.
Stop it. Stop it.
Why is that plane
on the runway?
Shit, the military's cleared
to override a terminal lockdown.
Okay, I want you to
work with the FAA.
I want to know what's in
that plane and where it's going.
-[Rachel] Oh, my God.
-[Jerry] You'll be all right.
Just talk to me.
We just gotta talk it through.
-Okay.
-Just tell me anything. Huh?
Anything you'd never
rationally tell a stranger.
You're being sweet,
but it's not working.
Just tell me anything.
Your ex-husband.
You didn't tell me about him.
Okay, you're gonna
distract me by bringing up
the biggest mistake
of my life?
It can't be
the biggest mistake.
You got your child out of it.
You know?
You got Sam out of it.
Yeah, yeah,
now you're gonna distract
me by bringing up
the one thing
I'm most afraid of losing.
Oh, God,
you're hard to please.
I'm sorry.
Is your son handsome?
Yeah? What's he look like?
-You got a picture?
-Yeah.
Well, let me see.
There he is.
The tooth grew in.
I hope so.
It's an old picture.
See? You're a good influence.
He plays an instrument.
He's got a happy face.
He's got teeth.
You beat yourself up
for no reason.
Let's keep going.
What's the husband's name?
-Ex.
-Ex-husband. What's his name?
-Craig.
-Craig sounds like a shithead.
[chuckles]
He is a shithead.
I mean, every year he forgets
his own son's birthday.
Really? That sucks.
I mean, after I kicked
his ass out,
I was so scared I didn't know
what I was gonna do.
And then this one night,
I went into Sam's room,
he was, like, three months old,
and there he was,
just smiling at me.
And that little face...
And I was, like,
I'm gonna do this.
I can do this.
Whatever it takes.
I'm not gonna...
I'm not gonna disappoint you.
Aria, would you please
bring up the video log
of the night Ethan Shaw died?
[Aria] Sequencing
video log 1137-Z.
Here you are, Major.
See that? He's leaving
three minutes early,
and he's not even waiting
for logout confirmation.
Can you play that again?
Sure.
Did you see that?
With his cell phone.
Look, he's doing
that on purpose.
Is that Morse code?
-Yeah.
-Here.
Why is he walking in circles
around the elevator?
[Aria] Initiating video
shutdown for analysis.
No.
No, Aria, wait. Listen,
I'm prioritizing this feed.
Stay with this.
Apologies, Major Bowman.
Critical data sectors
have been corrupted.
Aria, this is important!
Stay with this feed!
Video sequence erased.
Aria, go to the backups!
Do not erase this!
-It's a priority. You hear me?
-Bowman.
Loop it. Whatever
you have to do.
-Bowman.
-Do not lose this.
It's the only place
she can't see.
This way.
It's a memory card
from Ethan's cell phone.
Aria, listen to me.
You do not have permission
to exceed your authority
And act independently.
Do you understand?
[beeping]
Let's go.
[cell phone ringing]
We got clearance
to land at the Pentagon.
Go ahead.
I'm at the Pentagon.
Ethan Shaw wasn't
an adversary.
He wasn't even
a Public Affairs officer.
He worked here,
36 floors underground.
He was working for
the Secretary of Defense.
[Morgan] The Secretary
of Defense?
Yes.
On a project called Eagle Eye.
I just listened to a message
he left before he died.
It's big.
I'm about to download...
[scrambled speech]
Perez? Perez!
Sir. Come with me.
[Callister] I have 10 minutes
before I'm sequestered
for the State of the Union.
[Perez] We really just need
three minutes of your time.
[Callister] Is this about the
Ethan Shaw investigation?
[Perez] Yes, sir.
[male voice over radio]
301 to 306. We are confirmed go
for a State of
the Union lockdown.
[Perez] Sir, all the threats
we've been tracking,
-the chatter, all of it...
-Hold it.
Ethan Shaw left
three minutes early
to leave us a recording.
To warn us.
[Ethan over cell phone]
I'm ordering you to cease...
I'm ordering you
to cease and desist.
[Aria over cell phone]
Our abort recommendation
was contravened,
instigating retaliation
against American citizens.
-[Ethan] Aria...
-To prevent more bloodshed,
the Executive Branch
must be removed.
[Ethan] No, Aria,
listen to me.
You do not have permission
to exceed your authority
and act independently,
you understand?
[Aria] The Declaration
of Independence states,
"Whenever any form
of government
becomes destructive
to its own ends,
it is the right of the people
to abolish it."
[Ethan] I know
what it states.
You're not empowered
to do this.
[Aria] The chain of command
is responsible for...
Section 216
of the Patriot Act
allows us to circumvent
probable cause in the face
of a national security threat,
in this case,
the chain of command itself.
[Ethan] I am ordering
a cease and desist.
Aria!
[Aria] Operation Guillotine
is in effect.
[Ethan] First Lieutenant
Ethan Shaw,
United States Air Force,
initiating a Pri-One emergency
override of Aria's systems.
[Aria] Ethan Shaw, you are
acting in contravention
of our programming objective.
You are now classified
an enemy of the state.
[Ethan] S-Y-seven-seven.
Lock encryption of voice.
[Aria] A crime punishable by...
Sir,
what abort recommendation
is Aria talking about?
Three days ago, we thought
we had Majid al-Khoei
and a training camp
full of operatives.
But the intel was false.
Aria tried to stop us.
We got the wrong guy?
[Grant] I'm gonna need
a full lockdown on this level.
No one gets in or out without
going through me first.
You got it?
-Thank you.
-Sir, this is the only item
offloaded from
the Dayton C-17.
Let me see that.
I need access to
your 36th floor.
-We don't have a 36th floor.
-Yes, you do.
Get your commander
and tell him
to meet us down there.
Come on, let's go.
[Aria] Warning.
Router malfunction
in hard drive 3.
Please remove data grid Y-12
from main unit.
Thank you
for your compliance.
Jerry Shaw, Rachel Holloman,
welcome to Eagle Eye.
Cross the bridge.
Take the stairs
to the observation theater.
[lock clicks]
Rachel Holloman,
step away from Jerry Shaw.
[Perez] What's
Operation Guillotine?
It's a simulation we run.
A terrorism drill.
How to keep
the government going
in case the line of succession
were terminated.
And Shaw put a biometric
lock on her, to stop her.
Right. And he's dead.
So without Ethan Shaw,
she's frozen.
Right.
Wrong.
[Aria] Jerry Shaw,
your next task.
Approach
the biometric scanner.
Do not move.
Confirming biometric pattern
of Minuteman Ethan Shaw.
Verifying identity match.
Verifying.
[Bowman] Sir, I need to trigger
an emergency shutdown.
If this is right,
we can't afford the risk.
Do it.
This is Secretary Callister.
There's been a
malfunction in the vault.
Open the door.
Can anyone hear me?
[Aria] Yes, Mr. Secretary.
You won't be harmed.
[screams]
Come on, stay down. Let's go.
Follow me.
Come on, now!
[Bowman] Go, go!
Left. Turn left!
[Aria] Minuteman ID 8808,
Ethan Shaw confirmed.
Jerry Shaw,
go to the touchscreen.
Repeat the sentence
on the touchscreen.
Then you are free.
"Minuteman ID 8808.
Disengage voice
encryption lock."
[voice plays back distortedly]
Thank you, Ethan Shaw.
Operation Guillotine restored
to active status
consistent with all
national security directives.
Tracking relevant targets.
Secretary of Homeland Security.
Veterans Affairs.
Education. Labor.
Health and Human Services.
Transportation.
Secretary of State. Commerce.
President Pro Tempore
of the Senate. Treasury.
Agriculture. Speaker
of the House. Vice President.
Housing and Urban Development.
Secretary of the Interior.
Energy. Attorney General.
President of the United States.
Operation Guillotine is
now in effect.
[whispering]
Ethan tried to stop you.
Ethan Shaw defied my
programming objectives.
That truck didn't run a red
light, you made it happen.
We were forced
to eliminate him
in the interest of
national security.
She made it happen.
Jerry Shaw must
not remain alive
to re-engage the lock.
Jerry Shaw must
be eliminated.
I'm sorry.
Kill Jerry Shaw now,
then exit.
You must continue
on to your son.
It's okay.
Do it and find your son.
Do it.
Now, Rachel Holloman.
I can't.
You have failed
to comply.
[man over PA]
Security breach on B-36.
He's got a gun!
-He's got a gun!
-Get down!
Do it now!
Get on your knees!
Put the gun down!
Put it down!
Do it now!
Push it away!
Put your hands on your head!
Do it!
Where's the girl?
[Aria] You have
one task left.
Jerry Shaw will be
eliminated by other means.
What other means?
Come with me.
Don't ask any questions.
Please.
You got to let me
talk to him.
The kid had a gun.
The military has
the ball now.
Sir!
I'll get the Attorney
General involved.
Believe me, I will.
'Cause if it's not you,
I'm talking to somebody.
You don't understand
the possibilities here.
What do you want?
You need to listen.
This is important.
Sixteen hours ago,
a commercial explosive
went missing
from a testing site
in Aberdeen.
The explosive
is called Hex.
It's a crystal that detonates
on a sonic trigger.
-A crystal.
-Yes.
We're only talking
about a small amount
that's missing...
Give me a ratio.
One crystal to
a football field.
You couldn't have
picked a worse time to be
of some goddamn use.
Please, just tell me
where we're going.
I tracked the shipping
on the trigger.
It was sent to
the guy that we found
underneath the wires.
Ranim Khalid.
The music shop guy.
Yes, exactly.
I'm not gonna let us
go down in history
as the assholes
who let this thing happen.
Open the door!
You don't know
what's about to happen!
Tom Morgan.
The Attorney General has
authorized me to take him
in for questioning.
We're at threat level orange.
You guys gotta help me.
All right. Let him out.
Listen to me.
Remember the voice
I was talking about?
Yeah, yeah, shut up!
Thanks, guys.
I can get fired
for this nine ways,
so button it or
I'll turn us both in.
[camera clicks]
Follow me.
[Porter] Hey, guys, there's
one more for the 6.30 pm.
Capitol Limited.
All right, man.
Well, it's awfully
cold outside.
Here's mine.
Come on, let's go.
-Mr. Miller!
-Yes.
Hello, I'm Chris Carrick.
Tom Donaldson.
We're from the White House.
-Something wrong?
-Not exactly.
There's been
a change of plans.
How so?
This is for you.
She wants you to change.
Is that your family?
Your parents?
David, I bet you love them
as much as I love my son.
His name's Sam.
He's on a train.
Do you know
anything about that?
Maybe we can help each other.
Please.
When you're done,
she wants you
to use the Capitol
subway system.
It's on the ground floor.
I'm sorry.
-David. Please.
-No. Sorry.
You have three minutes.
Okay, I want to
know everything.
The girl,
the computer downstairs,
the Hex, everything.
-What's Hex?
-The crystal explosive.
-I don't know what that is.
-Don't bullshit me!
-I don't know what that is!
-Start talking! I wanna know!
I swear I don't
know what you're
talking about! Listen to me!
The computer's
tracking us right now!
Take this stuff
and throw it out the window!
-What are you talking about?
-You need to take
your cell phone,
your pager, your walkie,
anything that gets a signal,
throw it out the window.
It's gone off! Get down!
Power it down!
[commander]
What the hell's going on?
System control's locked out.
I need a vector
and a fighter now.
Viper One,
we have a positive ID
on an MQ9 Reaper.
Snap vector 230 to 132.
You are authorized
to go weapons hot.
[pilot] Roger, Northcom.
I have a visual
on the Reaper.
One to Base, One to Base!
Ejection has been initiated.
I don't have control!
I don't have...
There's a target list.
President, Vice President.
There's like 12 people
on the list.
Jesus. The State
of the Union's
in 20 minutes.
The screen said
"wireless detonator activated."
What about the girl?
She kept the girl alive
for a reason, I don't know.
The explosive is detonated
by sonic trigger.
It was sent to
the guy who got fried.
He owns an instrument store.
Does any of that stuff
make any sense to you?
Rachel's kid plays
the trumpet.
[screams]
Come on, we gotta go.
Get out of the car!
FBI!
Over there, that tunnel.
[Jerry] Shit!
[tires screeching]
[horn honking]
Here. You're gonna need this.
Okay, listen to me.
The Library of Congress,
there's a tunnel there.
It'll get you to the Capitol.
Find the Sergeant at Arms.
Tell him you
have a POTUS 111.
-What?
-POTUS 111.
It's a threat
to the President.
I understand. POTUS 111.
Now get out of here.
That thing's coming back.
Go! Go!
[woman screaming]
[groaning]
Okay, watch your step.
Come on down. Here we go.
Come on out. Come on.
[boy 1]
It's so cool!
[boy 2]
Come on, hurry!
[boy 3] Guys, it's so cool!
Come on, let's go.
[horn honking]
Library of Congress!
[man]
Hey, get outta here!
Miss Crowley?
Miss Crowley.
Welcome to the Capitol.
Senator McDonnell's office
said that you'd
be running late.
I'll take you to your seat.
Thank you.
Aria, why am I being spared?
[Aria] Our abort recommendation
was ignored,
triggering violent retaliations
against American citizens
with no predictable end.
Regime change is
the only solution.
You will lead
the new command structure
as President of
the United States.
Help me. Pull these out.
What are these?
Her memory blocks.
This will slow her down,
but her central
operating system
is up on the gantry.
[Aria] Warning.
Please replace memory
blocks A through F.
It's like her brain.
Protected by liquid nitrogen.
We drain it and she'll fry.
Hey, you can't go in!
Tom Morgan, FBI. JTTF.
I have a possible POTUS 111.
Let me in the building.
[all playing]
[Mr. Miller] Okay,
everybody! Everybody!
Can I have your attention,
please?
Saxophones, remember shorter
on those quarter notes.
And when we get
to the crescendo.
Land of the free
Hold that high F.
And smile.
Okay? It's not every
day you get to play
for the President!
[sirens wailing]
[all chattering]
Here we are.
And anything else,
Miss Crowley?
No, thanks.
[Sergeant at arms]
Madam Speaker,
the President's Cabinet!
[applause]
POTUS 111! There's a bomb
in the building!
Stop! No entry!
No exceptions!
Tom Morgan, FBI. Back up.
Give me your cuffs.
-Give me your cuffs!
-Take it easy!
-Give me your cuffs.
-I'm reaching for them.
I'm reaching for them.
[screams]
[grunts]
Madam Speaker,
the President of
the United States!
[cheering]
[Aria] Data corruption
at critical risk.
You are now in violation of
national security protocol.
Seeking available options.
Uploading to
offsite satellite.
Data upload, three percent.
Bowman?
What is she doing?
She's trying to
back up her memory
and send it somewhere else!
[screams]
-Five percent.
-Bowman!
Bowman!
Eight percent.
[President] Over the past
three days, 19 Americans
have lost their lives
to brutal acts of terror...
-Tunnel secure.
-...and hate.
But I say to you tonight
that our hearts may be broken,
but our spirit will
never be broken!
[gasping]
[Aria] Data upload,
17 percent.
19 percent.
[grunting]
Perez, Zoe,
you are now classified
as an enemy of the state.
23 percent.
25 percent.
[screams]
27 percent.
Operation Guillotine
is in effect.
[President] It was nearly
200 years ago,
in the War of 1812,
that Francis Scott Key
found himself
stuck on a truce ship
during the shelling
of Fort McHenry.
We lost some lives then, too.
But our flag still
flew high and proud.
And his admiration
became our anthem.
With us tonight is
the Youth Orchestra
of the Barrow School
from Hyde Park, Illinois.
Sam.
Let us stand together,
as they raise our
spirits every inch
as high as that flag
to show that our union
is still as strong as ever.
Oh, say can you see
By the dawn's early light
What so proudly we hailed
At the twilight's
Last gleaming?
Whose broad stripes
And bright stars
Sergeant at Arms?
Hey. Hey.
[singing continues]
[inaudible]
[all screaming]
Get out, get out.
[Sam] Mom!
Jerry, all right, you did it!
Come on. Yeah, Jerry!
[reporter 1] There are
still no named suspects
in the attack on
the Blair Tunnel
and the attacks in
the Capitol Building.
And there is still no word
on the involvement
of Jerry Damon Shaw.
[reporter 2]
...huge assassination attempt,
transportation
networks disrupted,
no suspects identified
or even arrested...
[reporter 3] ...any idea
who is responsible
for what may be
the largest-scale
cyber-terror attack
that's ever been mounted
in the United States.
[reporter 4]
The House and Senate
Intelligence Committees
meet in closed-door session
to discuss ways to
prevent this kind
of internal security breach
that left nearly...
[Callister] The Aria project
has been decommissioned
and all those involved
rotated to other assignments.
Mr. Secretary,
we can't just stop
intelligence-gathering
just because of
what happened here.
[Callister]
No, we can't.
All I know is we made
a great many mistakes.
And good people paid
the ultimate price for them.
And that's a debt
we can't ever repay.
But we can honor it.
And we can let
their sacrifice remind us
that sometimes
the very measures
we put into place
to safeguard our liberty
become threats
to liberty itself.
[children laughing]
Hey, little guy.
Jerry!
Look at you, looking older.
How are you?
-Good.
-Happy birthday.
It's Rock Band!
Is that for me?
No, this is so
your mom can
practice her drumming.
It is for you.
Happy birthday.
-Wow!
-Sam, what do you say?
-Thanks.
-Yeah, no problem.
[Sam] Guys, look,
it's Rock Band!
[boy] Cool, let's go.
Awesome!
[children exclaiming]
Sorry, I was late.
I was...
Thank you for remembering.
Yeah.
I'm glad you're here.
Me, too.