In 1917, I signed up
to fight the Huns in France.
Good men died ail around me.
And I saw no reason for it.
The rules we lived by were lies.
And the y didn't apply
to those who made them.
1 swore if 1 made it home,
I would never follow orders again.
I left a soldier.
I came home an outlaw.
I lived one robbery to the next.
A good day was filled by sleep,
and a good night spent
running too hard to look back.
I lived that life for 10 years
until it caught up to me.
It all started with an inside man.
The Albert White crew
was playing a high stakes poker game,
and our inside man
left the back door open for us.
Three, two, one.
Give us the fucking money.
- Do you know whose fucking place this is?
- Give it!
I asked, "Do you know whose fucking card
game this is", you fucking dunce?
- You heard of Albert White?
- Keep talking, bimbo.
Miss, come here. Come here!
Do you want a drink
to go with your robbery?
No. Just the money. Put it in the bag.
Let's go. In the bag. Right here.
Nice and easy.
What's your name'?
Emma Gould. What's yours?
- You're gonna put a sock in my mouth?
- That's right.
A sock? In my mouth'?
Never been used before,
and I wouldn't lie to you.
That's what all the liars say.
Quick, open up.
Just do a quick...
Watch this guy.
Here we go.
Hey, put your fucking hands
on the table.
Great.
All right, boys. Let's go.
You've got some balls.
Just slow down
and stop driving like we did something.
Relax.
We made out pretty good.
It was a nice hit.
Yeah, it's all mine.
Yeah. It's a living.
- Yeah, you fucking Mick.
- Get the fuck out of here. Drive the car.
Good afternoon-I'm Albert White-
You must be Joe.
Coughlin.
Good to put a face to the name.
This is Brennan Loomis, friend of mine.
How are you'!
You're too smart
for the stuff you've been pulling.
Nickel and diming with two dumb Guineas.
They're your friends,
but they're stupid and they're wops.
And they won't live to see 40.
Take your time.
But you can't work on your own.
Not in this town.
Albert was rounding up the troops.
There was a war going on over rum.
Dermot, go and have a word.
Albert White ran the Irish mob...
Brennan, keep an eye on him.
Uh-huh.
And Maso Pescatore ran the Italians.
It was tit for tat.
The deadliest year
in the history of Boston.
White's gang set fire to rum trucks.
Then a guy on Maso's payroll
went home with a girl
no one had seen before.
No winner. Just a lot of mess.
I wanted nothing to do
with Albert White and his war.
But I didn't have a choice.
His girlfriend was my inside man.
And I was in love with her.
He'd kill her if she tried to leave him'
and he'd kill us both 10 times over
if he found out we were together.
But we were in love and we were stupid.
And every time he was out of town,
we were together.
The fit was perfect.
get revenge on me,
when I least expect it.
- You just keep saying stupid things.
- No, I don't.
Yes, sir.
I know what you like to hear
'cause I'm no fool.
Like a book.
Mind if I join you'!
Sorry, Father Time,
we're waiting for someone.
No.
Emma, this is my father, Tom Coughlin.
Dad, this is my friend, Emma Gould.
Pleasure, Miss Gould.
Mind if I sit down'?
Where are you from, Miss Gould?
Dorchester.
No, I meant before.
You're clearly Irish.
All my mother's people are from Cork.
Really? What's her maiden name'!
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
She died. She's dead, my mum, so...
So, what is it you do?
It's a real swank place, this, isn't it'?
I'm aware of how my son earns a living.
I can only assume that
if you've come into contact with him,
it was either during a crime,
or in an establishment
populated by rough characters.
Are my questions
making you feel uncomfortable?
I don't know what you're on about.
And to be honest, I don't really care.
I'm on about you being the type of
lassie who consorts with criminals.
The fact that the criminal is my son
isn't the issue.
It is that my son is still my son.
And I have feelings that cause me
to question the wisdom
of consorting with the type of woman
who knowingly consorts with criminals.
- Did you follow all that?
- Enough, Dad. Enough. Okay?
My uncle mentioned a copper
on his payroll, name of Coughlin.
Is that you'?
This uncle would be your Uncle Robert?
Who everyone knows as "Bobo"?
No, the police officer you refer to
is Elmore Conklin.
He's stationed in Savin Hill.
He collects shakedowns from
illegal establishments such as Bobo's.
I rarely get over to Dorchester.
Still, as deputy superintendent,
I'd be happy to take
a greater interest in Bobo.
I need to powder.
Was that necessary?
I didn't start the fight, Joseph.
So, don't criticize me
for how I finished it.
I've been a police officer for 37 years.
If I've learned one thing above all,
do you know what it is'?
This gonna be another yarn
from the old country?
No.
What you put out in the world
will always come back to you.
But never how you predict.
I'm sure it doesn't.
Unearned confidence
of that about which one is ignorant,
always has the brightest glow.
I think I've earned enough.
She's quite easy on the eyes.
Yeah, she is.
Apart from that,
I fail to grasp what you see in her.
Because she's from Dorchester?
That doesn't help. Her father's a pimp.
Her uncle killed two men.
But I could overlook all that,
Joseph, if she wasn't...
She just doesn't pretend
to be something she's not.
Maybe she's just asleep.
Thanks for stopping by.
Maybe you should
climb under his covers tonight.
What?
He looks at me like I'm trash.
We're not people.
We're just the Goulds from Dorchester.
We tat the lace for your fucking curtains.
- Jesus! You know what...
- Don't fucking touch me.
My whole life,
I got the high hat and the icy mitt
from people like your father.
We're not less than you.
I never said you were.
Well, he did.
Fuck him, okay? I love you.
You think love's so easy.
It can be.
on, God.
- Come here.
- I don't want to.
Leave me alone!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- I want to go.
- Okay.
Okay.
Can you spare two bits?
Thanks a lot.
Joe Coughlin. I got an invitation.
Put your arms up there. I gotta check you.
Go ahead.
Joseph?
Joe Coughlin. Yeah.
Pleasure.
Do you know who I am'?
I know enough to show up here
when I'm asked.
My name is Maso Pescatore.
I run the North End
and liquor coming up from Florida.
I'ma man, uh,
with the power
of other men's lives in my hands.
But the truth is, uh,
I'm just a simple wop
from the old country.
Today, my only true rival is Albert White.
When that is no longer the case,
we can see an end to the fighting
that has plagued this town.
Well, I got no beef with you.
But I don't truck with gangsters.
Not even a Sheik like you.
You do soup jobs and stickups,
but you're not a gangster.
- What does that make you?
- I don't know.
An outlaw, I guess.
I just don't want any part of that life.
How many things, good or bad,
come to us
whether we ask for them, or not?
For example, one of my men
saw you with a young lady.
Well, not so much a lady,
but a Bobo's moll
whose daddy's Albert White.
So, it no longer matters
so much what you want.
You're in this life,
and it can only end two ways.
One, you get to Albert
and put an end to him.
Two,
I tell Albert about the girl.
And he gets to you first.
Like I said, I ain't a gangster.
And I done enough killing in this life.
You wanna tell your enemy
some rumor you heard'? Go ahead.
If I kill Albert White,
somebody's just gonna jump up
and take his place.
And I'd be married to the
Pescatore mob for the rest of my life.
I stopped kissing rings a long time ago.
Good afternoon.
Do you think he told Albert?
Nah. I'd be dead already.
Christ.
We could leave.
Where would we go'?
Somewhere warm.
My brother, Danny, lives in California.
Where'?
I don't know.
I haven't talked to him in 10 years.
He sent back a bunch of postcards
saying he was doing stunts,
trying to be a writer.
God, I'd go to California.
I don't know much about honest work,
I gotta tell ya.
- Who said anything about honest work?
- Good.
No, we do what we wanna do.
We'll go where we wanna go.
Sleep by day-
I got a job in Lawrence on Saturday.
And then I'll be free.
Free to leave?
Yeah. Free to leave.
I have to see you-know-who on Saturday.
- Fuck you-know-who.
- That's the idea.
Oh, come on. What's the alternative?
You want me to end up in the Charles?
I'm supposed to meet him
at the Statler on Saturday.
Turns him on to see me
when his wife's on his arm.
After that,
he's going to Detroit for a week.
Can you clean yourself up
and get to the Statler by 7:00?
I think I can clean
myself up and get to the Statler by 7:00.
- $hut up!
The Lawrence bank job would net us
enough to get to California on.
It's true
that's what I was thinking about.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
Copper. Copper!
Whoa, look out! Look out!
Fuck!
Get out of the way!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Oh, fuck!
- Shit!
Move! Get out of the fucking way!
Get out of the way!
Cop!
- All right, get out. Let's go.
- Go, go, go!
Get in the car! Go!
Shit!
I walked half a mite,
stole a car in North Reading,
and replaced it with a Dodge
I found in Somerville.
I came back to my childhood home
and considered my options.
The story was in all the late editions.
The third dead cop was a trooper
who pulled someone over
near the state forest.
Had to be Dion.
- Keep going.
- There's a service elevator up here.
I can't believe you came!
- What was I gonna do?
- Run.
- Where?
- I don't know. It's what people do.
It's not what I do.
Come on.
Shit! Shit! Shit!
Why are you crying?
Because I love you.
Then smile.
I can't.
No.
I'm sure as you die,
you'll tell yourself you did it for love.
No.
You feel guilty about what you do,
so, you spend your life hoping someone
will punish you for your sins.
Well,
here I am.
Joe, I'm so sorry.
She's sorry.
We're all fucking sorry.
Take her out of here.
You said you wouldn't kill him.
Albert, that was the deal.
- Don't worry.
- I would never have brought him here...
You think I'm going
to be humiliated by a whore?
Someone comes to me
says some arsehole
is putting horns on my fucking head.
You're lucky I didn't cut your tits off
and throw you in the fucking dump.
- Take her to the car, Donnie.
- No!
Joe, I'm sorry!
Albert, don't kill her.
You should be more worried about
what I'm going to do to you.
Albert, don't kill her.
Fuck do you care?
She just sold you down the river.
Please.
I wasn't honest.
I said if she delivered you to us,
I wouldn't kill you.
But we both know
I have to kill you, don't we, Joe?
And then,
I'm going to kill her, too.
Leave him.
Let's get out of here.
So, you're a cop killer now, Joseph?
I didn't kill anybody.
Looks like your friends were
about to take you on the dead man's drive.
Dad, they're gonna kill her.
Well, we won't kill you, Joseph.
But some of my coworkers
would like a word.
Listen, please. Dad!
They're gonna kill her.
She's in the car with Donnie Gishler.
I don't know what his skull's
made of, but it isn't bone.
In a coma two weeks.
No cranial bleeding.
No loss of memory or speech disability.
His nose and half his ribs are broken.
It'll be a long time before he doesn't see
any blood in the bowl. Go on in.
Dad, where is she'?
Did they find her'?
We followed her and Donnie Gishler.
His car went off the road
and into the ocean at 9:20.
An officer from Beverly
dove in looking for them.
Ended up in the hospital
for a week with hypothermia.
She was Albert White's girl.
She betrayed you.
She did.
And'?
I'm crazy about her.
Crazy isn't love.
I saw your marriage for 18 years.
It wasn't love.
No. No, it wasn't.
Either way, she's gone.
She's as dead as your mother.
God rest her.
They caught up with Paulo in St. Albans
about 10 miles from the border.
A number of officers gave chase.
He was struck by at least 14 rounds.
Low fora cop killer.
What about Dion?
It's possible he made the border.
You were the child that
was supposed to fix the distance
between me and your mother.
Were you aware of that?
I was aware of the distance.
People don't fix each other.
And they never become anything
but what they've always been.
All we get sometimes is a little luck.
Don't waste yours pining for a dead girl.
You make your own luck.
Sometimes.
Sometimes, it makes you.
If he pleads guilty,
I can take the death penalty
off the table.
Three years served, 20 probation.
Three years?
There are three dead police officers.
And he didn't kill them.
He may be the son
of a deputy superintendent,
but he will long know the inside
of the Charles town prison, I promise you.
Chief inspector.
I was demoted yesterday.
Then we can leave unsaid,
the notion I was going to dispel for you.
I have no illusions. I'm a practical man.
The photograph is of a door
to a row house in Back Bay,
where you have been keeping time
with a young man of Mexican descent.
If you move the location of your liaisons,
I will know within the hour.
Let me see what I can do.
Seeing what you can do
is of little interest to me.
I plead guilty
to abetting armed robbery,
and was given three years and four months
in the Charles town prison.
If my father had lived two more weeks,
I could have said goodbye.
I got one guaranteed life,
and I was gonna live it.
I would use Maso and his haired for Albert
to get me started.
Funny how things change.
What happened to all the talk
about not being a gangster?
Now, you come to me, looking for a job.
I got nothing left.
I don't wanna be a gangster.
But I'll work for one
if I can get to Albert White.
From what I heard in prison,
you're still the man to see about that.
We ran Albert White out of Boston,
like 'you heard.
Now, he's making a run
to our rum operation in Central Florida.
He wants Tampa.
It's true, I could use someone
who is committed
to putting an end to Mr. White.
Then you've found your man right here.
Your duty would always have to be
to the Pescatore family first,
and yourself second.
You five with that?
Sounds fair.
I just need one guy,
Dion Bartolo from my old crew
to help me go down there and setup.
It's good to have someone you can trust.
It's hot down there.
I don't mind hot.
You ain't never felt hot like this hot.
I spent some winters in Charles town.
I could use a change.
And get the narcotics running.
Starting in Tampa.
Frank Ormino runs Tampa.
He's gonna decide
he doesn't need the headache.
When's he gonna decide that?
Ten minutes after you get there.
I see.
Is that gonna make
me and you equal partners?
No.
Frank Ormino's an equal partner.
But look what's gonna happen to him.
I guess I work cheap.
Can you tolerate an Irishman in your crew?
This is America. I've lived with worse.
I realized
it's not enough to break the rules.
You have to be strong enough
to make your own.
Hi! Hi!
Joseph! Ah!
How you doing?
- Look at you.
- Look at you!
Hey, sorry about your father.
Yeah, sorry about your brother.
Thank you. Hey, thank you.
Listen, when Lefty Downer
found me in Montreal
and told me the Pescatores
wanted me to come work for them,
I thought it was a straight bamboozle.
Then I thought,
if anyone could charm the devil,
it's my old partner.
- Look at this.
- Holy shit!
Would you look at this?
Here. After you.
Get the fuck out of here.
I work for you now. Boss Joe Coughlin.
Reach under the seat,
and you'll find a friend.
Welcome to Ybor,
the Harlem of Tampa.
Cigars built this place.
What you're smelling now
is probably bolus or empanadas.
The rest of Tampa leaves Ybor alone.
As far as they're concerned,
we're a bunch of dirty spics and wops
and we can fuck off
and do what we need to do
as long as we leave them alone.
You'd think we all get along,
but it don't work out that way.
The Italians and the Cubans
keep to themselves.
But the Cubans, they hate the Spaniards,
and the Spaniards look at all Cubans
like they're uppity coons
who forgot their place
since America freed them in '98.
The Cubans and the Spanish,
they look down on the Puerto Ricans
and everyone, I mean, everyone,
shits on the Dominicans.
The Italians only respect you
if you came off the boat.
How you doing, ladies?
And the white people think
anyone gives a shit what they think.
You're a fucking piece of work.
Port of Tampa.
Who is it?
Fireplace.
Thanks, JT. Good work.
There's a whole network
of tunnels like this under the city.
- Who owns this warehouse?
- Frank Ormino did.
What do you mean Ormino "did"?
Ormino sprung a few leaks the other day.
That was quick.
Look at this over here.
Best money can buy!
You gotta keep it ai 186 Fahrenheit.
Yeah, these babies never lie.
Like to keep people from dying
when they drink your hooch.
We made a lot of toilet booze in prison.
Looks to me like
you're missing two key ingredients.
- Which are?
- People and molasses.
Yeah, we got a problem.
What?
- Our distributor.
He's been coming up empty.
- What is it?
- Boats have been sinking.
- What's his name?
- Gary L. Smith.
- Gary Ellsmith.
- No.
Gary L. Smith. it's a middle initial.
I don't know. He wants people to use it.
It's a Southern thing.
Not just an asshole thing?
Both.
Thank you, Miss Roe.
You must be Maso's new find.
I guess something like that.
- How you doing?
- All right.
So, what brings you by?
I've been asked to take over
Frank Ormino's affairs.
I hope that's not permanent.
- No offense.
- None taken. Why is that?
Folks like dealing with who they know.
And nobody knows you.
I see. Well, who would you suggest?
I have no ambitions for it,
but to keep continuity,
I might consider doing it fora term.
We're mostly concerned with why
the last three supply runs were hit.
That's the Cubans.
Why don't you just go to a new supplier?
- Not that simple.
- Why not'?
Because they're all
paying tribute to the Suarez family.
That's the Cubans
who own that club down on 7th, right?
We're gonna need to talk to them, too.
Uh...
I'm afraid you don't understand
how things are done here.
I deal with Mr. Suarez and his sister.
Okay, I'm sure we can arrange a table
for tomorrow night about 9:00.
Great.
Now, Gary L., tell me this.
Do you work directly for Albert White?
Or is there some intermediary
I should know about, as well?
What?
- We marked your bottles.
- You what?
- If you distilled it, we marked it.
And all these runs
that were supposedly lost at sea
somehow made their way
into Albert White's speakeasies.
Can you explain that?
No. I don't understand.
Dion drove me by your house
on the way over here.
You got a lovely place.
You're gonna have to pack up all that shit
and send it wherever it is you're going.
Where am I going?
Are you fucking her?
What'? Who'?
- Miss Roe.
- What?
- He's fucking her.
- Without question.
- Definitely fucking her.
- Oh, come on.
Afternoon taste of Miss Roe.
Sugar in the morning
Sugar in the-..
Whatever. I don't care who you fuck.
Here's some tickets.
This is the 11:00 Seaboard tonight.
I don't care who you take with you,
but you gotta be on that train.
Wait a minute, gentlemen.
- Come on a second here...
- We could go through the whole thing.
I can bounce your head off the floor
like a fucking bowling ball.
But let's just make it easy.
Put yourself on that train, Gary L.
Or we're gonna have to put you under it.
Listen, I think... Could we...
Now, come on, fellas. Gentlemen, can we...
Let's just sit and visit with each other.
IS this...
Mr. Co...-
Miss Roe!
When did you mark the bottles?
Fuck you talking about'?
You've been with me every second
since I've been here.
See me mark any bottles?
No! That's how come
I knew it was bullshit.
- Dion Bartolo.
- Yes, of course.
This way, please. Mr. Esteban is waiting.
Mr. Suarez, nice to see you.
Let me introduce you to Joe Coughlin.
- It's a pleasure to meet you, sir.
- Pleasure.
Have a drink.
Thank you very much.
I never agreed with the Spanish
that the lighter rums were superior.
Of course, we Cubans went along
because of our obsession
that lighter is greater in all things.
Dion, Joseph, my sister, Graciela.
- Nice to meet you.
- We've met.
My mistake. Of course, we have met.
Yes, we have.
How you doing?
Hi. How are you? Nice to meet you.
God, this rum is incredible.
Be nice if we could sell it up north.
When your country treats you like adults.
No hurry. We'd be out of a job.
Esteban took those.
- The working people of Miami.
- Very good.
It is a hobby.
Perhaps I photograph you
someday, Mr. Coughlin.
I don't know about that. Fewer pictures
out there of me, the better.
I'm with the Indians on that one.
Speaking of captured souls,
I've been told that Mr. Gary L. Smith
was seen boarding the Seaboard Limited
with his wife in one Pullman,
and he had that puta maestra in the other.
You never know.
Sometimes, a change of scenery
can do a man good.
Is that why you're here in Ybor?
Little change of scenery'?
I'm here in Ybor
to distill and distribute the demon rum.
A task which is made more difficult
by your erratic import schedules.
We don't control the tides.
Tides have been fine from here to Miami.
We know nothing of the boats to Miami.
Señor Famosa assures me
the tides have been calm all summer.
And you say Señor Famosa's name,
so we worry
you may overtake our supply routes.
No.
I use Señor Famosa's name to reassure you
that from now on,
you can work directly with me
and that you can charge me a higher price.
- What do we get in return?
- You get access
to Ormino's cops and judges,
which we now control.
And most of whom wouldn't do business
with you otherwise because you're Cuban.
And you would want exclusive access
to our molasses?
Nope. You just can't sell
to the White operation.
Albert White is a paying customer.
We've never had a problem with him.
I know Albert White.
I thought you might like
to deal with someone
who treated you like a human being.
It is possible this will bring bloodshed.
This will definitely bring bloodshed.
These are very favorable terms.
Albert White is what we get.
The local sheriff wanted to see us.
Apparently, it was a custom down there
to talk about how you were gonna
break the Saw before you did it.
What kind of guy is the chief?
He's a copper, so he's an asshole.
Beyond that, he's okay.
What are you doing?
Don't fuck with the guy's stuff.
The sheriffs gonna come in to find some
dago going through his fucking papers.
Hey, this is Figgis right here.
Please, sit down.
I won't insult you
by asking the nature of your business,
so you won't have to insult me by lying.
That fair?
Sounds fair to me.
It true you're a police captain's son?
Yes, sir.
You serve overseas?
France.
Tell it to the Marines.
Yes, sir.
They told it to us.
I was a soldier and then a U.S. Marshal.
I've killed seven men in my lifetime.
Truth be told,
their faces haunt me most nights.
You keep your business north of 2nd,
south of 27th, and east of Nebraska,
you and I will have little
in the way of discord.
Sounds good.
I know we live in a fallen world,
but just because I breathe corrupt air
and rub elbows with corrupt men,
never make the mistake of thinking
that I am corruptible.
I won't make that mistake.
Right.
Oh, dear, I'm sorry.
Thought you were alone.
That's all right, Loretta.
These gentlemen were just leaving.
Honey, your manners.
Yes, Father.
Miss Loretta Figgis.
Pleased to meet you, miss.
I'm Joe Coughlin.
Dion Bartolo.
Loretta is taking the train
on a long journey today.
It's going around.
California.
- Is that right?
She's gonna be a star in Hollywood.
- It's only a screen test, Daddy.
- No.
A screen agent came here
and picked out a few girls.
My brother's out there.
Your brother's in Hollywood?
He's a stuntman, I'm told.
Falling off horses.
Pleased to meet you, miss.
Chief.
Gentlemen.
- You're sure you don't want a banana?
- No, that's all right.
- You can't get fruit like this in Boston.
- No, I know. It looks good.
- Uh-oh. Here she is.
- What?
- All right. Just watch this.
- Oh, yeah?
Hello. Good afternoon.
- How are you?
- I'm well. How are you?
Excellent.
You, uh... Have you and your brother
come to any decision on our...
Not yet.
We're still considering, Mr. Coughlin.
Okay.
Yes. It would be quite an upheaval for us.
I understand. Of course.
We don't make changes easily.
Oh. There's all kind of change, you know.
Where I was recently staying,
we used to play chess a lot,
and this is the kind of change
where you get your pawn
to the end of the board
and it changes into a queen.
There's not a lot to think about here.
- Yes. I do play chess.
- You do?
Yes. My father taught me.
And what you might do well to remember
is that the pawn and the king
end up in the same box
at the end of the game.
The end? It's not about the end.
It's about when you're playing the game.
You could hang me upside down
and light me on fire at the end.
I wanna win while I'm playing.
I have a feeling
you win most of the games you play.
Not yet. But I plan on it.
Why don't you join me?
You know' some people say
liquor is only your side business.
Is that so'?
In fact, I heard rumors
you give most of your money away.
A lot of it in Cuba.
And you think that's foolish?
Not foolish.
It's just not my cause, that's all.
What is your cause?
The distribution of demon rum.
And that no man should rule
another man's life.
If you corner the rum market,
you will be a king.
I'll Still have to deal with Albert White.
But how will you hold the power
once you have it?
Why? You don't think I'm strong enough?
I don't know if you're cruel enough.
And if you are,
I will be very sad.
Powerful men don't have to be cruel.
But they usually are.
Tell me something. Do you think
there is such a thing as a noble man?
I got nothing against noble men.
They just rarely live past 40.
My father died for Cuba.
My mother died of a broken heart.
He would often tell Esteban and I,
"You cannot truly live
"unless there is something
for which you would die."
He sounds like a good man.
He WES.
We will never be lovers.
No?
Why is that'?
We will not be lovers.
We cornered the rum market
and lived like kings.
You know what'? Fine. Come on, hurry up.
Banks collapsed. Jobs dried up.
But vice, it seemed,
was Depression-proof.
Okay, let's go.
The Suarez-Coughlin
partnership created a rare stability.
We paid off Albert's guys
in Central Florida
to put down their guns.
So, when Amen wanted to hit us,
he had to use his Miami crews.
And when they showed up,
we bushwhacked them.
Albert was living on the run in Miami,
and there wasn't a speak in Central
or North Florida we didn't sell to.
Get something from in there
and put this shit out.
All right.
Get on the floor!
Get down, now!
Get on the floor. Get down!
Get down! Get down!
This is what happens
when Catholics
try to sell liquor down here.
The guy's name is RD Pruitt.
Well, we'd better go find him.
He's in the Klan.
So, what? So are five million
other guys in this country.
The Klan has a lot of fucking juice.
They're in breds
with fourth grade educations.
Oh, they're gonna love you.
A Catholic who works
with coloreds and lives with a Cuban.
Bigger problem is RD's brother-in-law.
Who's he?
Chief Figgis.
Joe Coughlin.
Don't shake hands with papists.
No offense.
None taken.
Would it help if I told you
I haven't been to church in half my life?
All right, now.
RD,
word is you're causing trouble
down in Ybor.
How's that'?
Well, we hear you're sticking up places.
I don't know a damn thing about that.
I'm just playing with you.
You all know that.
RD,
this is a businessman
who's come hereto do business.
And I suggest that you do it with him.
This man is a bootlegger
and a fornicator with niggers.
He needs to be tarred and feathered,
not done business with.
I'm just playing-
You can take a joke, right'?
Sure, I can take a joke.
Long as you don't become one, right?
So, you like the Parisian, right?
And if I did'?
I might be able to cut you in
on 10% of the house take.
- You'd do that?
- I would.
Well,
I ought to be worth more than 10%.
What were you thinking?
I was thinking 60.
60%?
The biggest club in town'?
That's right.
For what, exactly?
My friends might look on you more kindly.
- What friends?
- 60%.
Son, I ain't giving you 60%.
I ain't your son. Ain't nobody's son.
Save your father some embarrassment.
- What's that?
- 15%.
I will beat you to death.
Excuse me'?
You know,
that does sound like a fair arrangement.
You go to 20?
I think 15's pretty good for a job
you don't have to show up to work for.
Well, it's a fair deal
and I'm pleased to agree to it.
How do I pick up my cut'?
Come by the Parisian.
Second Tuesday, every month, 7:00.
Pleasure, Mr. Coughlin.
Irv.
Sounds like we have a deal.
Boy's dumb as a grape.
I don't understand what Maso wants.
Arrests are down 70%, revenue's up 300%.
I don't like getting some kid
sent down here like we need supervision.
No! We don't need supervision.
Digger wants to look at the casino option,
check progress, that's all.
He's gonna report back to the old man.
It's a joke. Don't make a big thing of it.
Maso's still gonna listen to what his son
tells him about starting a new casino.
Don't worry about it.
How did he get the name "Digger"!
Because he's a fucking dummy.
All they let him do is dig ditches
for the bodies they bump off.
- No shit?
- Yeah.
That's great.
I'd come up with a plan
to invest in a casino
with stakeholders in Sarasota
at the new Ritz development site.
Ritz Hotel and Casino.
Top shelf. A-one.
Right to the casino.
Absolute top-level resort.
Extraordinary resort experience
whether you gamble, or not.
For such a violent business,
it was populated with
a surprising number of guys
who were just putting food on the table.
Digger wasn't one of those guys.
So, this is it.
Volstead Act won't last forever, right?
What are we gonna do
when Prohibition ends?
Gambling.
We use the connections
we put together to get it legalized.
And we're the only ones in place
to run it.
And this is it?
It will be. Ritz Longboat Key.
I sat down with the owners
in Sarasota last week.
Why did they let us in'?
Because they can't get gambling legal,
and they can't run a casino.
They own the property, we run the casino.
We chop the profits 50-50.
Wait a minute.
Do we have a magic stick
for changing laws?
I heard you got bingo legal.
It's a step. It's that prerequisite.
You gotta do one thing,
- and then you get...
- Yeah, I know. It was a prerequisite.
Your grandmother can come down.
She'll play in the church.
Bingo!
Look, I got bagmen buying inspectors
in Tallahassee and Sarasota.
I got guys going after senators
and IRS agents who gamble.
We get gambling legal, we are rich. Legit.
For the long fucking haul.
I talk a good game, too.
But I like you.
He's a very smart boy.
Maso went crazy for the casino.
Called every day for updates
like ii was his idea.
It was addressed to
“Sir Joseph Coughlin, nigger fucker."
inside, was a two-word note'
"Sixty percent."
Same note. Same message.
We're doing everything we can,
but he's protected.
His roots here are too deep.
Well, time to start digging.
Afternoon, gentlemen.
Virgil Beauregard.
What can I do for you today?
We're hoping you can talk
some sense into RD Pruitt.
Ain't too many people
ever had much success doing that.
We'd like you to try.
And what would the reason be'?
His self-preservation.
He needs to stop shooting up my clubs.
Clubs?
What kind of clubs? Bridge clubs'?
Because I belong to
the Greater Tampa Rotary Club myself,
and I don't recall ever seeing you.
I come here
to do a piece of business with you,
and you wanna play fucking games?
- Is that what I wanna do?
4.005',
you're the Grand Wizard
of the Ku Klux Klan around here.
Congratulations.
But do you think that we got where we are
by letting some inbred
shit pickers muscle us?
If that's who you think we are,
you're making a fatal miscalculation, son.
'Cause we're clerks, and bankers,
and police officers, and deputies, and...
Hell, we even got a judge.
And if you're dim enough to fight us,
we're gonna rain bloody hellfire
down on you
and all you love.
So, you're threatening me with people
who are more powerful than you?
Exactly.
What the fuck am I talking to you for?
You've come to my home.
Thought I'd save you
the trouble of hauling me in.
Seventy-five witnesses.
Not a one will come forward.
You want a beer'?
It's near beer, but it ain't bad.
I'd love one.
Than ks.
I need RD, Chief.
I expect you'd feel that way.
You know what happens
if you don't help me.
No. I don't.
More bodies are gonna pile up.
More articles like "Cigar City Slaughter"
are gonna get written.
And the chief's gonna get pushed out.
You, too.
Maybe.
Difference is, when you get pushed out,
someone does it
with a bullet to the back of your ear.
I'm not selling out my wife's brother.
I don't wanna do this.
Do what'?
I don't wanna do what you're making me do.
I'm not making you do anything.
Yeah, you are.
What'?
She didn't make it to Hollywood.
She just made it to Los Angeles.
That's not right.
We got her with a special doctor now.
She's all right.
What kind of doctor?
Kind that gets people off heroin, Irv.
You do not ever call me
by my Christian name.
You'll call me Chief Figgis
for whatever years or days
remain in our acquaintance.
Are we clear'?
I didn't do this to her.
You just name your price
for telling me where my daughter is.
She's in a clean, safe facility,
and I'm not gonna tell you
where she is until you...
Until?
RD, you are gonna
meet with this boy again,
another discussion
to be had on the matter.
Yeah, M! just be the two of us.
Longboat Key, by the Ritz.
Tonight at 10:00.
When do I get her location?
Soon as I get out of this meeting alive.
You do it yourself.
What's that'?
If you're gonna km him,
be man enough to pull the trigger.
Ain't no pride in having other people do
what you're too weak to do yourself.
Okay.
In my experience,
it doesn't take much to pull a trigger.
Hey, RD.
Where's my brother-in-law?
He didn't come.
Boys, this one here is rat tricky.
Take your eyes off that peashooter,
I promise it'll be in his hands.
Not likely.
You a man of your word?
Depends on who I give it to.
So, you ain't come alone like I ordered?
Shit, RD, that would spoil the fun.
Where they at?
You know, this could be
the biggest casino in the United States
when they end Prohibition?
They ain't gonna end Prohibition
in a God-fearing country.
Country's in the tank.
Banks going under, cities are bankrupt.
Because we got a communist president.
Because we're not taxing liquor.
And that's why the state's gonna
change its laws to legalize gambling.
And you could be part of that.
I don't wanna be a part
of nothing with you.
How much is he paying you?
Who?
Albert White.
How much is he paying you
to shoot up my speaks?
Because you're doing
a hell of a job for him.
Yeah, I took his Catholic money.
You know why?
Because I'd have done it for free.
You are a pestilence.
You and your nigger whore girlfriend
and your dirty dago friends.
I'mma take the Parisian.
Not 60%.
The whole thing.
I'mma take all your clubs.
I'mma take everything you got.
Might even go by your house,
tear off a piece of that nigger girl
before I out her throat.
You ain't got this yet,
but you leaving town, boy.
You just forgot to pack your bags.
All right.
Go ahead.
Fuck.
Oh, shit.
Shit.
Bring the car around.
Au right.
- We'll get you to a doc.
- Fuck. It hurts.
Yeah. It hurts,
but it's not gonna kill you.
- Shit.
- Hold that.
Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck. We should have
never shown him the pictures.
- What pictures?
- Figgis.
That's what we had to do
to put this fucking guy down.
Price was too high.
I think it was you who shot me.
- What?
- I got him before he got a shot off.
- It wasn't me who shot you.
- It couldn't have been nobody else.
- Fasani was back there.
- It was Fasani who fucking shot you.
No, Fasani was coming from back there.
- Fasani came over here.
- Fasani was back there, shooting this way.
He came on this angle like this.
Right here.
I was over here.
- I got these motherfuckers.
- You hit me!
- Just get the fucking car around.
- All right.
It's gonna be a great casino.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Albert had been paying RD on his own
to come after us.
But once we kilted members of the Kian,
the Klan took it personal.
They came to finish me off
at the hospital,
but we had guards posted at the doors.
When the Klansmen gave up and went home,
Dion had them followed.
The subsequent string of
beatings, bombings, and murders,
effectively put an end
to the power of the KKK in Tampa.
How do you feel?
I'm all right.
You are'?
Thank you.
Irv's wife moved out
and took their son with her.
No one saw Loretta for the whole season.
Can Hake your name?
You wanna get married?
What'?
Well, we are married, aren't we?
Graciela Isabella...
I can't remember them all.
Lunes, Martes...
- Estupido! I don't have that many names.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Graciela Coughlin.
Best thing that ever happened
to that name.
I bought buildings.
Wow! We're married and, just like that,
now you bought some buildings?
Yes. I bought three buildings
by the Perez factory.
What are you gonna do
with these buildings?
I want to give shelter
to abandoned women and their children.
It's important, Joe.
What happened to
Cuban politics for a cause?
I fell in love with you.
You restrict my mobility.
Come here. I love you.
After months of seclusion,
Loretta emerged from home
and declared she would only wear white.
A decision made for her by Jesus Christ
to whom she would now be wed.
Damnable business.
Her show was a hit.
And her vision of Tampa cleansed of sin
didn't include a casino.
What's the problem with this preacher?
There's no problem with the preacher.
Everything's gonna work out fine.
Nothing can jeopardize our casino deal.
Absolutely, Maso. 100%.
Do what you need to.
Look, I'm gonna go down there.
I'm gonna talk to her.
Whatever needs to be done
will get done, okay?
Just make sure the problem goes away.
I don't want to hear about it.
All right. Thanks a lot.
You don't need to listen in on me.
Ask me anything you want
about my business, I'll tell you.
It's your business, not mine.
But I will.
I'll tell you anything you wanna know.
Yeah.
I came down here, it was all about
getting revenge, making money.
Now, everything I do, every step I take,
is about you and me
and protecting our future.
And that's what you need to understand.
But if those steps make you,
even little by little, someone else,
then you will not be you anymore.
You're you,
except for all those bad things you did.
You're almost you.
I want the real you.
You have me.
You have me. Come here.
Gambling destroys the spirit.
Amen.
One hears much
of personal liberty.
But when you've seen the barbarity of man
and been treated to personal doses...
You see'
it is simply liberty for the gambler.
For the gambler
to fritter away the gifts of God,
using it for himself.
Amen.
Personal liberty
is the liberty
of a murderer.
A seducer!
A wolf who wants to remain in a sheepfold.
I ask you,
how cheap is your virtue?
- No! Not cheap!
- Not cheap.
How cheap is your virtue?
It's not!
My virtues always been pretty cheap.
What virtue?
And they seek to build a house of gambling
on our waterfront!
No!
But we acquiesce.
I'll tell you,
there's only one way to deal with it.
With her around,
the casino gets voted down.
The casino gets voted down,
- me and you are on the hook for it.
- I'll handle it, okay'?
- Mr. Coughlin!
- Miss Figgis.
Such a pleasure.
Thanks so much for seeing us.
It was a great show today.
- Great.
- Terrific.
And you know my father.
Chief.
And this is Mayweather.
Mayweather's taking the good word
and preaching it down south.
It's a pleasure, sir.
My pleasure. That's good.
They need to hear about this in Miami.
- Keep up the good work.
- I'll try, sir.
Great.
What can I do for you?
I was hoping I could
just have a word with you for a second.
I was hoping to, uh,
talk to you a little bit about the Ritz.
My father says
there once was a good man in you.
I wasn't aware he'd departed.
You do quite a lot for the people here.
But we both know
your good works are mitigated
by your evil deeds.
We do'?
You profit from
the illegal addictions of others.
Their weakness and sloth
and libidinous behavior.
But you can free yourself of that.
But I don't want to.
Of course, you do.
Miss Figgis, you're a lovely woman.
And your story is amazing.
I'm not surprised the flock's
up threefold since you started here.
More like five times.
More booze has been drunk
in the last 10 years than ever before.
Because people don't wanna be told
they can't do it.
The same could be said of fornication.
People want it,
but don't want to be told
they can't have it.
Well, nor should they.
I'm sorry?
If people want to fornicate,
I see no reason to stop them.
And if they wish to lie down with animals?
Do they?
I'm sorry?
Do people wish to lie down with animals?
Some do.
And their sickness will spread
if you have your way.
Forgive me. I see no correlation between
alcohol and lying down with animals.
There's a correlation across all sin.
It is all against the wishes of God,
therefore, all equally offensive.
Let me apologize.
I think we got off on the wrong foot here.
I'm just here to ask you
if you would be amenable to omitting
the casino issue from your sermons,
and in exchange,
we're gonna bring a business here.
Business will create jobs,
which will reduce the sinfulness
that comes with poverty and idle hands.
We'd be willing
to contribute to the church.
Hell, we'd be willing to
build a few churches.
If God rewrites the Bible
to cast gambling as virtuous,
I will refrain from speaking against it.
But until then,
we don't get to pick
our sins, Mr. Coughlin.
I can't do it.
What'?
She's gonna fuck up the whole deal.
What do you mean you can't do it?
I know. No one touches her.
That's a mistake.
No shit.
Can we get you anything?
Oh, we're okay. Thanks.
We know you men are busy,
and we don't want to waste your time.
We're not going to invest
in the casino at the Ritz.
Are you sure about that?
I'm afraid so. The publicity is too much.
One woman preaching in a fucking tent?
Yes, because the casino would represent
only 2% of our total holdings.
And we can't appear to be
a company of Irish and Italian Catholics
turning white Protestant girls
into drug addicts.
The people I work for
are gonna be very upset about this.
We aren't men to be muscled or conned.
We're an institution.
We can't be bribed or bullied
because I simply represent
the vested interest
of a board of governors.
We are the landed
white gentry in this country
and we have no plans
to carve off a strip of this country,
which we have gone
to great pains to break and colonize
and hand it over to Catholics,
Jews, darkies or dagos.
It's just a bigger, better racket.
That's all.
Keeping the money in your hands
and out of the hands of people like us.
All those people,
the Negro
on whose back you went
to great pains to break this country
and the immigrants
who came over here with nothing
and worked their fingers
to the fucking bone,
all believed it
when you told them they could get ahead.
And one day' and I may not live to see it,
they're gonna figure it out.
But I tell you what.
I'd hate to fucking be you.
Standing between those people
and what they deserve.
Good luck to you. Prick.
Would have been a hell of a casino.
You'll get another chance.
Things swing back around.
Not all things.
They announced it on the radio
just when we got back.
President-elect Roosevelt
promised to sign the Cullen-Harrison Act
the minute he was elected,
effectively ending Prohibition.
- Hello, Miss Figgis.
- Mr. Coughlin.
- May I?
- Yes.
- Just for a minute?
- Yeah. Please sit.
You're looking very well.
I see you're not wearing white.
It's almost white.
Would you like a menu?
Thank you very much.
Could I have a cup of coffee, please?
Sure.
Thank you.
Why does my father hate you so much?
I'm a crook. He's the chief of police.
That's how it goes, I guess.
No. He liked you.
He said you were the Mayor of Ybor.
- Is that what he said?
- Mmm.
What did you do?
To him?
We had photographs.
And you showed them to him.
I showed him two.
How many did you have?
All of them.
We're all going to hell.
I don't think you're going to hell.
You know what I learned
as I've been thrusting my soul out to God?
What'?
This is heaven.
Right here.
We're in it now.
Then how come it looks like hell?
Because we fucked it all up.
After my trials,
I slept in the bed of my childhood.
I felt certain again.
I missed that.
I don't know if there is a God.
But I hope there is.
And I hope he's kind.
Wouldn't that be swell'?
Yes, it would be.
You seem not to despair.
Do you have a secret?
Ne. No secrets.
I have my wife.
That's enough.
But what if you lose her?
What are you gonna do now?
What do you mean?
You stopped me. Stopped the casino.
Law couldn't do it.
The people couldn't do it.
The Klan couldn't do it.
You did it.
I didn't get rid of alcohol.
No. That was too big.
But you've stopped gambling, and before
you came along, that was a lock.
I did do that, didn't I?
Yes, you did.
What's your father gonna do'?
Sit in his chair, I guess.
Blind with rage
that men touched his daughter
the way he used to touch his wife.
And worse.
He goes around the house
whispering one word over and over.
What word?
Repent.
Repent, repent.
Give him some time.
Maybe he'll come out of it.
We heard from Boston.
All three trucks made it up there fine.
Same payoffs as last week,
so it's no problem.
Good. Good, good.
And Loretta Figgis
cut her own throat yesterday.
What'?
Yeah, she did it at home
in the chief's bed, they say.
Gotta give it to her.
She's got moxie. I couldn't do that.
I don't know,
I guess some things are meant to be.
Hell, she could've done it
three months earlier,
and done us all a fucking favor.
Too late.
You blame yourself?
She went out west
as so many other girls do.
And she was preyed upon.
Not by you.
By men like me.
Men who get the booze,
they get the girls...
They get the drugs.
One hand washes the other.
We are not our brother's keeper.
In fact, it is an insult to our brother
to believe we are.
Look at these people.
If this man, say, dies of drunkenness
is it our fault?
When did you take this picture?
A month ago.
Are you sure'?
I took this picture myself
a month and three days ago.
Why?
Because that woman died in 1927.
There has never been
anyone like you in my life.
And one day,
I'm gonna be good enough for you.
- Are you sure it's her?
- You tell me.
- You tell Graciela?
- Of course I told her.
Jesus Christ.
What? You wouldn't tell your woman?
No.
No, I don't tell them shit.
But you're more of a I work than me.
What'd you say?
"Look, sorry, hon, that girl
I was bent out of shape over for years,
"she's not dead. She's in Miami.
"Don't make
a big fucking thing out of it.“
When you going?
- Going where?
- What do you mean, where?
You found out this girl
you used to be bugs for is 200 miles away.
When you going?
- Probably go after this thing with Maso.
- Good.
Give you something to live for.
What does that mean'?
Him and his guys are
taking over half a train to get down here.
That's a big fucking entourage.
Ah, bullshit. I ain't worried about it.
There's no percentage in killing us.
We doll and a half million dollars a year
from rum alone
in this fucking cow town.
What's he want to kill us for?
All we do is send him bags of money
up to his mansion in fucking Nahant.
I don't like the signs.
- What fucking signs?
- We lost the casino.
We never moved on narcotics,
and you're Irish in a world where there
ain't much of a shortage in guineas.
Okay? You're walking into a building
where he bought up every room.
I can't hide a weapon. Nothing.
You're going in blind
and we'll be outside.
Is that enough signs for you?
I need you to do something for me.
I need you to go slay in Miami
for just a little while.
How long is a little while'?
I don't know. Not too long.
I'm not gonna have your address.
I want you to give it to Dion.
When the time comes,
he'll tell me where you are
and I'll come get you.
So, you can find out if
you are as cruel as you need to be?
I guess so.
Joseph.
Even if you win today's battle,
there's so much violence in what you do.
Come here.
Gino, where you living now?
Neponset.
Oh. Settling down?
Two kids. A Nahant, 'a casa.
Whole thing.
- You got any?
- None for me.
There's never a right time.
This way.
How are you, my son'?
Fine.
Fausto, see if Dion needs anything.
So, how've you been?
Good. You?
More good days than bad.
Good.
This is the filly
who fucked up the whole casino thing?
Yeah, that's her.
Why didn't you clip her then?
Too much blowback.
That's not it.
You're not a killer, Joseph.
You are a bandit in a suit.
That's why you didn't kill that
Nahant Nahant.
You know how much money
this place was doing when I got here?
- You know what it's doing now?
- But that's all rum.
You neglected the girls and the narcotics.
I went after the rum
'cause it was the most profitable,
and I added four houses in my time here.
Yeah, but you could have added more.
Maso, look...
Mr. Pescatore!
I ran Ybor. I ran Tampa.
Did you ever have a problem?
You did more than that.
You ran the whole coast.
You boxed out Albert.
Put him in a little piss corner of Miami.
We been through the books.
You made us a force down here.
But now what?
"No Irish need apply?" What can I be?
What I fucking tell you to be.
Before you get a fucking pop
in the mouth, Mick.
You can he Nahant.
You teach Digger the ropes. Meet people.
Teach him to fish.
But you need to take a haircut.
What kind of a haircut?
Digger gets your take.
Look, Mr. Pescatore,
I think it's a fabulous idea.
Digger comes down here, takes over.
We 'Il run Florida, we'll take over Cuba.
But my take's gotta stay
somewhere near where it is.
And there's no power in being crew boss
and shaking down longshoremen.
You ever think maybe
that's the point, smart guy?
You need me. I built this.
We could use you.
But I'm sensing a lack of gratitude.
So am I.
You work for me.
Not the spics,
or the niggers you hang out with.
If I tell you to clean the shit
out of my toilet, guess what you do?
I can kill your cunt girlfriend
and burn your house to embers
if I feel like it.
So, do you want to be crew boss,
or clean the shit out of my toilet?
I'm accepting applications for both.
I guess it's crew boss.
That's my boy.
You want dinner tonight?
We have a few nice spots set aside.
You know, Joseph,
what I like about Albert White?
What'?
It's that he knows Tampa, too.
Which means nobody needs you, dumb fuck.
My fortunes have changed a little bit.
Me and Maso, we patched things up.
Turns out when you blew the casino deal,
he looked to me to help his son.
And that was just the start.
You see,
you need to trust the people
you work with.
We don't get into this game
to place second.
To back the wrong horse.
That's it.
You thought you'd be eating tomorrow,
looking at the fucking sun?
Well, think again.
Take your last look because you die now.
Wait.
Albert, I have something you wanna see.
Something that if you don't see,
you'd regret your whole life.
You'd never forgive yourself.
She's dead.
She look dead to you?
Where is she?
She's in the fucking picture, Albert.
- Where is she?
- I'd love to tell ya.
I'd love to walk outta here more.
That's an old one.
- You just folded up an old one.
- That's what I thought, too.
But, look, that guy
in the corner with the newspaper.
That was last month.
You tell me,
or I'll put you in the fucking ground.
I loved her, too, Albert.
Like you love that woman'?
Yeah.
She a nigger, or a spic?
She's both.
No! No!
Where the fuck are they?
Why don't you ask Albert? He knows Tampa.
You know why all the molasses and rum
that comes into Florida
comes through Tampa, Maso?
The tunnels.
What tunnels'?
The ones running underneath
this neighborhood.
That's how they get the booze in.
That's where my men are right now.
Your guys are ail standing around,
guarding the front door.
But that ain't where we're coming.
We're coming for you, Maso.
But we're coming from below.
Go, go!
Go!
You cleared the room?
Everything. The whole floor.
Seppe, give it another look.
Boss, they spotted Coughlin downstairs.
He even get a scratch?
A cut on the head.
I don't suppose you can wait for him
to die of blood poisoning?
Well, I don't think
we got that kinda time.
It's a hard thing fora man
to have a son this stupid.
All clear, boss.
I want you to cover the door
and the stairs
like Roman fucking centurions.
Pour me one, will ya?
Where were you hiding?
Hiding?
When Seppe cleared the room.
Sitting right here.
I asked him if he wanted to work for
someone who'd be alive tomorrow.
That's all it took?
That, and you wanted to put
a fucking dunce like Digger in charge.
We had a good thing going here
and you fucked it all up in one day.
You know how many people died here
'cause of your simple wop bullshit?
Maybe someday'
you'll have a son and you'll understand.
What will I understand?
How is my son?
Your son is dead now.
They would have killed
every last one of us.
Hunted us down. You know that.
They didn't expect to see old age.
Neither do I.
I had this whole thing I was gonna say
to Albert before I killed him.
Too late.
All right.
I don't wanna see
anyone else get killed today.
Any of you guys wanna die?
No, Mr. Coughlin.
Whoever wants to go back up to Boston
has my blessing. Go ahead.
But if any of you want to stay down here,
where the sun is warm
and the girls are pretty,
we got jobs for ya.
But I'm finished.
You want the boss? Go to him.
He runs things now.
Any confusion on that?
Good.
Graciela.
All right, let's go.
Clean up this fucking mess.
Dion ran the crew for eight years.
And he was right. He didn't see old age.
- Say what you have to say.
- So, what?
You had the wreck, you thought
you'd just make the best of it?
- No.
- Then, what?
What happened, Emma?
Well, once the coppers
started chasing me,
I said to the driver, the only way
to get away was to drive off the bridge.
But he wouldn't listen.
So?
So, I shot him.
We went into the water. I swam out.
Ran to the nearest house with a light on.
He was a fisherman.
Oh, he was happy to take me in.
You didn't wanna reach me?
If I put my head up,
they would've killed me.
I didn't owe you.
I mourned you for years.
Why don't you tell me
how bad I'm supposed to feel for ya?
Maybe if I had a police chief father
from a nice part of Ireland.
But I just had to make do.
Did you ever love me?
We had a laugh, Joe.
Sure, there were moments.
But you had to make it
something it wasn't.
Which was what'?
A lie.
You know, we're not God's children.
We're not fairy tale people
in a true love book.
We dance like motherfuckers,
so the grass can't grow underfoot.
I'm free, Joseph.
If you wanna come by now,
you got an open invitation.
We always had a lot of laughs.
I don't wanna be free.
Oh, come on.
That's all we ever wanted.
It's what you wanted.
And now you got it.
Goodbye, Emma.
We built Graciela's casitas
for abandoned women and children
who needed a place to stay.
We named our son after my father.
But he was thoughtful,
kind like his mother.
Yeah, Tomas.
Where you going?
Repent.
Come here, sweetie. Let me pick you up.
Repent!
- Tomas!
- Repent!
Repent!
Are you all right'?
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no.
Oh, God! Oh, God.
Oh, no.
Oh, God, no.
On Saturdays,
I take my son to the shows.
Some little German guy
is making trouble overseas.
I don't believe
they'll fight another war, though.
No percentage in it.
My son loved the show.
It was about an honest sheriff
in a dirty town.
All he could talk about
was getting his own badge when he grew up.
That's my brother.
That was my brother's name.
That's your uncle.
In the afternoons,
we fished for red fin and snook.
One day, my son asked me,
“Where's heaven in the sky?"
And I told him what Loretta told me.
"This is heaven. Right here.
"We're in it now."