What do you know, boys?
Hey, Papi,
get over here.
I got someone
I want you to meet.
Roland Legrand.
Caught this fucking goat
singing like a canary
to the police.
This is what happens
when you cross me.
Get this piece of shit
out of here.
So, what do you
got for me?
Piece of cake,
just like you said.
You pocket any
for yourself?
Yeah, just a couple
of the big ones.
You sure got
some balls on you.
You try to hustle me,
and I'll cut them
the fuck off.
Good for 10,000.
Did you have
a good night?
Yup.
At least you did.
Maybe this'll
cheer you up.
Take it.
It's for you.
A couple of
the big ones for us.
You're crazy.
Where you going?
Castili doesn't want me
leaving early.
To hell with Castili.
Let's go have some fun.
Let's turn that frown
upside down.
I know you want
to have some fun.
/ love you.
Say that again.
Slower.
...love...
...you.
I want a house.
In the countryside,
like where you grew up.
You make it sound so nice,
riding our little
horsey around.
Let's go today.
How am I going to earn
in the country?
There's nothing to steal.
We'll get jobs.
I made more last night
than most people
in the country
make in a year.
Give me six months.
I'll be making more money
than Castili
and all those bums.
Hey.
I don't want
to wait six months.
I'm here for the rent.
All right. I'm coming,
I'm coming.
It's him.
What the fuck?
You're under arrest
for the murder of
Roland Legrand.
What are you
talking about?
Well, he was murdered
last night.
A witness
identified you.
The pimp Roland Legrand.
You know him, right?
You got the wrong guy, pal.
I was with her all night.
Come on. Let's go.
All right,
let me get dressed.
No, no, no, no, no.
We got some stripes
at the station for you,
pretty boy.
This is bullshit.
Cuff him.
I didn't kill anyone.
You can't do that.
He was with me.
Nenette, relax.
They got nothing.
Nobody believes a whore.
Nenette!
Get back in your room.
Honestly, I'll be back
in no time.
Papi! Papi!
Don't worry. Don't worry.
Papi!
He didn't kill anyone!
He was with me!
Step away from the bars.
I can't believe
they gave you a life sentence.
You need to appeal.
Appeal what?
Nenette,
this is a frame-up.
They're all in on it.
I just need to concentrate
on breaking out.
Okay.
First thing
I'm going to do
when I get back
is Kill that lying
rat witness
and anyone
who has anything
to do with this.
Calm down.
All visitors have to leave.
Nenette, you need
to forget about me.
Don't say that.
I love you.
Time's up, lady.
Papi, I love you.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Get your hands off me!
Papillon, right?
They fucked you
good, huh?
Framed you for murder.
Say you're one hell
of a safe cracker.
I'm more of
a smash-and-grab guy
myself. Name's Julot.
Got any money?
No?
Get some.
You'll never escape
without it.
All right. Let's go.
Let's keep going.
Next. Move forward.
Next. Come on.
Line five.
Let's go, let's go.
Move.
Next.
Line up.
Go to the end.
Come on. Move along.
Stay in line.
Hey.
Perhaps I could speak
with your supervisor.
Sure. Whatever you say.
Louis Dega.
Guy's a millionaire.
Busted making counterfeit
defense bonds.
All right. Next.
Won't last long.
Every con in the prison
will want to cut him open
to get the money
he's carrying.
Next.
As of this moment,
you are the property
of the penal administration
of French Guiana.
After serving your full term
in prison,
you will remain
in South America
as workers and colonists
for a period equal to that
of your original sentence.
This is for the greater good
that is French expansion.
As for France,
she has disowned you.
She has rid herself
of you altogether.
Forget France.
Now dress yourself.
I'm going to hell.
God, please. Keep walking.
Mr. Dega.
Your appeal is
in a few weeks.
Be strong, Louis.
I love you.
You'll be home
before Christmas.
Dega. Mr. Dega, here.
Look this way.
Mr. Dega.
Move it.
That's enough.
Pick your feet up.
Hey, Julot.
All right, pair up.
Hey, take the corner.
Looks like Dega's
making friends already.
Julot, make sure no one
takes this hammock.
What are you looking at?
Hey.
I saved you a spot
next to me.
You got a lot
of eyes on you.
I can keep you safe.
All I need's enough money
for an escape.
Won't be cheap,
but you'll be safe.
Said the scorpion
to the frog.
We're all scorpions
in here, pal.
I think I'd be better off
taking my chances
setting up in front of the
guards, wouldn't you agree?
You seem like the kind
of man who can make up
his own mind.
You're a good judge
of character.
Have a good night.
Yeah, you, too.
Hey. Me and you,
we should team up
for an escape.
If I get caught in some
half-assed escape,
I want it to be my mistake.
Settle down, now.
I know you hide
your money in your guts.
Upper deck.
Move it back. Back, you.
Back. Back now.
Get him out of here.
The animals can clean up
their own mess.
Come on. Get rid of him.
Show's over.
How'd you sleep
last night?
Smells like freedom.
What, you've
heard of someone
escaping the prison?
Doesn't mean
it can't be done.
I have trouble seeing hope
in hopelessness.
That's why I need
a man like you.
I've reconsidered
your offer.
You keep me alive until
I'm set up on the island,
I'll underwrite any escape
you care to arrange.
All right.
And when the time comes,
you're not coming with me.
I have no intention
of escaping.
Unlike you,
I enjoy being alive.
My wife's working
on my appeal.
I'm confident
I'll be home by Christmas.
A fellow optimist.
I'm in for one.
Two.
Look what the fuck
you did!
Yeah!
Get the knife.
Come on! Get the knife!
Get the knife!
I'll kill you!
Steam!
Turn on the steam!
Come on,
come on, come on.
Get back!
Strip and line up,
you fucking animals,
or it's the steam again.
All right, on your feet.
Strip down.
Give me
the fucking knife.
Move it. Come on.
Line up in back there.
Let's go. Strip down.
Come on. Come on.
On your feet.
Line up in back there.
Strip down. Strip right up.
Hands. Hands out.
Everybody, hands out.
Everyone, let's have
your hands out. Let's see.
What you got?
Get him to the infirmary.
All right, let's get
this piece of meat
out of here.
Show me your hands. Let's see.
Turn them over. You.
Yeah, this one's
been fighting for sure.
Take him to first class.
Come on.
Time to go.
First class, let's go.
Try and behave, ladies.
Go!
You should've finished him.
I don't want
to kill anyone.
I'm going to get
myself sent
to the hospital.
Let me know if a guard
looks this way.
Do not stop!
Get a move along!
Eyes front!
Move it. Now! You, too.
Let's go! You heard me.
Move it! Move it!
Crazy, Julot.
Go that way.
You go this way.
You two. Come on now.
Form a line.
I said form a line.
Go ahead.
You two. You stay here.
Go back in line.
Move it! Come on. That way.
Come on, move it. Come on.
Move. Move along.
I said move it, God damn it.
Get up! Get up!
Come on, you. Move along.
Move along.
Eyes straight. Eyes straight.
Come on. Move.
That way. Over there. Come on.
Faster!
Move! Move it!
Come on now!
Come on, move.
Don't be looking at me
like that.
Come on, move!
You, too.
Move along.
All right! Get him up!
My fucking leg!
My leg.
My leg!
That's enough.
Break it up. Break it up.
Move back. Move back.
Get in line!
Move. Back to the line.
Move. Move.
Raise your hand
if 1 call your name.
Augustin.
Barba.
Come on, now.
Stay in line.
Bellaire.
Move along.
Over there.
Lofton.
Form straight
up over there.
Navarrone.
Move out!
All right.
Come on. Move it.
Keep moving!
Prisoners, halt!
Open the gates.
March!
I know many of you
at this very moment
are thinking about escape.
Feel free to try
whenever you like.
We'll be happy to shoot you.
If, however,
you should avoid
that mercy,
there are two guardians
who are always on duty.
The bush, where the best thing
that can happen to you
is starvation.
Or you could choose the sea,
where sharks, too,
I assure you,
are always hungry.
If you manage to survive
your first attempt,
you'll get two years
in solitary.
Second attempt,
five years in solitary
followed by a life sentence
at Devils Island.
If you commit murder,
you'll be executed.
That's all.
Move, move!
Jesus Christ.
Here. Take the corner.
Hey. Keep your eyes open
and don't move.
Hey.
Who decides what work
we get assigned to?
Excuse my ill-mannered...
I thought I told you
not to move.
He has yet to be tamed.
And you're obviously
a very important,
very, very busy man.
I'm just a turnkey.
We're looking
for someone
to ensure
we're assigned
the right sort of
work in the morning.
It'll cost you 1,000.
I don't think so.
No. Now that seems
entirely too high.
Sir.
I think we started off
on the wrong foot.
I think 1,000
is actually fair.
Now, is there a selection
of work you have?
Attendants at
the hospital.
And for a thousand
you can throw
in a pouch of tobacco.
And a notebook.
A notebook?
I'm an artist.
You're a forger.
And you're
a safe cracker,
a profession of which
I thoroughly disapprove.
At least I'm
an honest criminal.
Hey, I'm gonna
need that
right now.
I mean, right now.
Excuse me.
I think you need
to go to the bathroom.
Yes, of course.
If you'll excuse me,
gentlemen.
Where are you going?
I've never
been here before.
Toilet's there,
princess.
What animal but a man
keeps his only means
of survival up his ass?
Something bit me.
We got a runner!
Lockdown!
Lock it down.
Which barracks?
No, he broke
out of the hospital.
Just one, I think.
The hospital?
Lock down your barrack!
I bet that's Julot.
Lock it down!
Son of a bitch
didn't waste any time.
Lock down
the north barrack!
You see?
It can be done.
Lock it down.
Into the jungle.
Stand down.
Route zero.
My friend and I need
to be kept together
at all times.
Set these two up
in the hospital.
And it'll be a few
days before I'm well
enough to do any...
Don't push it.
...work.
Route zero.
Mr. Dega. Stop.
I know you.
Do you know me?
Yes. Yes,
of course.
You're the deputy
warden, Sir.
My sister's husband
was arrested selling
counterfeit defense bonds
you furnished him
with in Marseilles.
Dega is a very
common name
in Marseilles.
Santini.
Yes, sir.
This one goes straight
to route zero.
Take him away.
Wait.
Take him, too.
We try not to separate
old friends here.
Get them
to route zero.
Move.
What is route zero?
Are those men clear?
You're on the rail!
I don't feel so good.
It goes in the cart.
Move along.
You do a lot of talking.
I do.
Yeah, stop that.
It passes...
Passes the time.
Get out of my face.
Here, you take
the bigger rock.
If you get into
a fight with him,
I'm not protecting you.
If your wife was here,
you were in Paris
with all that money,
how much would you pay
to get her back?
Everything I have.
How much would she pay
for you?
You're a real optimist.
Little man.
You need to put
some weight.
You can push harder
than that. Come on.
Trust me, he can't.
Trust me, he has to.
Come on, push it!
Clear the charge!
Push it!
Pick up the pace.
I have...
I have diarrhea.
What you want me
to do about it?
No, you don't understand.
I lost the money.
What's the holdup?
What the hell are you doing?
What?
Stop shitting around.
He'll get us all killed.
You mind your own cart.
That little guy is
making more
work for the rest of us.
Mind your own business.
Break it up.
What are you doing?
Get up. Get up!
Get up!
On your feet.
I can't.
Pick him up.
Come on, pick him up.
Put him in the cart.
Back to work.
Move your cart.
You had one job to do.
You couldn't do it.
My body's in revolt.
Where is it now?
Where do you think?
I should've known better
than to trust a thief.
I can't steal
what's already mine.
As soon as we get back
to the barracks,
you're taking it back.
And you're gonna
hold onto it
this time.
I don't care if you
have to sew your ass
up to do it.
I'm sorry.
I may have prematurely judged
you with an unworthy
degree of suspicion.
Well, don't propose yet.
I just don't like carrying
things in my ass.
He's dead.
He's dead!
Shut up, birdie.
Are you stupid or what?
We share his ration.
Here.
You got yourself
a boyfriend, huh?
You were in the navy?
What do you think?
I thought maybe it meant
"jailbird."
The swallows.
Stands for hope.
First thing you see
when you reach land.
I know.
Yeah? How come?
You were in the navy?
Eighteen months.
Followed by six
in the brig.
Didn't suit me.
A butterfly.
So, you're a thief now.
Guess that didn't
suit you either.
We should
go sailing sometime.
You got a boat?
Can you get any of that?
Maybe.
Well, let me know then.
Your boyfriend's
got trouble.
Give me your money
or you and your friend
will die.
Is there trouble?
I was talking
to your bitch.
And now you're
talking to me.
Bitch...
Work it out
in the barracks!
Break is over!
Get in line!
Break's over! Form up!
Line it up!
Stop. Stop!
Turn around.
Eyes up front. Come on.
You know better than to truck
your ladies through here
after a rain storm.
Yeah. Can you help me out?
I'll make it good for you.
Get the girls up here.
Come on.
Hey.
Can you hear me?
How much to take me
up the coast?
Don't be stupid.
I'll give you 2,000.
Guard!
Don't turn me in,
for Christ's sake.
4,000.
What's the problem?
Just wanted to know
which girl I should send
to repay you.
One that hasn't
caught anything yet.
My boat is on
the other side
of the river.
I'll be there
for three more days.
It's 5,000.
You're a goddamn thief.
The guards are coming.
Don't fucking touch me!
I didn't know
it would be like this.
I'll be dead long
before my appeal.
I need to go with you.
That wasn't part
of the deal.
Yes, I realize that,
but I still have
to go with you.
You ever sail a boat?
Spent any time at sea?
Yes, I've spent
a number of days at sea.
I was locked in a cage
for most of them.
But I think I understand
the concept well enough.
You can't come
with me, Dega.
You should call me Louis.
Keep it moving!
Get them in line.
Stand straight!
Down on your knees.
Take off your hats
and cross your arms.
At the moment of execution,
you're all to bow your heads.
A man stabbed two guards,
one of whom died
this morning,
leaving two children without
their father.
And for what?
So he could go on a run
through the jungle.
Thank you for coming.
Watch me go to hell!
Prisoner ready.
Keeping you is no benefit.
Destroying you is no loss.
You.
Pick another inmate.
You carry the body.
Go get the boat ready.
He's gone.
It's just flesh and blood.
Why are you stopping?
What are you doing?
Move.
I said, what the hell
are you doing?
Get up.
Get up, you little worm.
Get your ass up!
You little worm.
Oh, shit.
Stop.
Hey, stop!
Hey!
We've got a runner!
He's heading north.
Papi. Papi?
Heading north now!
Papillon!
Check the tree line!
Hey!
Take that north side!
Pick him up.
Come on.
You're a good man.
Yeah, I'm a good man
that wants good money.
Look, I don't have it.
Not with me.
But I'm going to make it
worth your while.
I got a lot of money
in Paris.
I'll give you
everything I got.
Even if you had the money,
the warden will pay us double.
Son of a bitch.
You're lucky
that guard didn't die,
otherwise, you would
have met
the guillotine.
Now you'll be
transferred to the island
of Saint-Joseph,
where you'll serve
a two-year sentence
in solitary confinement.
It's not
rehabilitation.
We know
that's useless.
So, we do our best
to break you.
Strange things
happen there.
Especially to those
who cling to hope.
Because there is no hope
on Saint-Joseph.
Just silence.
You heard the warden.
Silence must be observed
at all times.
YAWNTiC Encode | www.movieddl.me
Thought you grew wings,
didn't you?
Grab him.
I'll teach you
to be quiet.
You make another peep,
you might not survive
your time here.
Come on. He's crazy.
Come on. Come on.
Enjoy your next
two years here.
Dega.
Hold on.
Need to check that.
What is that?
Somebody paying you
to bring this shit in,
you son of a bitch?
Who's paying you?
Who's paying you,
you son of a bitch?
Jesus.
I think you killed him.
Get that body out of here
and clean up the mess.
What the hell
were you thinking?
No wonder you
haven't broken yet.
How long has it
been going on?
You may speak.
Who sent you
those coconuts?
If you don't fess up,
I'll put you
on half rations.
You're choosing
another man's life
over your own.
Put him on half rations.
I brought you
some soup.
It's got meat in it.
Just tell me his name.
Tell me his name.
Do you think a person knows
when he's going mad?
Or do you think
it's blissful ignorance?
'Cause you're
about to find out.
Put him in darkness
for the remainder
of his sentence.
Or the remainder
of his life.
Whichever comes first.
Six.
This is a good escape.
Is he still alive?
The years are up.
I know that some
of you at this very moment
are thinking about escape.
Feel free to try
whenever you like.
We'll be happy
to shoot you.
However, should
you avoid that mercy,
there are two guardians
who are always on duty.
The bush, where
the best thing that can
happen to you is starvation.
Or you could
choose the sea,
where sharks, too,
are always hungry.
If you
manage to survive
your first attempt,
you'll get two years
in solitary.
Second attempt,
five years in solitary
followed by
a life sentence
at Devils Island.
If you commit murder,
you'll be executed.
That's all.
Papi.
I wanted
to come sooner,
but I was afraid
you wouldn't wanna see me.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault
you're here.
As you predicted,
my appeal's
run into some problems.
But my wife's
doing very well.
She recently
married my lawyer.
Well, to hell
with her then.
You son of a bitch.
I thought you'd gone
simple on me.
That's the idea.
You know, you'd have had
a much easier time
if you'd just given
them my name.
It's not like I didn't
think about it.
I just know how
goddamn delicate you are.
Hmm.
I fear under
similar circumstances,
I would've fared differently.
I don't know
how you made it.
I just got used
to the silence.
If I ever get out,
I'm gonna live
a different kind of life.
This Sunday, the warden
will be showing a film
in the courtyard
entertaining some
local politicians.
It'll be loud.
The guards
will be doing double
duty, spread very thin.
This is your best chance.
Can you get a boat?
No.
What about Celier?
Is he still here?
Unfortunately, yes.
If he can
still get a boat,
do you have enough
money to pay for it?
I might, but then
he'd wanna come with us.
"Us"?
Us.
All right.
But we still need a boat.
You leave now.
Leave!
Get out!
This man's mad!
Go!
Get out!
He's out of his mind.
No! No, no, no!
No!
No! Help me!
He's out of his mind.
Help me!
Help!
Here.
Come on, come on.
Calm down, calm down.
Let him go, let him go.
It's okay, it's okay.
Bring me some pills.
Come on. Take one.
Bring me some water.
Swallow.
You'll be okay.
Lights out, 10 minutes.
Stop. Relax.
Relax.
Get off!
I will never
let you fuck me.
Shh.
You will soon,
if you know
what's good for you.
Hey. Hey,
I just want to talk.
I'm not a goddamn whore.
That's not what I want.
Yeah, everybody
says that until they do.
Trust me, I don't.
I got a different
proposition.
If you repeat one word
of this, it's not going
to be good for you.
I don't want
to know, then.
Maybe you do.
Look, I'm putting
something together.
This Sunday.
We got room
for one more.
I have nothing
to offer you.
I need you to
distract that turnkey.
Get him to come in here
at a certain time,
keep him occupied.
If I do that,
your plan better work.
It'll work.
It's not going
to be easy.
Can you handle yourself?
You were framed
for murder, right?
Well, nobody framed me.
That's Celier.
He's gotten us a boat.
Let's see
the arm. Infected.
Good job.
Papi!
You skinny son of a bitch.
Good to see you.
What'd you do
to your arm?
I had to cut myself
to get in here.
It still work?
Yeah, it's nothing.
Don't think about it.
I can still kick your ass.
Can we hurry this up?
I have to get back.
Birdie, can you
shut up for once?
This is Maturette.
He's our fourth.
Oh, yeah?
You know how
to handle yourself?
Yeah, with a knife.
All right, take it easy.
Oh, feisty little
one, huh?
You all set?
Yeah, I'm set.
I got a guy
that's hiding a boat
on the bank.
It's upriver a ways.
From there,
it's a straight shot
to the ocean.
But we need
half the money now.
What about you?
When the film starts,
we'll go through
the warden's building.
I'll have a key.
We got a plan.
You all right?
No.
I'm not sure
we can trust him.
Look at him.
He's unpredictable.
He's like
a caged animal.
We're all animals
in here, pal.
He'll be fine.
He needs the money now.
Here.
It's the sedatives
they gave me.
Get them
in the guards' coffee.
We'll do the rest.
I have to get back.
Hey.
You're doing good.
What do we
have here, huh?
Go to hell.
Give me those back.
He's going to
fuck up our plan.
He's going to be fine.
What the...
What are you doing, man?
All right!
That's enough.
Break it up. Break it up.
He does the
warden's books.
Huh...
I'd have figured I'd know
how to throw a punch
considering
how often my father
used to beat me.
Yours, too?
My parents
are schoolteachers.
See you tonight.
Anisette for the warden.
The best you have.
Just give me the bottle.
There's two or three.
Would you gentlemen
like your coffees freshened?
Yeah, bring it on in.
Compliments
of the warden.
Very nice.
Here.
If we kill someone
and this goes wrong,
it's the guillotine.
No one dies.
Give me another
one of them.
All right.
Dega, where
are you going?
Dega. The warden. Now.
Stop!
What was that?
I'd better go check.
It's working.
Oh, man.
We're too early.
Louis, do you
have a light?
Yes, of course, sir.
No.
Okay, go inside.
Everybody, go inside.
Come on.
Come on, darling.
Fuck.
That's our way out.
No, no.
What's he doing?
Power's out.
Oh, fuck.
Papi, we got to move.
We can't stay here.
We wait for Dega.
Forget about Degal
He's not reliable,
and you know it.
Let's just go. Come on.
You want to go?
Go.
Are you with me?
Hell, yeah.
Open the gate.
What's wrong with you?
I stole the keys
to get us up
to the central walkway.
We can take that
to the guard tower.
As long as
the lights stay off,
they won't see us.
And then we jump?
You got a better idea?
Come on. Come on.
Go, go!
I've got the wall.
You! With me
to the south wall.
Yes, sir!
Yes, we're on lockdown.
Section secured!
Oh, shit.
All right.
Come on. Let's go.
Easy.
Lock it down!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
oe Let's go. Come on!
Go, go, go.
Go.
Come on.
Jump!
Come on!
They're going to see
you! Come on.
Come on.
Jump!
Come on. Jump!
Shit.
Hey, it's broken.
Leave him.
He's got the money.
Maturette, help me.
Christ.
All right, come on.
Let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
How much further
to the boat?
You're slowing
us down, Dega.
Come on.
We've got to move faster.
Don't take another step.
You're not taking me back.
That depends.
Do you have my money?
Hey.
Papi, it's okay.
This is my guy
with the boat.
Where's our boat?
It's a ways up the river.
You want me
to take you there?
Pay me.
Or fuck you.
This is all I have left.
Let's
keep that between us.
Enjoy your freedom.
Fucking jerk.
Fuck!
What kind of shit boat
did you get us?
Shut up, Degal
You're lucky to be here.
Keep bailing.
Get it out of the boat.
I'm trying.
Don't throw it at me,
Dega. God damn it.
Throw it in the water.
I'm throwing it
at the water!
Maturette!
Yes?
Check the tiller.
I got it, I got it.
Papi, this boat can't hold
all of us. You know it.
We need to lighten
the weight.
He's going to die
anyway, Papi.
Nobody needs to die.
Fuck! It fell off!
Fix the tiller.
Fix the tiller!
It's broken.
Move.
Here, take this.
Take this.
Maturette, help me.
This storm is gonna
sink the boat.
We need to act,
and we need to act now.
Just let me get
the boat ready.
Did you lose your
mind? Huh?
You want to die
because of this guy?
Nobody needs to die.
Well, we can't all live.
Dega, he's dead weight.
How much money you have?
He doesn't have any money.
He doesn't have any money?
You hear that, Maturette?
They've been lying to us.
You want to die for him?
That makes it
two against one,
Papi. Step aside.
No need to do anything.
Step aside, Papi!
I'm not going to
die for that guy.
Last chance, Papi.
Step aside!
I don't know about you.
I'm going home!
Shit.
Dega.
Stop! Stop!
Enough.
That's enough.
Welcome.
I was traveling
with two other men.
They're being cared for.
Where are we?
This is Colombia.
We know where
you've come from.
But you need
only repent.
Allow God back
into your life,
and you'll be forgiven.
You should go
and wash yourself.
Then come
and pray with us.
We need to keep moving.
They know where
we came from.
Our deal is done.
I told you we
couldn't trust him.
I'm leaving.
With or without you.
Good luck.
Papi, we made it!
Papi, it's
paradise here.
Yeah, but it's not home.
Not for me, anyway.
Good luck, Maturette.
We're leaving.
Now!
Come on.
Papi!
Maturette!
Repent!
If you are truly sorry
for what you have done,
then you have
nothing to fear!
God will watch
over you.
You came back.
Come on, Papi.
I had to come
and see this for myself.
Few men survive
five years in solitary.
What were you living for?
'Cause I don't think
you're going to find it
where you're going.
Devils Island.
Let me out!
Now, what's the son
of two schoolteachers
doing in a place like this?
Well,
what do you think?
I've had five years
to work on it.
The warden wasn't very happy
with my disobedience,
so he sent me straight
here to Devils Island.
Let's get some
food in you.
Rise and shine.
Come on.
There's work to be done.
Let me out!
Can we get to the ocean?
I know what
you're thinking.
But even if you
survive the fall,
you'll never
survive the ocean.
It's all about the waves.
What?
What are you
talking about?
What do you think
I'm talking about?
Oh, go back to bed.
That's suicide,
not escape.
No, listen.
All we need to do
is build a raft
and get it to the ocean.
The tide will take us
straight to the mainland.
Just come and see.
Come and see.
See? We ride
the current to freedom.
I'm a little concerned
about your ability
to protect me right now.
Don't worry.
The fall will
probably kill us.
Let's tie
these together.
I need to stay.
What are you
talking about?
I need to stay.
For the same reason
you have to go.
I belong here.
It's okay.
It's good.
Come on, now,
you don't want to
waste any more time.
Louis!
I made it, you
dirty little forger!
This is for you.
Thank you.
Sir? Your water.
You're welcome.
I'm surprised
you risked coming back.
I'd read the statute
of limitations.
You're still a wanted man.
I won't be here long.
My home is Venezuela now.
But it's important
that my memoir
be published here,
in France.
My wife convinced me
to write it all down
while I'm still young
enough to remember.
So, is this
really your story?
It's the story
of a lot of men.