- You don't remember me, do you?
- Fuck off! Fuck...
WE'RE SCREWED
Jose, she's here.
Did you find it?
Don't wave.
OK.
Mom, hurry up.
Mother!
5 YEARS AGO
- ¡Riley!
- He's back.
- Just keep going.
I know you can hear me.
Honestly,
I don't know what you were thinking.
Sorry, Peg.
I said I was sorry.
This parking lot is
where we settled.
Everyone knows it,
from here to the Pottery Barn.
We have earned this
position because we sell...
more Christmas cookies
for the Fireflies, that no one.
Maybe if you went to a meeting of
Den's mothers, you would know that you are...
Well, not all of us can
sit in our perfect little houses,
South of the Boulevard, Peg.
Some of us
we have to work.
I will file a formal complaint...
in the next one
Den mothers meeting.
Okay, do it.
I don't think you're material
for the Firefly troop.
Neither.
Come on, Penelope.
What an idiot.
- Don't say that.
- Well, it is.
Well, maybe so. But still...
You should have given it to him
a punch in the face.
A punch in the face?
You can't go around hitting
to people who are idiots.
Then you'll be so bad
like them.
Mother,
I know you took the morning off.
Thank you for trying to help me.
Do you know how amazing you are?
Happy birthday, get in the car.
Run, run, run.
Come on, come on.
Listen, I wouldn't ask you...
When do you think it will be?
Next month.
True. Yes, thank you.
- Hello, daddy.
- Hello, little girl.
- How are you?
- Hello.
- I'm fine.
- GOOD.
- I should be home by 4:30 pm
- OK.
Someone is going to have one
birthday party.
The other children
They will be there at 4:00 pm
Can you handle them by
half an hour on your own?
How many other children?
All my friends, daddy.
Chris North, everything in your life
has prepared for this moment.
Hey, I'm going to be late. I love you.
I love you, goodbye.
- I love you.
- Bye, guys. Bye!
Come here, birthday girl!
Hello, Mr. Watson.
I'm late. Sorry.
Well, we'll talk.
about it later.
I have to do some
Christmas shopping.
- OK.
- And I need you to close today.
- Today, it's actually...
- Dee-Dee called in sick.
So you'll be closing.
- It's my daughter's birthday...
- You asked for overtime.
I'm giving them to you.
You will be closing.
Are you sure, Mickey?
Are you really sure?
- Because, don't put me in a situation...
- I have children too.
Ten minutes and our
lives will change.
The lives of our
children will change.
Nobody knows, nobody will know, everything
all you have to do is drive.
I'll take care of everything else.
I don't know, Mickey. I don't know.
You want to get Riley a house,
TRUE?
A good school for Carly.
This shitty mechanic,
It's not going to get you there, buddy.
This will do it.
Hello!
I'm here now.
Happy Birthday...
Where is everyone?
Nobody came.
Nobody came?
Riley, Peg.
Let's forget that little problem,
in the parking lot,
We are having a little
Penelope invited the whole class.
I think Carly's invitation
Feel free to stop by.
I'm sure you remember
Hope to see you girls.
I told you.
You should have given it to him
a punch in the face.
You know what, my friend?
We don't need them anyway.
It's your birthday.
My birthday sucks!
Carly, the language.
He does.
We're going out for pizza.
We'll do it, just the three of us.
It will be fun.
And then we're going to go...
We are going to the Christmas carnival.
- Yes!
- Yes, the Christmas carnival.
And when we get there,
we are going to ride every attraction,
already play all the games.
We will do all the infestation tests
of viruses and germs... Whatever.
But I'm okay with that,
It's your birthday.
- And then...
- Frozen?
- Frozen.
- Ice cream. Yes!
Fuck yeah.
Ice cream, yes, all you want.
All right, we're going to have a great night.
Go get a jacket.
- Come on, come on.
- Yes! I'll be ready in a second.
Sorry, I just...
Hey, honey...
it's not always going to be like this.
Do you promise me?
Yes. I promise.
Come here.
This is Mickey. I'm not here.
Mickey, hi, I'm Chris.
I'm out.
I won't risk it.
It's not worth it, my friend.
Okay, listen, I'm sorry.
Call me when you hear this.
- Where is your dad?
- It's out here.
GOOD.
Carnival!
OK.
Here we go.
Carnival. I'm so excited.
It's me. Is the boss around?
I found the other one.
Oh really,
are you trying to scam me?
Did you really think that you
Would you get away with it, Mickey?
Boss, it's for you.
Es Cortez.
I have to take this call.
I hope you don't mind, Mickey.
Talk to me. What's wrong with you?
I'm following the other guy.
Liquidate it.
Let it be an example.
A very noisy one.
Mickey,
is this what you wanted?
Will this make all your
problems disappear?
Are you feeling okay?
Have some money on you.
- TRUE?
- No...
TRUE?
Damn fucking.
King! I am the King!
More like the Queen.
Give me that one.
High five!
I kept my eyes open
almost all the time...!
I hope I look smart.
- Not so much.
- Look at me.
You're a brat.
- Quite charming.
- Frozen!
Let's go for some ice cream.
- Come on.
- Here we go, here we go.
Hello, what's it going to be?
Two of his best Rocky Roads,
and...
Yes, and whatever the miss...
Mint. Double scoop.
And one of two mint balls.
- OK.
- It's her birthday.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- With the...
- Yes, I agree.
My God, look at that.
Can I prove that?
- Do you like it?
- No, I don't like it.
- Birthday girl.
- Bye, cupcake.
- I'll get a napkin.
- OK.
OK.
- Do you mind if I have one?
- Yes of course.
- Thank you. Have a good night.
- Goodbye, goodbye.
- I know.
- Every day!
Birthdays every day.
Hey, make sure that
we can put it in the car.
List?
Three, two...
Adult woman, 35 years old.
Gunshot wound to the head.
Severe cerebral hemorrhage,
vital signs remaining.
Closing.
We're ok.
May I browse?
It's a mess, I understand.
But you have to put
your serious face.
We have a job here,
OK?
It's not easy when you're a kid.
It's not supposed to be easy.
That's the difference
between us and them.
I was supposed to be called in
the moment he woke up.
You don't wake up from a
medically induced coma,
as easy as turning on a
light switch.
The shot may not hit him.
has hit the brain,
- but brain inflammation...
- But will it be okay?
The "it's okay" is
out of my hands.
When he recovered his memory...
We had to contain her
and had to be sedated.
Mrs. North.
My name is Detective
Stan Carmichael...
Detective.
I've been waiting to talk
with you for a long time.
I am so sorry for your loss.
Forgive me for appearing
so suddenly,
but, we have three
suspects in custody,
to whom otherwise
we would have to release tomorrow.
Detective, this is not the time.
I... I can talk.
We believe that what happened can
be related to her husband.
There were rumors that
was involved...
in a plan to rob
a drug dealer...
called Diego Garcia.
I wouldn't do it...
He wouldn't do that.
No, yes, you are absolutely right.
We recovered a voice message
on your friend's phone,
her husband refused to continue
go ahead with this, but,
the word had already spread.
And, back with Garcia.
Now, an informant has informed us
given a very credible lead,
but no witness is there
willing to take a step forward.
We know everything,
but we can't prove anything.
Detective.
I think that's enough
for now.
Get some rest,
Mrs. North, I'll be back.
But I...
I thought you'd want to have this.
Yes I saw them.
All right, bring them on.
Come on. Get in there.
It's number five.
Number five, one step forward.
Get them out. Next group.
Number three.
Number three, one step forward.
That's him.
The four.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Hey, thanks.
What's wrong, aren't you hungry?
Tell me what this is.
That would be a Detective badge.
That's all they found of the
last policeman who went after Diego Garcia.
It was in his locker,
hanging in a locker here,
inside the Headquarters of
Metropolitan Police Homicides.
Does Garcia have people inside?
Garcia has a nickname,
There's a reason for that shit,
Stan.
Chris North is
He didn't even rob Garcia.
He just considered it, and ended up on the side
wrong side of the lawn, with his daughter.
Whatever happens with this case,
let it happen.
Don't be stupid.
They will only kill you and
that won't change anything.
Hello?
- Mrs. North.
- Who are you?
I hope you don't mind
that has entered.
I am... I am a friend.
Do you want to sit down?
What do you want?
Eviction notice.
I can only imagine how horrible
what all this has been like for you.
I mean, how can you
start to recover from something like this?
Why are you here?
I just want to give you some advice.
The road to recovery
has to start somewhere.
The recognition that...
As heartbreaking as it may be,
In the end, nothing will come of it
back to his family.
I know, and that's the sad thing,
but inevitable truth.
Possibly,
maybe not immediately,
but in the end the moment will come
to keep going.
New place, new clothes,
new memories.
A new life.
What is this?
Lorazepam. Lithium. Resperidone?
It is an antipsychotic.
Listen!
I think it's time for you to go.
Maybe he made a mistake.
His memory is a little fuzzy.
I'm just putting it out there.
Maybe he didn't see things...
the way in which
he thought he had seen them.
Get out of my house.
Get out of my house!
Get out of here!
Do you think you're going to get justice?
Make everyone pay?
You won't have it.
Go fuck yourself!
Is there anything else you want to ask?
to the witness, Mr. Henderson?
One last question, Your Honor.
Mrs. North,
just to clarify one point.
Did you see them get out of the car?
No.
Did the car stop moving?
And yet you identified my clients?
like the alleged shooters?
- They did it.
- I object, Your Honor.
I ask that it be reached
a legal conclusion.
Accepted.
Ms. North, we are interested in the facts.
No opinions.
He just asked me one question.
- And I just answered.
- Alright.
Identified my clients,
correct?
- Yes, I did. They were...
- Okay. Okay.
And are you taking any?
antipsychotic medication?
That?
- Lorazepam. Lithium. Resperidone?
- Wait.
- Is there anything else we should know?
- But that's not...
Wait, that's not accurate.
He identified not one,
but to three men...
in a moving vehicle
at night at a distance of 10 meters.
- After a month in a coma...
- I saw them.
- And a mental breakdown...
- It's not something that is forgotten.
And under the influence of
antidepressants and antipsychotics.
Excuse me, you're not listening to me.
Is it possible that your memory
not be who you thought you were?
No.
There are no further questions, Your Honor.
Wait, but you're not listening to me.
Can you help me here?
He is the District Attorney.
Can't you do anything?
I didn't even take those pills...
It is the opinion of this Court
that in this preliminary hearing,
the evidence is insufficient...
for a jury
reasonably conclude...
that the State has complied
with their burden of proof.
I see no reason to retain
the accused for trial.
Wait a moment.
This can't end.
- These men killed my family.
- Mrs. North, you may leave.
No, they killed my family!
- This guy showed up at my house.
- You may leave, Mrs. North.
No, I'm not done!
You may leave, madam...
- He offered me money!
- Mrs. North.
- No, no, no, no! I'm not finished!
- Mrs. North, you may leave!
They are murderers!
They are fucking murderers!
Mrs. North.
Officers!
Get away from me!
I'm going to kill them.
Officers, get this woman out of here.
Mrs. North, the
I will be sending a...
treatment program
mental health.
Next case.
Why is it bleeding?
What happened to him?
He kept hitting his head
head against the bars.
- Now she's all yours.
- OK.
Mrs. North? Riley,
I'm Detective Stan Carmichael.
Can you hear me?
Hey guys, let's go.
He saw his family murdered and the
guys who did it walked away.
How about you relax?
List?
One two three.
- Where are you going?
- County General, a internarla.
That place is a nightmare.
County General, a internarla.
They hold on.
Let me make a call.
Understand!
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
I'm sorry.
NORTH
Well, you said it.
It will appear.
One way or another,
they always do.
THE PRESENT
Carmichael, 3-8-7-7-7,
Gang Homicides.
Aren't you especially
beautiful this morning?
Thank you for coming.
I have always firmly believed
in restful sleep.
Professional advice.
Wait until you are
dead before being embalmed.
Well,
that's new.
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE
- Good morning, Lisa. Do you have a minute?
- That?
Someone drove a truck
to a gun shop...
in San Bernardino,
a couple of nights ago.
The place was
class 3 armament.
And military grade stuff.
The ATF called us after reviewing
security recordings.
It was a woman. They have a part
from the suspect's face.
Give it to the DHS Fusion Center.
Let them run it through their system
facial recognition.
I already did it. I have a possible
Customs coincidence...
in a stowaway incident,
a container ship,
in the port of Los Angeles
three months ago.
Your name appeared in the
case file, so...
Inman.
Maybe you're thinking
the same as me?
Carmichael.
Who?
Yes of course.
The FBI wants to talk to us.
The Federals?
Have they run out of terrorists?
How do the Feds care?
for a mother who takes to football?
Didn't it hit him in the
head five years ago?
Hitting idiots no
It is a federal crime.
Bank robbery is.
The night that Riley North
they got away,
stole $55,000 from the
Bank where I worked.
Are we talking about the same thing?
Riley North? Bank Robbery?
She just disappeared,
completely off the grid,
as if it had ceased to exist.
You're fucking with me.
She wasn't that type.
I agree.
A woman with no criminal record, even if
his family is brutally murdered,
He doesn't just get up and take $50,000.
and then he leaves.
It caught my attention.
How many times did he betray
to your oath, Your Honor?
I think it's so corrupt,
that they didn't even notice.
OK...
So, here's the deal.
If you can tell me my name,
I'll let him live.
I mean, he'll eat for a
lived the rest of his life,
but he will live.
Are you ready?
Do you remember my name?
Interpol tagged her
four months later.
He used his real name in
a hospital in Hong Kong.
He showed up with a dislocated shoulder,
facial fracture, ruptured spleen.
- A car accident?
- We don't know.
He left before
we could stop her.
He disappeared.
From time to time,
a clue comes from somewhere.
We can almost corroborate some of them,
to others not.
It's a shit magnet. Why?
are they wasting our time?
So,
we found this on YouTube.
Wait, is that...
Is that Riley North?
The same,
in Europe last year,
under one of the four identities
that we have tracked so far.
She became very, very good at
stay off the radar.
So he spends the last five years
bouncing all over the world,
learning to get into trouble.
AND?
We don't know exactly
what was I doing.
What we do know is
who arrived in Los Angeles...
three months ago.
Security cameras
they got this during...
a shoplifting
of weapons a few days ago.
She just took it
military grade.
Automatic rifles, high-power shotguns
capacity, specific ammunition.
I knew exactly
what I was looking for.
She's back.
And today, they found the three guys
who allegedly killed his family.
Hanging, execution style.
Do you know what today's date is?
- What do you say?
- The date.
What is today's date?
It's December 21st.
The fifth anniversary of the
murder of his family.
This thing wrapped around you is
detonation cord, explosive cord.
You can cut any
thing with this.
Cut down trees, cut down concrete...
To corrupt judges.
Watching someone take everything away from you...
All you have,
everything you're going to have,
just go away.
It hurts, right?
And knowing that it's all over,
and there is nothing you can do
do about it.
He did not serve justice,
Your Honor. But I will do it.
Carmichael.
That?
OK.
Thank you.
¿Steven Goldman y Robert Henderson,
the Prosecutor and the lawyer
at that hearing,
- five years ago?
- Yes.
Goldman was found
face down in his pool...
and Henderson's house is
set fire with him inside,
last night, both of them.
And that's not all.
The bomb squad of the Police of
Los Angeles is currently in the place...
from the residence of
son of James Stevens,
Judge of the Criminal Court,
recently retired.
A kind of
explosion in his house.
There was hardly enough of him left,
to fill an evidence bag.
I don't think I have to
tell them who he was.
We need to go further with this.
APB, the media of
communication, the whole thing.
That looks good. Stack it up.
We need to talk to you.
- We have a problem.
- That?
Just a minute.
Our informant called.
She caught a Judge and...
And a lawyer we pay.
He also liquidated some
of our friends.
Those we send to
eliminate her husband.
When the fuck was that?
About five years ago.
Is there a problem?
No, just...
Go and get Jessica out of the car,
bring it with a couple of shots.
And that matter?
Set a reward for
his head,
and we leave it for today.
Some personnel things.
You know how it is.
I have ten more tons...
Your nonsense is not the
reason why I'm here.
Know,
you shouldn't play with the Cartel.
I came to deliver a
message from my father.
It's just a misunderstanding.
If a shipment is lost,
maybe it's a mistake.
But two?
In a week?
Do you think I tried to steal from them?
Would it have lasted?
so much being stupid?
Everyone wants
be a big dog.
Little dogs trying
from eating my food.
That's all it is.
Hello, babe.
Get the fuck out of here.
There is something you have to remember.
You're still a puppy.
Don't let our affairs
have interference again.
Who is that for?
It's for you.
Thank you.
Is he okay?
Grandma.
Sometimes I have to take care of him.
Stop requested. Please,
Dad. Let's go.
Bye bye.
I told you no
you will talk to strangers.
Understand.
Where did you get that?
shitty toy?
Sit down. Sit down.
Give me your wallet.
OK.
I'm going to need you to
stay still, please.
Okay. What do we have here?
Bryan Hartley, 1214 de
Harlow Street.
Open your mouth, Bryan.
This is one of those moments
that change a life.
Do I have your attention?
I want you to take your child
Christmas shopping.
I want you to give it to him
best time of his life.
I want you to mature and be
the father he deserves.
Did you understand me?
I understand.
- Say it again.
- I understand.
- Do you swear?
- I swear.
1214 Harlow.
I will never forget you, Bryan.
Is it clear?
- Yeah?
- Yes, ma'am.
What are you still doing here?
Let's go.
If you sell him anything else, I'll blow you up.
to pieces you and this place.
Did you understand?
- Do you have a car?
- Yes.
Give me the keys.
Consider it rent.
Understand.
You are in the wrong place.
I'm not really.
Get the fuck out of here.
- What's up, friend?
- What's up?
Listen, I'm about to
to get this money.
In this neighborhood normally
Maureen, ¿puedes decirnos algo más?
What do we know about the
It is suspected that he was
And possibly kill
Authorities believe she is armed.
If you see her,
the phone number
It has been called the
What can be expected from
What will the agencies respond?
What the fuck...?
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Let's go!
Shit.
- Hello.
- Oh, God!
I have questions for you.
You're not busy, are you?
No.
A fire has destroyed
piñata shop in
Loca.
Crazy, crazy.
She's completely crazy, my friend.
You already said that, Marvin.
Yes, well,
I'm saying it again.
So you decided to tell him everything.
The whole damn operation.
Yes, but you would have
done the same thing. It's...
I'm so impressed
because of how stupid you are.
How much did he take?
She... Well,
She didn't take anything. She...
She burned all the money.
It's the last shit that
I need it right now.
Boss, I'm so sorry.
You know you never...
It's just that this was
an extenuating situation...
Shut the fuck up!
Trust me,
we're going to have a short...
a very short conversation
about this in a minute.
Double the security.
Put that bitch in a
box before sunset.
Before I do
that they kill us all.
Thank you, Joanna.
Today, Los Angeles has been
a disturbing series
What some are speculating about
possibly even the
According to sources from the Department
everything seems to lead to the same name,
Riley North.
So who is Riley North?
Looking at social media,
One possible link is that,
the husband and daughter of
were killed in a shootout
There is a storm of speculation
Friends, I'm going to need you.
behind the tape, thank you.
Thirty-four, Asian, male.
- Yeah, hey. Take a look.
- Approximately...
Well, I have a dozen
of witnesses who...
suddenly they were left
blind and saw nothing.
So we have that
in our favor.
What the hell are Koreans doing in
the low-rise neighborhoods with Garcia?
Money laundering.
Garcia is using his
infrastructure to launder your money.
These bastards are not going
to be happy.
It's going to get a lot worse,
if we don't get ahead of this.
We have all the whites and
city blacks looking for,
each camera.
His face is all over the news.
Well, she knows what she's doing.
It's becoming a typical
shitstorm on social media.
Garcia is going to love it
all this attention.
Hey, buddy.
There's something I want you to see.
Here.
Back, thanks.
Well, this is a tough sell.
Do you really think that?
Riley North did this?
Well, your Federal girlfriend thinks so.
- My what?
- Stan, my friend,
you have to concentrate on the task
that you have in your hands. It's embarrassing.
The only interest I have in
Agent Inman is professional.
- If you say so.
- Jesus Christ.
Okay, I'll go to Gangs and Narcotics.
and I'll see if they have any information...
of the locations
suspected of Garcia.
Get a list,
prepare some codes 5,
keep watch and see if he appears.
Be careful who you
you ask those kinds of questions.
- For the love of God!
Here we go again. - Hey.
It only takes a few
types in the right places.
Watch your ass,
that's all I'm saying.
And say hi to Bigfoot for me.
What, a lovers' quarrel?
What about Bigfoot?
Yes, we were debating who would
impress with your FBI prowess.
I won.
So what are you thinking?
Riley North arrived in Los Angeles
almost three months ago.
Aren't you curious?
to know where he has been?
They have a Department of
Crime Analysis, right?
Yes, come with me, I'll take you there.
A Cartel on our ass.
And now the Korean mafia?
What are you going to do now?
I bet Marvin
He told about the laboratory.
- I bet.
- GOOD.
So we sent everyone there
and we kill her when she shows up.
Boss.
How did you find out about Marvin?
The only guy who knew everything.
And she doesn't kill him.
How did she know?
He must have been watching us.
You think?
Those lost shipments,
it was her.
He's been stirring things up,
discovering the
moving parts.
The bitch has been fucking us
fucking around for weeks.
If that is the case,
then maybe I hope that
let's send everyone to the lab.
That dance is over.
The whore wants to have
the damn laboratory,
Well, I'll give him the damn lab.
The system tracks crimes
reported in real time.
From this data, we determine
where to send our resources.
And prevent them
problems spread.
Any anomalies?
Areas of violent crime,
higher than expected?
Besides tonight?
Going back a few weeks,
Is there any area that stands out?
This cannot predict where
will appear next time.
Could you tell me where you've been?
Wherever he goes, people die.
He has to be living somewhere.
Maybe I can locate
where he has been staying,
their base of operations.
Find her that way.
Nothing.
No sector or
neighborhood stands out.
There are no abnormal peaks in the
crimes nowhere.
It was a good idea.
I was impressed.
Really.
Do you want to see something?
really interesting?
I was looking at this
before they arrived.
Social networks are
full of support for her.
She is suspected of
multiple homicide.
Well, for them it isn't.
Now that people know why
what has happened, they support her.
Look.
Come closer. There.
What's that?
¿Skid Row?
Why does it look more
sure Bel-Air?
That's strange.
Has it always been like this?
You save the data, right?
Can you give me a minute?
What's going on?
Do you see anything?
I don't see anything.
She's in.
OK,
so the pattern of crime began
to change about three months ago.
Shit. What's that?
Multiple reports
from an explosion.
Fire. Industrial warehouse,
city center...
You stay here. I'll let you know.
- Inform me? Where are you going?
- I have a hunch.
But we are not talking about a hunch.
That?
The radios are turning on.
What happened?
A warehouse in the center of
Is it her again?
I'll check it out.
Was it on the list of places to
Garcia what did you get from Narco?
- Don't know.
Did you get a list or not?
It's... I haven't known yet
none of them, okay?
But, I'm on it.
They're probably busy, they're
a lot going on right now.
Yes, of course. By the way,
Bigfoot sends his regards.
Come on, Moses, it doesn't mean anything.
They're just...
Hey, are you okay?
Understand.
Hey! Hey, what...?
Hey! Hey! Get out of my car!
Wait, come on!
¡Devuélveme mi auto!
It's them.
They caught her.
What do you have for me?
Boss, we're done for.
You're sure?
She was in there
when it exploded.
There is no way that
survived that shit.
Trust me, he died.
You fools,
are rising in the world.
We will be taking some
Thanks, boss.
Now bring your ass
We will be taking
some decisions!
That's a Police.
How do you know?
Who else would be as foolish as
to bring a new car here?
Hello.
Can I speak to
you guys a second?
Did you get lost?
I'm looking for someone.
Looking for someone.
Nobody is looking for anybody.
Isn't it dangerous at night?
for children?
No more.
Why is that?
Because now we have a
guardian angel.
Is that car following us?
What are you talking about?
I told you to leave that shit,
friend.
- You're getting paranoid.
- Shut your fucking mouth.
Shit.
What the fuck is wrong with that guy?
No.
And.
Boss, look at this.
What makes you think that?
Because I saw her steal the car
And she was angry.
Social networks
about the vigilant woman,
It's them. Open it.
Turn off the lights.
Stay with the boss.
No, please don't do it.
Please don't do it.
I'm not here to hurt you.
- He...
- Go, go.
Fuck.
Don't fucking move!
Who the fuck are you?
What do you want?
What do I want?
I want justice.
Dad?
Come here, baby. Let's go!
Boss?
Where is she? Where is she?
It's okay sweetheart.
It's okay. It's okay.
Boss, we have to go.
We have to go now!
¿Riley?
Good night, Peg.
I remembered the address.
Sorry if we got lost.
the party last time.
Riley, you're crazy.
Everything they said
It is true of you.
Know,
I couldn't help but notice,
that you no longer wear a ring
on that finger.
He left you, didn't he?
For someone younger,
prettier.
Fuck off.
Yes, he...
He's gone, okay?
You're right, I...
Please.
This is...
This isn't going to bring her back.
I... I'm so sorry that Carly and...
Don't say my daughter's name.
Okay. I won't.
They...
You have to lock it up.
You're going to jail
for a long time.
They'll... get you.
This is not...
You don't want to do this.
- Thank you.
- I'm going to...
burn your house down now, Peg,
with you inside it.
GOOD.
Riley.
Riley! Come back here, Riley!
- ¡No!
- Stop screaming, Peg.
- I was just joking.
- ¡Riley!
¡No!
¡Riley!
Moses.
- I have the information you wanted.
- Dime.
Okay, this place is owned by
a foreign company from Belize.
So, any number
of imbeciles it can be...
This is Diego Garcia's house.
Hey, I'm just saying.
Understand,
Have you seen Carmichael around?
I can't communicate
with him on the phone.
It's not my turn to
keep an eye on that guy.
Hey, asshole.
If you see him, tell him to call me.
- I'm a little worried about him.
- Understood.
Hey, Barker.
Barker.
What the fuck is this?
What's happening in Narcotics?
¿Carmichael ha estado
trying to get?
A list of the
Garcia's locations...
of you and you put it off?
Do you have someone trying to
protect that son of a bitch?
- Wait, Moses...
- No, no. Don't give me that "Moses" thing.
I've been trying to call
Carmichael all damn night.
- That?
- Yeah.
Calls, text messages,
emails.
I even passed by his
desktop twice.
We have been trying to coordinate
with him since this started.
Who told you not to?
did we call back?
He did it.
I think it's another police officer.
Where are your reinforcements?
What took you so long?
Sorry, they're a little behind.
What do you have?
I've been snooping around a bit.
Look what I found.
Damn.
The truck neither
it wasn't even closed.
You'd have to be crazy to leave
a vehicle in this neighborhood.
But without a key, with a
arsenal in the back?
People have too much
fear of stealing from him.
I don't think it's fear, Stan.
It's not a software problem that
makes this area low crime.
It is a low crime because of her.
So how do you want to do it?
Put surveillance,
arrest her when she returns.
- We can catch her alive.
- ¿Viva?
Obviously he has been watching the
Garcia's operation for weeks.
Only God knows what
that has been discovered.
We make him talk, we catch him
to him, to his suppliers,
everything and everyone.
If the rumors are true,
Garcia has someone
giving you tips from within.
And she has come closer than
what we will never do.
I'm going back to the office,
I will coordinate the interagency, the FBI,
DEA, Los Angeles Police,
and Internal Affairs.
Hey, Inman, I have to tell you something.
- Yes, what?
- I'm sorry.
I know where to find her.
Stay where you are.
Gather your people.
Tell those idiots that it is
time to earn your money.
I don't care if we have
to burn the city.
But this shit ends
tonight. Understood?
Let's bring these sons of bitches.
I have someone in the
emergency center.
Any call from this area
will be directed through it.
We have to do it quickly.
Is this smart?
We are advertising
ourselves.
I don't know if he's here yet.
If she is here,
we will find her.
Okay, let's go.
Hey! Get up!
Get out of here.
Check over there.
Mami.
You have to wake up, now.
We have something here.
Warehouse, west of the alley.
Let's go.
Talk to me, guys,
Did they find her?
Maybe so.
Shit.
Man down.
Cortez, we heard gunshots.
Cortez.
Listen to me.
Get out of here.
Leave these people alone.
Just give me Garcia and go.
Or I swear to God,
I'll kill everyone and...
to each one of you.
Your choice.
He's lying!
I can hear the pain in your voice.
You are suffering.
You are suffering a lot.
Without people, with fewer weapons.
How do you think this is going to turn out?
I'm going to shoot you in
the fucking face.
And then I'll think about it from there.
See you soon.
He contacted the Agent
- She doesn't answer me either.
- Shit.
We have to find her.
Let's see if we can get the
Inman's cell phone location.
Find out where he went last time
who called a tower.
Yes, I already got ahead of you.
Hey, I'm Special Agent Li.
I need the location
from a mobile phone.
I'm Barker from Narcotics.
Special Agent Lisa Inman.
I need a Stingray pickup truck
immediately, in the Los Angeles area.
- 323555-9357.
- What? Yes, yes, right now.
Where is the remote control?
for TV?
- Where is the remote control?
- Here.
- I'll show you right now.
Look.
OK.
Summer,
That guy is a corrupt policeman.
Son of a bitch.
That scum over there...
That's Diego Garcia.
He is the man who killed
If you have a news team,
And if you have a mobile phone...
and if you want to come and take videos,
And if they are the Los Angeles Police,
this is where the party is.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm Riley North. I'm on Skid Row,
I'm on the corner of
- We have a location!
Let's go! Let's go!
Let me go! Let me go! No!
- Detente.
- Understand.
Come on, buddy. He's just a kid.
You're in this.
You've always been in this.
You want to get out,
just nod your head.
No, you're right. I'm in.
Maria!
Hey, there's going to be a dead whore soon,
can you hear me?
I have someone here
that I want you to know.
Say your name, darling.
Tell him your name.
My name is Maria.
Maria, here,
is about to die, because of you.
Damn. Looks like you don't have
Good luck with the little girls, huh?
No! Stop!
I'm going to count to five.
Then I'll blow his fucking head off.
A...
¡No!
Of the...
Maria.
Three...
Four...
I'm on my way. I'm on my way.
The SWAT team is ten away
minutes behind us.
Forget it. We're not going to wait.
Drop the gun!
Is it her?
Are you okay?
I knew you would save me.
I already knew it.
You were right.
Here I am.
Let her go.
You have to go now, Maria.
You have to come with me.
- I can't. I wish I could.
- ¡No!
- Get her out of here. Come on.
- Just go. Take care of yourself.
No! Please!
¡No!
No, let me go! Please!
Let me go!
¡No!
Detente.
Are you afraid of me?
This is when you put one
of your lackeys to shoot me?
Coward.
Don't want to get your hands dirty?
Lift her up.
- I'm waiting.
- We have to get out of here.
He's playing with you.
Making time.
- Just get it over with.
- Shut up, damn it!
Let me have some fun.
¡No!
You hit like a girl.
Jesus.
Do you see that?
He's not playing for shit.
I must say that I am
a little disappointed.
I thought you were going to put up a real fight.
Make it fun for me.
Do you want to hear a secret?
You should have
listened to Carmichael.
Los Angeles Police.
Drop your weapons.
Police!
- You sold me out, you bastard.
They can't get through here.
Stay back.
Hey, hey!
Muévanse! Muévanse!
Get out of my damn way!
¡Riley North!
Back off! We got it.
We'll take care of him.
How did they do last time?
No, he's not going to escape.
Just drop the gun.
¡Riley!
Get down on the ground!
Don't do it.
I beg you.
Please, Riley.
You're completely crazy.
You will spend more time
in prison than me.
We are not going to prison.
Stop the fire!
Fuck!
Where is she?
Aerial, aerial, what do you see?
Do you have anything in sight?
Negative. Negative.
A total disaster.
It could be anywhere.
We will establish a
perimeter of ten blocks, but...
Who knows?
Don't bother. I know where this is going.
I've missed them.
I have missed them so much.
I miss you so much.
Riley.
My husband.
My daughter.
They are waiting for me.
Please let me die now.
I can't do that.
This is not where
the story ends.
It is for me.
I need a doctor! Now!
Thanks. So Riley North
popular heroine, common criminal,
Public opinion seems to
but the law may disagree.
The Los Angeles Police's position
By Chief Matthew Rogers.
The position of the Department of
Riley North will be held accountable
And will be judged by multiple
Questions?
How are you? Detective Beltrán.
I'll take over for a while.
Why don't you take it?
a cup of coffee?
OK.
Hola, Riley.
Do you remember me?
How do you feel?
You killed a lot of very bad people.
You finished an operation
massive drug rush.
You exposed dirty bastards,
in my own Department.
There is no police
that I know that...
Well,
Let's say that some of
we would wish...
that things did not have
to end like this for you.
GOOD...
I hope you get better soon.