Our Father in heaven, hallowed be your name.
"Your kingdom come, your will be done."
On earth as it is in heaven
Give us today our daily bread
And forgive us our sins
"As we forgive those who trespass against us"
And do not lead us into temptation
And save us from Satan
"For yours is the kingdom, the power, and the glory."
From now on and forevermore
"Amen"
Do you know the most important thing your grandfather taught me?
Be prepared
due to hurricanes or floods
or any other disaster
When the food runs out of stores
Grocery stores and gas stations are running low.
...and a dispute arises between people, and
Suddenly the only obstacle will be
Between your life and death is your own behavior
I am proud of you, son.
That was a good shot.
Okay, come on, dear.
Hey, hey
I forgot to bring something.
(Wait a minute, Anna
Ralph, did you bring the deer?
Okay -
I forgot the pie
Are we going to ride the truck?
We'll just cross the road, you idiot.
this is -
Wait for your mother please -
Can you give me a call?
Come here -
You became heavy
Danny's father said that
He might sell me their old car.
I have half of what I need from what I saved
From my summer work
...and I thought you could-
Forget it -
He barely makes me money from my carpentry work.
enough to pay the mortgage
Why don't you rent out my grandpa's old house then?
As I always tell your mom, it's a building.
It's old and would cost a fortune to restore.
Okay, okay
They have arrived
Welcome
Happy Thanksgiving -
For God's sake, Keller.
Please enter here
Keller, did you bring the deer you shot?
This time Ralph did it.
You killed him, so you have to take him to the kitchen.
Good -
Thanks -
Happy Thanksgiving
Thank you, Happy Thanksgiving
(Okay, Joy, Joy
I told you 3 times
Joey, get your blood off the table.
You will miss the match
(to come), (to come) -
Hello, how are you? -
Welcome
Happy Thanksgiving
Anna, come here
We have to wait until
We're invited in, understand?
Well, you're responsible for this.
We are like disappointed butchers
No problem
Can I go out with Joey?
If you convince your brother to go
With you, you can go
Good
And please, put on a hat.
You will overcome the cold
Joey, you too wear a hat.
I felt sorry for that deer.
When did you shoot him?
Do you feel pity for cows?
When you go to McDonald's?
That's what my dad told me.
Deer give birth to many young ones.
And those little ones are starving anyway.
We have to reduce their numbers.
That's right, your father said that too?
Pull more -
Stay away from that thing -
Let me see this -
Come on, let's go -
no -
I said, let's go -
Stop, you can't take things.
Just another person
Let's go -
No, let me-
Let's go, come on, come on
Hey, did you hear that?
There is someone inside
Well I don't want anyone
To shout at me, let's go
Let's go
Not on Thanksgiving, okay?
And now the school committee
They told me there was no
enough money to buy an outfit
New uniform for the infantry division
These children are wearing
same uniform
What we were wearing while we were there
It was already old.
It's a 1979 style.
Why won't he talk to me?
He doesn't talk -
(His name is (Cutie Pie-
Oh, my God -
It's fast -
Very fast, is this a sled?
Thank you, thank you all.
I have a surprise
I will play whatever you request
Okay -
no -
You should listen to this because it's not easy.
My mother
Can I take Joey home?
Why?
My red whistle
You will help me find it.
Oh dear, I think the whistle
Alhambra was lost a while ago
What whistle?
Emergency whistle that
My dad gave it to me. I lost it.
133 days ago
Well, if you want to find the whistle
You should whistle for her.
So we'll sing a song
The bells jingle for us to find
Bells are jingling, Batman stinks.
Robin laid an egg
Batman's vehicle is missing one of its wheels.
The Joker was able to escape... Well done!
Okay, okay -
You can go -
Just ask Ralph.
May I come with you please?
Don't search the basement -
I won't -
Your eardrums are still
It's growing and I don't want to destroy it yet.
I'll play any song you want, Killer.
I? -
It's your day and you can ask -
play the piano
no -
No, no, no -
Ready?
Hey, look he's always loved the singer.
Springsteen) wearing the same dress
truly? -
(Yeah, I love Springsteen-
(Remember the song (The River
And Jersey Girls?
Well, I'm not white.
But I also love him very much.
I'm so drunk
I can't sing the leader's songs
Thank you
What else, dear?
Nothing comes to mind, nothing -
I know -
What? -
He really loves the anthem.
American National
I know, I know, he sings it in the bathroom.
I don't do that
Yes, you do.
I'll play it for you-
Where are your sisters?
I didn't find them
Did... did you go home with them?
No, what are you talking about?
A while ago?
no -
What? They should have left early.
To take you, didn't they come to take you?
No, we haven't seen them since we ate.
decent -
Don't worry, they're probably at our house.
Anna? (Joy?)
Anna)?)
Hey girls?
Hey girls
Who put the plates here?
You weren't out
And it started to rain
Have you looked by Mary's swing?
Okay
Okay, we'll scold them.
When you come back here
Sorry, Grace.
But I will shout at the two girls
What do you say they weren't there too?
You must be home.
Did they come here?
No, they're not here.
Weren't you there?
No, you weren't home.
No, you weren't there.
And I searched the house
All of them are not here
recreational truck
Which recreational vehicle?
There was a truck
You two are playing on it, Dad.
We thought someone was in it.
Where? Where was it? Show me -
Wait here, I'll search.
Around the house again
...Calm down
go this way
We'll meet you on the other side.
Anna)?) -
Joy)?) -
Roger, did you see my daughter passing by?
No, is there a problem?
Anna)?)
Here, Dad, it was.
The truck is parked here.
(to come)? (to come)?)
Hello, hello -
Do you see them?
no -
Welcome -
I didn't find them
Were you playing in this house?
no -
I told you not to come here-
We didn't -
They were playing on top of the truck.
Entertainment, and We sent them down from above it
Tell me everything you can remember.
About that recreational truck
everything -
It had a ladder in the back.
Hey, police please
Happy Thanksgiving
Thanks
Do you have any cakes?
Little luck?
My manager told me that men
Police don't like fortune cookies.
What year of the Chinese zodiac were you born in?
Are you a Dragon, Snake or Horse?
I am a monkey
You are a monkey
You are very smart
You have the ability to influence people.
Maybe you can influence your manager.
To reduce the account a little
No, I can't.
My manager is a rooster
So he is selfish and weird.
...this
To all units, a vehicle has been spotted.
"Entertainment to specifications"
The vehicle was spotted parked in one of the
Rest stops on Route 46
Located north after exit 17
Are there any units available?
Here the 12-12 periodicity responds to the signal" -
Patrol 10-80 responds -
Period 13-40 I'm 5 minutes away
I will meet all units that responded.
Periodical 12-12 Get Ready
Patrol 10-80 ready -
Journal 13-40
I'm in place, we'll move carefully
You, don't move
Beware
Don't shoot, don't shoot
Don't shoot
Okay, Sloane.
Take the right
maternal uncle
It's empty
Okay, wait, wait.
I'll take care of it
give me this
You
See you here
Show me both your hands now
You, I see you raise your hands
Show me both of your hands, now.
So slow, slow, slow
both hands
Both of your damn hands
Oh my, oh my.
Wait
Amish
Get up, get up
Get up
Show me where the girls are?
Show me where you hid the girls?
Where are the girls?
Give me a flashlight
Are they in the forest?
Did you take them to the forest?
Where did you put the girls?
Do you hear me?
What is this guy on?
Yeah, he's on something-
Put that damn thing in the car-
Get in the damn car, walk
Call the Pennsylvania State Police.
Tell them to bring the sniff dogs.
They closed the whole area.
Good -
The entrance and everything -
And you, come with me -
Why don't you play on top of your RV?
both -
Well, take a look at them again.
Don't you recognize these two girls?
I didn't see them, may I sit?
What do you do in a recreational vehicle?
Answer my question
I sleep in it
You sleep in it
Were you sleeping in it that day?
Why did you park your car in front of that house?
I was driving it around.
Were you driving it around?
But you weren't driving it.
I know for sure that the two girls
They were playing outside your truck.
You weren't driving it, it was parked.
Was this a special day?
Did you plan to kidnap the girls?
no -
Have you done that before?
no
Did you ask them to get into the car?
no -
I asked them to come in.
To the cart and then took them?
no -
Did you put the girls in a place?
May I sit down?
Did you put the girls somewhere?
Don't touch me
I know you put the girls somewhere-
Did you hide them?
no -
Where did you hide them? Did you tie them up?
Did you tie them?
You, you
Listen, I know you're a good man, okay?
I know you are a respectable man
I'm not trying to accuse you of committing a crime.
I'm just trying to get the answers.
Right from you, okay?
Real answers, that's all I want.
Where to park your truck
Usually entertaining, Alex?
At my aunt's house
At your aunt's house
Let me park it in the back garden.
where the grass no longer grows
It belonged to my husband.
It's for sale if you want it.
No thank you
Okay, can you tell me what you're doing?
On my own property then
I'm just glad I knew where he was.
He always comes home before dark.
I don't understand
That boy didn't get into trouble.
Throughout his life, not once
In the summer he sleeps outside
...on the bed of the cart, but
At this time of year he sleeps
Here on a folded bed
This is my husband
We had a fight
About... five years ago
He went out and never came back
(Alex), I love him like a father.
Where are Alex's parents?
My husband's brother and his girlfriend
They died in a car accident.
(When Alex was
At the age of six
I'm sorry to hear that.
He doesn't have much.
What did you find?
This truck is clean.
I mean it's so dirty.
But we didn't find anything in it.
Didn't we find any wool fibers?
Or anything like that?
One of the girls might have been wearing a glove.
Or a wool hat, didn't you find any cotton fibers?
Well, I might believe he used it.
This vehicle is for transporting girls.
But if you resist him
I would find something
If I were you, I would search
In the forest next to the rest house
Yes, half officers.
The state is doing it now.
When you're done checking this thing out
Would you send the crew to Auntie's house?
(to come)
(Please come in, I'm Franklin Birch.
My wife is here
(Darling... this is Nancy
Detective Loki is... dear.
These pictures are better
From the one my husband gave you
You can see her eyes more clearly.
Did we succeed?
Excuse me, what did you say?
The thing about lying, the lie test
What we took this morning, did we succeed?
Yes, yes, excuse me
Yes, we appreciate your cooperation.
It's embarrassing, all that fuss.
Everyone will think we're crazy when you come out.
The two girls from their hiding place wherever they were
Do you have a reason to?
You think they ran away?
No, they are happy.
But they must have run away.
I guess they must have run away, right?
The police captain told me you solved everything.
The cases you were assigned, is that true?
I'm sorry
...I'm really sorry, did you
Do you have children, Detective?
I will find your daughter
We think they came here.
After they left the Birch house yesterday
They were searching
About Anna's Red Whistle
Yes, I read your statement.
(I am Detective Loki
I am heading the investigation into your daughter's disappearance.
Please have a seat.
My son already told you that the person who
He was in the truck watching them, wasn't he?
We did not find any physical evidence in the truck.
Recreational or at his aunt's house where he lives
nothing?
Unfortunately, Alex Jones has a low average.
intelligence of a ten-year-old child
It is impossible for a person with such an IQ to
10-year-old boy kidnaps two girls
In broad daylight and then make them
Somehow they disappear
Well, how can he drive?
So the recreational truck?
I mean, if he can't answer a question,
He has a valid license.
(To drive from Pennsylvania
But he tried to escape, didn't he? They said.
He tried to escape.
Why...why did he try to escape?
I just spent 10 hours
In interrogating that boy, shall we?
I understand your point very well -
Did you make him take a lie detector test?
She subjected us to a lie detector test.
Did you subject him to it?
Sir, I understand what you are trying to ask of me.
And yes, we did.
We gave him a lie detector test.
...and it was impossible
Lie detection is useless if it is
The person does not understand the questions
Well, maybe he wasn't alone.
How can he drive a recreational vehicle?
If he had the IQ of a 10 year old?
Sir, we are considering all possibilities.
I don't think you're thinking of all the possibilities -
I understand your meaning, sir.
No, just listen to me -
Just shut your fucking mouth for a second.
This is what I want you to do for me.
I want you to calm down
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
Please hear me out for a second.
Mr. Dover, I understand perfectly well.
This is a very difficult time.
But I made all the police officers
(In the state they are looking for (Anna
I don't understand what any of this means.
But they said he tried to escape.
They said he tried to escape.
I didn't understand why he tried to escape?
We are thinking of all possibilities.
(Mr. Dover
I understand what you mean
I won't cross anyone off my list.
Just... let me do my job.
Your Honor
Damn
It will remain reserved.
Until my daughter is found, right?
Isn't that right?
We can hold him for 48 hours until tomorrow.
This is if we do not prove any charge against him.
So, accuse him of something, accuse him.
Mr. Dover, I understand your suffering.
Your Honor, Your Honor -
Two little girls definitely deserve it.
To break the rule for them
to put that bastard in custody
Now I know you can't
Promise me anything, I understand.
But I ask you to be careful.
%to be 100% sure
Thank you
I appreciate that.
Now, you are sure he is innocent.
But you want to keep it here.
Anna Dover's father was hateful.
Towards me in the morning
I understand and appreciate that.
But it won't happen
You know, all I ask is one day -
Damn you -
No no
When you find his daughter he will forgive you
If you don't, he'll hate you anyway.
What next?
I kept knocking on doors all night.
Yes this is what happens when you have
Missing for 24 hours and no evidence
I have 3 sex offenders.
(Within 10 miles of Fairmont)
So if you don't mind
Go -
Okay -
It's right here.
Listen to me, I'm straight.
Good?
It's not... I didn't
...Listen, I know you
Well, do you enjoy some?
German porn movies?
...Listen, I was just
Open up, father
I am from the police
Father
Do you mind if I look around?
drunkard
What is this?
Amazing
Damn
Damn it
No, please don't, God.
What is your friend's name down here?
What's his name?
I don't know his name -
Don't you know his name?
Did you know that I worked 6 years in prison?
Events in Huntington, Father?
Learn about juvenile detention
In Huntington, right?
Hurt a lowlife like you
It is a real pleasure for me.
Why don't you tell me his damn name?
He refused to say his name.
He came to confess, saying he killed 16 children.
He was proud of it.
I convinced him to come here.
When he said he would kill more
16 children?
Let's go, you bastard.
Welcome -
They will release him.
What? -
That man -
The police announced
They will release him today.
Okay, I'll take care of it.
my dad? -
Keep searching -
Where are you going?
You must write your full name.
This is good
Well done
Now give it to the man.
Okay, let's go.
I don't want you to care about those people.
Don't talk to them, there is no
What you tell them, let's go
Come on Alex, you took
The two girls, right?
my lord -
I just want to talk-
He is a free man and I am a free man
Tell me what you did with them?
Tell me -
They didn't cry until I left them.
What did you say? What did you say?
No, no, no, no
Stay away from him
Stop
to retreat
please let's go
We are fine, thank you
I knew your father when he was a guard.
(in Graterford prison
I also have a daughter
So I'm going to pretend it didn't happen.
(Well? And as for Alex Jones
He has an order not to leave the country.
What?
Sir, I want you to go home.
What did I just tell you?
Why didn't you send anyone?
To catch that bastard?
Tell Detective Loki what you told me.
I just sent it to him and he will definitely look into it.
Come on tell him
That shit you promised to keep
In detention, okay?
And she didn't do that
Tell me now when you catch him
In the garage
He said the words to my face
They didn't cry until I left them.
He said the words to my face -
He told you that in the garage just now?
Now, yeah like I said in the garage
Cars, before you pull me off him.
Anyone else hear that?
I don't know he was talking in a low voice-
He was talking to me
He wanted me to know.
Are you sure he said that?
What? -
Are you sure that's what he said?
Come on, do you think I'm making that up?
Absolutely -
Why would I invent that?
No, I don't think about it.
I didn't say you did that-
I was just asking you a few questions.
I'll talk to him, okay?
No, don't talk to him.
Mr. Dover
Catch him
What did I ask you?
All I asked for was one more day.
Are you sure you didn't say anything to Mr.
Dover) in the garage today?)
Anything I might have misunderstood?
I was there, neither of them said anything.
To the other, but the man attacked the boy
You didn't say anything like, get away from me?
Or help me? Anything like that?
no
May I speak alone?
To Alex for a minute?
It's okay, my love
I'll be in the next room.
You love your aunt
Isn't that right, Alex?
Okay
Do you know if you know something you haven't told us?
She might go to jail for a long time?
Do you want that to happen to her?
After everything I've done for you?
no
Mr. Dover, this is Detective Locky.
Did you catch him?
Listen, I just got out."
From Alex Jones' house
And he told me he didn't say anything to you.
In the garage
I pushed him too hard.
to speak, but he didn't budge.
So we can't waste any more.
Time for this boy
Good?
You have to trust me
I'll let you know as soon as I find anything.
(New Mr. Dover
You bastard
Her coat zipper was broken.
And I told her it didn't matter.
Because we're just crossing the road.
No no -
Why haven't you come home yet?
It's been 3 days
Why can't you bring her back home?
I don't understand, I don't understand
It's been a long time
Please, bring her home.
Please bring it -
How many, how many of these?
How many did you take?
I don't know -
Okay, that's okay, take one.
Take it
no
I just want to sleep
You
you make me feel safe
You told us you could.
Protect us from everything
Oh my God
I will go out to help the police
In search, take care of your mother
Your sister needs us
To be brave for her
Be brave for her, and be mature.
For me, can you do that?
Can you do that?
I know you're scared
Look at me, come here
I know how scared you are
everything will be okay
The past is the reason why
"One must be motivated to be patient.
The reason for his repentance is the coming
"For what he may suffer from distress
"This reminds him that his problems and troubles
They are the logical conclusion that
It should be expected to happen in this world.
Man was created with his problems.
"Not as a mere human being, but as a sinner
"He was a partner in the sin"
Man is born guilty
"So he was born to cause trouble.
Hey, hey, Tucker!
Bells are jingling, Batman stinks.
Robin laid an egg
Batman's vehicle is missing one of its wheels.
The Joker was able to escape.
Bells are jingling, Batman stinks.
Robin laid an egg
(Alex)
That song, where did you hear the lyrics?
Did you bring extra clothes like I asked?
Yes, would you tell me why?
I'd better show you-
Show me what?
Haven't you lived here before?
Close and lock the door
Amazing
Oh my, what have I done?
Keller, what the hell is this?
I heard him sing the same song.
that they sang at Thanksgiving
I swear, Franklin, same song.
And I told you what he said in the garage.
So, let's take him to the police.
No, no, no, the police won't do anything.
Because he'll just pretend to be crazy.
As he did last time
Someone has to force him to talk.
Someone did that
Damn man, this isn't right.
I mean, what if I'm wrong?
(You're not wrong, Franklin, really.
No, no, wait, what if I'm wrong?
What if you could hear what you wanted?
...just hear it? What if
Man I want my daughter back
Just the way you want it
(Oh Franklin, oh Franklin-
This is not right -
We have to hurt him until he talks.
Otherwise, both girls will die.
...this is not-
No no -
We have to hurt him until he talks.
Otherwise, both girls will die.
That is our choice.
This is the choice
What you should do
and I made my decision
Because I know what I heard
He is no longer human
No, he stopped being human.
When he took our two daughters
I need your help
This is your last chance, I know you
Scared and want to go home
Well, I don't want to, I don't want to.
To hurt you, I don't want to
I will remove the tape.
And I want you to tell me where they are.
You, come on
Have you seen my glasses?
What? -
I can't see -
If you don't talk, Alex
I will be forced to hurt you
Tell me where they are?
Yes, I'm in front of the house.
(Located in Fairmont)
That house that was
The RV is parked in front of him.
It was put up for sale a few months ago.
I will track down the owners to find out.
If they know anything
Is there any new information about?
The body we found in the priest's cellar?
We did not find a match with the DNA.
Dental records and fingerprints
nothing? -
The priest also sticks to his story -
Good
"The disappearance of the Connor family member"
The same person who took it
He took the two girls, I'm sure of it.
The tape started to deteriorate.
I think so
I watch it every day after breakfast
It's the only video I have of him.
That was too soon for you.
26 years ago
On August 19
I took a nap in the afternoon and when
I woke up and Barry was gone.
No one could tell me what happened to him.
He was playing in the front yard.
A few feet away from the place
where they said the cart stopped
What do you think that means?
I'm more eager to know what you think it means.
I don't think we'll ever know what happened-
(It's just like what happened to Barry.
Nobody took them, nothing happened.
They just disappeared.
How are you, Dad?
I was better off
Detective Schminsky told me
You have some details
About the crimes that claim
That man committed it
The kidnapper
He...was waging war against God.
Awesome! This is awesome!
I thought you said he knew certain things?
Tell him how he took the children.
He said
He was taking them in broad daylight.
And sometimes... more than one child
at a time
He said that?
Okay -
Did he say someone else was with him?
Or was he alone?
He said he has a family.
That's all?
Okay
Well, this was very informative.
I said they cried when I left them.
Look at me, I said
They cried when I left them.
I said they cried when I left them.
Now tell me, where is she?
Tell me where they are?
Just tell me, tell me and I'll stop.
I'll stop as soon as you tell me.
...only
Just tell me where they are?
Why don't you tell me?
Why don't you just tell me, you bastard?
He knows, he knows
I can see it in his eyes.
He knows
I know you know
Why don't you tell me then?
Why?
Good
Hey, let him stand.
Stop, stop
You will force me to use this.
Will you tell us?
If you don't I'll use this.
Good
You are the one who is to blame yourself
Just tell us
Tell me
Tell me! Tell me!
Where is my daughter?
Where is...my daughter?
It's been 4 days since he disappeared.
"(Anna Duffer) and (Joy Birch)
When she saw them
Their families for the last time
The girls are 6 and 7 years old and were
They were playing in the street and then disappeared without a trace.
"And as you can see, despite the cold"
Many people came
Tonight to support the two families
Police are urging people to report
Any information about the girls' whereabouts?
Where were you? -
I was looking for her in the forest -
I'm fine, I'm fine
(Franklin)
Franklin, what's wrong with you?
I just need a minute
Hey, what the hell?
get away from me
You, you
Good
This is what it looks like
Suspect by police
In the ongoing investigation
Regarding the two missing girls
This unknown man has been seen.
"Last time last night at the candlelight vigil
He ran away on foot.
When the investigator tried to interrogate him,
Police advise the public to
"By not approaching this man
"And inform the police immediately upon seeing him."
"...Thanks (John) for the update."
Listen, Keller.
Think about it
Why would the police look for that man?
If they thought he didn't do it
In the first place?
They did it together, they know.
each other
Listen, I told you so, okay?
He looked straight into my eyes.
He said, "They cried when I left them."
He left them with someone.
He knows his place
Holly Jones's Dog
He was hit by a car on South Street.
(It's clear that Alex Jones
taking the dog for a walk
The night before last
He hasn't come home yet.
His aunt didn't want to tell us about the dog.
until we called her this morning
She said she was afraid that would get into him.
In some problems
I thought you were going to keep him under surveillance.
And I thought you said the boy was innocent.
I thought you said the man I saw
Last night he was our man
Listen, I don't have enough money.
In the budget to monitor the innocent
But you said you'd put him under surveillance.
What do you want me to say?
Did you keep your promise?
You could call me, because I was
I'll stay there all night
I would know where he is now
I would like to know where everyone is.
You made your point.
Agreed? You made it clear.
If you are clear with me, I will be clear
With you, I have to know where everyone is.
If you intend to do something different
Please tell me
Tell me about your truck
What are you doing in your truck?
"It's where I go to be alone."
What music do you listen to?
"And you're in your truck alone?
"...radio, tape"
"Your truck is parked in Fairmont?"
"No, is my aunt coming?"
"...I, I, I, I, I, I"
"Have you seen these two girls?"
"no" -
Take a look at them
"Have you seen these two girls?
"no"
Did you participate in any way?
"In kidnapping these two girls?
"no" -
Loki! You have a call.
Good
I called you as soon as I saw"
"Drawing of the suspect on TV
He comes to visit us every week.
"Almost buys children's clothes
But he always buys clothes.
Different sizes
I caught him playing with a doll.
One-time model
How to pay?
Cash
Okay, call me if you hear anything.
We agreed -
Five days have passed
Maybe they haven't drunk water since then.
Tonight might be our last chance.
Look, I'll call you.
After Nancy goes to sleep, okay?
I promise you
Where have you been all this time?
What in heaven's name are you thinking?
Did you tell anyone?
I would like to see it
please help me
Can you help me find my little daughter?
I have a picture
Look?
This is my structure
Do you see it?
(Her name is Joy
...and...this
Her doll that we bought for her when she was
In the second, because she was afraid to sleep alone
Please tell me where my building is.
Please tell me where my building is located.
I know you'll tell me
I'm sure you will
Help me
"...Franklin, did you close the door to..."
(Nancy)
What do you do?
Damn it!
Damn it
Let go, let go
Did you undo his bonds?
That was close.
What's up? What happened?
Bring Franklin, I want to show you something.
Did he say anything new?
He will say soon, you will see -
No light enters it
barely enough room to sit
The laundry is still working.
But we control it from the outside.
I messed with the water heater.
So the water will come out either burning or freezing.
We will talk to him through this.
It's a reminder for us, just in case.
As soon as we started feeling sorry for him
Oh, my God
I can't hurt him anymore without killing him.
So this is the only way.
Are you out of your mind, Keller?
Got a better idea, Franklin?
Do you have?
Go ahead and take it out if you want.
I won't stop you
If that's what you really want, take it out.
Do you think anyone cares about life?
The two girls are as full of his life?
I hope so
Five days have passed, my friend.
Time is running out
You don't even know he's the culprit.
Yes, I know -
No, you don't know.
Know -
I know you, you don't know -
Look, I want my daughter back.
(As much as you miss Anna
Regardless of what you think of me
I am ready to sacrifice my life for my daughter
But this is not true.
It must end
Well, then it should
You can start working
We can start with that wall over there.
(Franklin)
to stop
Think of Joy
I need to get out of here, Ralph.
Everything in this house makes me want to vomit.
"Your father's building?"
It is impossible for me to stay in the house
This high, it's disgusting.
"Yeah, okay."
We won't help Keller.
But we won't stop him either.
Let him do what he needs to do.
I don't know what to do about it anymore
Eliza?
Sorry -
Eliza, open the door.
Eliza?
Is she in?
My dear?
Get out of the way, get out of the way
Yeah, screw you both.
If you intend to leave me here alone again
At least tell me where you're going.
Ralph?
Anna)?)
My mom?
Mom, what are you doing?
Anna, Anna was here.
Mom, it's freezing here.
Mom, mom, mom, sit down please
Stop, calm down
I will close the window
"And she wasn't here"
Then I heard a voice from my room.
When I entered, I found the window open.
It was not open before
...then (Ralph), came in
...and looked, then
Then... I don't know
Won't you write this down?
The basement, I didn't check it.
We should check the basement.
I'll show you, I'll show you
The two girls know that it is forbidden to go down here.
You're not supposed to come down here.
But I'm not sure
My husband loves
to be prepared for emergencies
Where is your husband, Mrs. Dover?
I was going to ask you about him, he's going out
(To search with the police for (Anna
This is what you should do now.
Does he always stay outside?
Even this late?
Yes, he is still searching until this hour.
About my daughter as long as she is missing, yes
Damn
You, turn around.
(Come on, Mr. Dover
Damn
Why are you following me?
Get in the car
Where did you go now?
I parked my car at a liquor store.
and I bought a bottle of alcohol
You are a genius detective
Think of a solution
I actually meant that before
You were going in the direction
Opposite through parking lot
(Towards Campello Street
Yes, I didn't drink alcohol.
Nine and a half years ago
I realized that if I walked
Around the corner for a while
Maybe when they open
My craving for alcohol goes away
Then I saw you, that helped me
To make up my mind somewhat
There is a bag of sodium hydroxide.
In your basement and half of it is used
Your wife thinks you're helping us.
But you and I know that this is not true.
I used sodium hydroxide.
To bury our dog last year
And resorting to police help seems better.
saying i'm driving around aimlessly
Because I don't know what else to do
Is that what you were doing Saturday night?
Most likely, am I a suspect?
No, I'm asking you because of a man.
I attacked him before, he is missing now
I heard about that, what happened to him?
I thought he was under your control
I'll assume you're addressing this to me.
The question is because you don't know anything.
I didn't consider kidnapping a crime.
A man could commit it and get away with it.
This is correct
Yeah, couldn't he have left town?
Because he's a lowly sinner, isn't that possible?
Because that would mean
It's your fault he ran away, right?
Mr. Dover?
What? -
You have to take care of yourself and your wife.
This is the best you can do right now.
That little girl
She'll need you when she gets home.
Children who are missing for more than a week
The probability of finding them is 50%.
After a month of missing them
They are often not found.
They're not alive, okay?
So forgive me for trying my best.
You know something?
It hasn't been a week yet
You're right, we're on day 6-
It did not pass
Good -
Day 6 -
And every day that passes
You wonder why I can't save her.
Good -
Do you understand that?
Me, not you
I'm the one you're wondering about
Daily!
Good -
So forgive me for not coming back.
home for a good night's sleep
Why don't you search now?
About my daughter instead of arguing?
Don't follow me -
Enough, enough
Mr. Dover, Mr. Dover
Don't think I'll let you drive.
The car after I got drunk, right?
I will walk
As for you, look for my daughter
"Dad, Dad"
"Look, Dad, we found it."
Anna, where was she?
"Grateford guard commits suicide in his home"
I'm not Alex
What are you saying?
What? What?
"I'm not Alex"
Wait a minute, you're not Alex? What?
I'm not Alex
Wait a minute, I don't understand-
Just talk to me -
I waited for him and he didn't come
Hey, no more puzzles.
Just tell me
I'll let you go back to your aunt
If you tell me where they are
I just wanted to play
Don't make me do it again -
And he did not come
Don't make me do it-
...He never came, but I wished -
Why do you make me do this?
help me god
I call upon you, O mighty one, O merciful one
O You who promised forgiveness, forgive my sins.
Damn me
No noise, shut up, make noise
And I will open that tap
I wake up
I won't find two girls here, will I?
Damn you!
What about Alex Jones?
What about him?
I came here for a drink.
I don't want to drink in front of my wife
Look, my father left
I have this building, okay?
Would you mind taking me for a tour?
Why didn't you tell me about this place?
I didn't think it mattered.
Everything matters
The whole building is dilapidated like this.
I will restore it soon
Yes, not organized.
Like your basement, right?
What's up with the survival gear over there?
Pray to God for the best, and prepare for the worst -
I think we agree on that, right?
Hey, hurry up!
Damn
Welcome?
The man you're looking for was just here.
He saw me watching him, so he ran away.
Do you know the license plate number?
Okay
Go home, Mr. Dover.
Welcome
Good morning
Why did you run away from me that night, my friend?
I've never seen you before
Are you sure?
That you went to the right house?
Have you done some shopping?
At Value Mall recently?
Okay
Why? Is shopping there a crime? No.
I can buy the suits from the Brooks Brothers.
Yes, I know.
You bought baby clothes.
truly?
I must have been in a hurry.
Do you have children?
no -
i have nothing
For God's sake
Give me your damn hand
If you move, I'll pass.
A bullet through your damn head
"Here" 40-13
I need an additional unit for inspection.
Address: 437 Carroll Street, possibly
Two kidnapped girls found in the house
Anna, really)
Anna, (Joy)?)
Damn
We took pictures of some of the clothes.
which we found in the suspect's house
Mr. Dover
Mr. Dover, is your wife here?
You won't come
Well, if you can't do an actual recognition,
On any of these pictures
I'll need her to come over and take a look.
Have a seat
So he confessed, he said he killed them?
We hope he's lying, but we haven't found any.
...any bodies, Mr. Dover, but
The British family got to know
On two pieces of clothing already
I want you to tell me
If you recognize anything
no
I'm not sure, I don't know
Good
no
this
This is her sock
I...wasted time
You wasted time chasing me.
I let it happen.
Don't talk to them
Eliza told me they were dead.
Is this real?
no -
She said they found
Their clothes were stained with blood.
Don't tell your mom that, don't you
You dare to tell your mom, okay?
Now I want you to listen to me.
I would like you to stay home for a few days.
And be careful not to let her watch the news.
And if the newspapers came
Throw it away, listen to me
We will not lose hope in your sister, we will not
I will find her and bring her home
We will not lose hope
Will you bring her home?
She's dead, there's nothing you can do.
You're leaving me and my mom here
While you go out and get drunk
Do you think I don't smell alcohol on you?
Be quiet -
How long has Bob Taylor been in business?
On this map?
Three and a half hours
You think that'll lead us to the bodies?
Because I assure you that will not happen.
Do me a favor, Captain.
And stay away from me
We do not reach any conclusion from his interrogation.
More of a maze than a map.
He has a penchant for mazes.
I will go home
Call me if anything happens
Give me that card, Johnny.
key card
Okay, I'm done now.
tell me what to draw
You said you were drawing a map.
This looks like a damn puzzle.
tell me what to draw
I can't-
...yes you can, you can-
Damn it!
Take it, come on -
...yes you can-
Yes he can.
Oh, damn it!
!Pistol! Pistol! Pistol
Bob, don't you dare!
Put down the weapon
(Bob), (Bob) -
Put down your weapon
(Bob), (Bob), (Bob), (Bob)
No, no, no, no
Damn
Call a resident guide
Our Father who art in heaven
Hallowed be your name
Your kingdom come, your will be done
As in heaven, so on earth
Give us this day our daily bread
And forgive us our sins
As we forgive
Did he explain this before he committed suicide?
I'm sorry -
Damn your regret, save it for the girls' parents -
I don't know what to do, Alex.
I don't know what to do anymore
The worst thing is that I'm sure
That you know where they are
I think we're done
They are in the maze
There you will find them -
What? What did you say?
In the maze -
Which maze?
Where is it? Where is the maze?
Where can I find it?
Alex?
Alex, Alex, listen to me.
I'll get you out of here, okay?
Just tell me where the maze is.
That's all, tell me, man -
Where is the maze?
Hey, tell me where the maze is, okay?
Hey, don't mess with me now.
Tell me, for God's sake
tell me where they are
Tell me! Tell me! Tell me!
Something will make you talk
There must be something that will make you talk.
One minute
How do I help you? -
Good morning ma'am, I'm Keller Dover.
my little daughter
She was kidnapped with her friend
What do you want?
I guess I didn't look closely.
Think about it carefully
I thought a lot
About what happened to your nephew
I know I scared him a few days ago
At the police station
What I'm trying to say is, I feel
Responsible for his escape
Would you like to come in?
Okay -
My husband and I were very pious once.
We spent the summers
We drive that truck with our son.
As we were distributing brochures
We spread the word of goodness
After our son died of cancer
We started to see things differently.
Adopting Alex helped us.
But we have not overcome our sadness
I'm sorry
You look so tired -
Yeah, I don't sleep enough.
I keep dreaming that I'm lost in a maze
Sorry, Alex doesn't talk much.
So when guests come to me
I hardly know what to say
He doesn't talk much?
Okay, he's talking, you get me-
Good morning, have a nice night
It is difficult to get other words out of it.
He had an accident when he was young.
Then he began to choose his words carefully.
What kind of accident did he have?
My husband domesticated snakes.
What happened wasn't that bad.
...but Alex was afraid of her, and
This is not a pleasant memory -
Sorry, that's none of my business-
But... Shall I bring you...
A cup of tea, Mr. Dover?
Taylor commits suicide, and the place
The two bodies are still unknown.
I'm so sorry, I thought you knew that.
In my opinion, this is better.
That horrific man would have spent years in prison.
Those sentenced to death watch TV and get fat
At least I don't have to worry anymore.
(From missing you in Pennsylvania Police
Once the forensic doctors are finished
From his home, we will deploy body tracking dogs.
Look, we can't save
The situation is always the same?
We are just policemen, guards.
So you lost this time, okay?
If you want an achievement, find a girl
He started a family and had some children.
Forget it
Good
Yes? -
Hi, I'm Rich, we found something-
Let's take a look
Two children's clothing mannequins
Their heads are pierced.
I just spoke to our lab mates, and they told us:
The blood in the plastic containers comes from pigs.
Okay, cover them.
It's going to snow soon, hurry up, okay?
As if he is playing some role
I mean it's a case in point.
Except for the elements that define
(  () (
All the baby clothes we found
It still has the manufacturer's badge.
The Book of Labyrinths
What we found settled the matter.
Photocopies and pictures of this
The book we found in the attic
A former FBI agent wrote it.
Finding the Invisible Man
Yes, it's about the theoretical suspect who is believed to be...
He is responsible for a child kidnapping gang.
It's a totally unbelievable theory.
I guess, but I read some of it.
Taylor was kidnapped as a child.
He fled after 3 weeks.
The kidnapper drugged him with a binary mixture.
Lysergic acid diethylamide and ketamine
He didn't remember anything.
They did not catch the culprit.
Well, he read the book and decided.
He was kidnapped by the invisible man.
And now he's imitating him better.
What he can, right?
Yes, he imitated it as best he could.
He committed suicide last night.
How did he commit suicide?
I thought he was under arrest.
Taylor) drew this
It's a map of the two bodies, I assure you.
We found the same design on a necklace.
We pulled it from a corpse days ago.
There's a connection, okay?
The connection is that it is the last maze in the book.
It is not solved, there is no way out of it
The two bodies belong to another imitator who read the book.
What do you mean, Rich?
What do you mean?
That this man is fake and that the two girls
Are you still alive somewhere?
Where did Bob Taylor come from?
On those clothes?
How did the parents know about those clothes?
I can't explain this -
You can't explain it?
Just keep investigating.
Hey, why is this here?
put it in a bag
Yes?
Yes, this is it.
What?
Oh, my God
Wait, is that it?
(Ralph), (Keller)
Keller, we have to go to the hospital.
They found Joy, but they didn't find Anna.
Maybe she knows where Anna is.
(Please, we have to go, Keller.
Eliza) Don't answer) -
You should write to her -
Okay
No one is allowed to pass -
Don't touch me
Ma'am, wait a moment -
decent -
(Nancy)-
(Grace) -
They will find Anna
I know they will.
Know -
How is she?
Is she awake?
Joey, how far are you from our street?
How far off the street did you get, Joey?
aerial)?)
You can't do this now -
How long did it take you to get there?
Let me ask a question please -
(Keller) -
The detective will be back in a minute.
You have to wait
She's drugged.
(Joy) -
Dear, let us know that
Just alive, okay?
Can you nod, baby?
Just nod
Can you give us a nod?
Please, Joy?
aerial)?)
Complete all the mazes and you'll return home.
I was there -
What? Where have you been?
Put two strips of tape over our mouths.
Take it easy, my little one
decent
Your mom and dad are here, okay?
you are fine
Sorry -
you are fine -
I said no one is allowed in the room.
Except her family... where are you going?
Keller)?) -
Wait, where's he going?
I don't know -
You -
Call downstairs
Don't let him out
You, you -
Block the exits
Wait
Stop that car
His truck
Stop, wait
I know your destination
Hello again
Hi I was hoping you would let me do this.
Something to atone for my sin
What sin?
The sin of scaring you a few days ago
At the police station
You already apologized for that -
...I know, I thought maybe you had-
You might benefit from some help, I noticed that
Your door needs repair, so I brought my equipment.
Understood
I burned myself
I'm feeling a little crappy today.
But I'm glad you want to talk more.
No need to make excuses
Come in and make me a cup of tea.
Enter
I don't want to hurt you
I know they were here.
Put your hands on your head and turn around.
Do this
I'll just go
Do not touch this bag
Put your hands above your head
Come here to this table
this is
Open the top drawer
Handcuff them
You don't know me, Mr. Dover, but believe me.
When I tell you I won't let you go
You don't have to drink it all, a third.
It will do for a man your size.
This is something that makes you more malleable.
Forget it -
Drink it, Mr. Dover.
Or I will kill you right away in my kitchen
And bring your daughter to gather
Your brains are off the ground
Where is she?
Drink
Just let me see it -
Want to see it?
Okay -
This is your ticket to your daughter.
(A little more, Mr. Dover.
A little more
Delicious right?
It's my dear husband's recipe.
Now, go back out -
Let me see it -
Take it out of your pocket
put it in the sink
Put it in the drain
Leave your car keys on the table.
Put your car keys on the table.
I did well
Go to the truck over there
The car is over there, go over there
Move over there
The look on your face
My husband had the same look.
(Until we kidnapped Alex.
He was the first child we kidnapped.
His real name was Jimmy or Barry.
I don't remember, and I doubt it.
The other remembers, what more names
(I had forgotten about Bobby Taylor.
until I read about it in the newspaper
Get in the driver's seat
Open the door and get into the car
Hiding children is war
which we wage against the Lord
That makes people lose faith.
And turns them into demons like you
I've had to slow down since my husband disappeared.
But I'm doing my best.
Start the engine, start the engine
keep trying
Slow down
Hey, back off.
this is
Stop, stop it
Stop it
Get out
I think you should know
Alex didn't touch the girls.
I just wanted to take them for a ride in the truck.
I decided that you should stay
Take a look, maybe your daughter is down there.
You never know
(to come), (to come)
Anna)?)
Come), (come)?)
I hid the two girls downstairs.
When the police came to search
I should leave them down there.
I've been so lonely without Alex.
Scroll down -
What? -
Get down
As long as you want me to come down
You'll have to shoot me.
I won't go down
Just because you asked for it.
Oh my God! Oh my God!
Come on down
I did well
Make yourself a stepladder
You may stay alive for 24 hours
I love being alive
When I throw your daughter's body down
Wait, no, wait, wait, wait
no
Welcome
I'd like you to go to Holly Jones.
She must be informed.
(No, I have to find Dover-
You're done for in Dover, all right? Please?
Do you want me to go to Holly Jones?
I would like you to go
To Holly Jones and learn it please
Oh, my God
Oh my great God, protect my daughter
Mrs. Jones?
Show me your hands now
Don't move, raise your hands immediately.
Stop immediately and raise your hands
Don't move and raise your hands
Make sure they burn my body
I don't want to be buried in a box
Raise your hands immediately
Damn
Anna, oh my god
(Oh my god, Anna
Damn
Come on, come on.
Anna), (Anna), Haya)
Stay with me, Anna.
Anna, stay with me.
Take it easy
Go, move, move, move
Don't die, don't die
Take it easy
you are fine dear
Look
Help, help
Detective Loki?
I hope we're not intruding -
both -
She's fine
She will be fine in a while.
A few days, right, dear?
She came to thank you and greet you.
You have to be saluted because you are the hero
Welcome
Would you give us a moment?
Good -
Thank you -
(Say goodbye, Joy-
See you soon -
I'll get back to you in a minute, okay?
(Say goodbye, Anna-
Did you find her whistle?
no -
She insists that Joy helped her.
To find her on Thanksgiving before they were kidnapped.
But I think it's confusing.
I bought her another one.
He didn't call me.
I think you probably
You won't believe me, but he didn't call.
I believe you
Do you think you will find it?
Okay -
And he will go to jail -
This is likely.
Overall, thank you for everything.
Lord
i miss him
He did what he had to do to find Anna.
I thank God for that
He is a good man
See you soon
We're done, let's pack up.
Are you done for tonight?
Yes, the ground is frozen solid.
We will spend several weeks
In excavating the whole house floor
We found some dead snakes and crap.
Pray for the best
And prepare for the worst, right?
Good night
Turn it off