Guardian, this is Omaha 4-4
on heading 158 to Laredo.
Copy, Omaha 4-4.
I'm picking up movement
on the FLIR.
Coming in for a closer look.
Stand by.
This is the
United States Border Patrol.
Get on your knees
and put your hands up.
- Hey! Get down!
- I speak English.
I speak English. Get down!
Stay down!
Get down!
This is the United States
Border Patrol.
Get on your knees and
put your hands on your head.
This is the United States
Border Patrol.
Get on your knees.
Put your hands up.
This is the United States
Border Patrol.
Let me see your hands!
Show me your hands!
Show...!
Be advised.
There's been an explosion.
Officers are down.
Hey! Over here!
What do you got?
Prayer rugs.
Hey, honey. Yeah.
Stay here with me.
Just stay here.
It's okay.
Just come with me slowly
and quietly.
Stay here with me. Stay...
Oh, God.
You don't have to
do this.
You don't have
to do this, please.
The scene in
Kansas City tonight
is one of horror,
confusion and grief.
15 people,
among them two children,
are so far confirmed dead
with many more injured...
The victims' families remain...
Haunting images
of the attackers
are coming to light
from surveillance...
Secretary of Defense
James Riley
is expected to make a
statement on the attacks.
Our intense focus on recovery
and assisting the injured
and the families of
those who have been killed
is matched only by
our determination
to prevent more attacks.
A message to our attackers.
Your bombs do not terrify us.
They empower us.
They empower us
to send you something
that is truly terrifying:
the full weight of
the United States military.
Down, down,
down on the ground!
No! Here for what?!
I'm not the f-fighter!
Fighter!
How you doing?
You think I'm gonna
waterboard you, Bashiir?
Waterboarding is
when we can't torture.
This is Africa.
I can do whatever the fuck
I want here.
You're gonna answer
every question I ask you
without me harming
a hair on your head.
Do you want to know why?
Because if you don't...
...I'm gonna call in
an air strike on your house.
Nice pool, by the way.
Whoever said
crime doesn't pay
wasn't stealing oil tankers,
were they?
Those men are Yemeni.
We have nothing to do
with that.
Your fight is with ISIS,
not me.
All my fights are on water.
They sure are, Bashiir.
And Yemen?
Just across the gulf.
What a coincidence.
It's kind of tricky
for Yemeni nationalists
to book an international flight
these days, huh?
So, if their passports
were fake,
they'd fly straight
to Kansas City
instead of going to Mexico and
hiring coyotes to truck them
a hundred miles
to the desert, right?
So, the big question is:
how'd they get to Mexico?
'Cause they sure as hell
didn't fly.
No, they... traveled by ship.
A ship you didn't
try and steal.
So that means
someone paid you not to.
So, here's my only question,
Bashiir.
Who paid you
to let the ship through?
Is that your brother?
'Cause I don't want
to kill the pool guy.
- Every ship smuggles people.
- Mm-hmm.
And they don't need
my permission.
Yes, they fucking do.
Last chance.
- This is a bluff.
- No.
You American.
You have too many rules.
No rules today, sport,
just orders.
Go ahead, sir. You're green.
Roger that.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, I want you to watch it.
I want you to watch it.
Watch.
You have a big family,
Bashiir.
Lots of brothers.
You should've chosen
another line of work.
I could do this all day.
But sooner or later,
I'll get the brother
you can't live without.
I promise.
It's one more thing
pointing to the cartels.
Now, the money came from
Quassim Al-Raymi's camp,
which isn't a surprise.
The ship, on the other hand,
is a Panamanian freighter,
La Victorina,
registered to the Mexican
holding company Grupo Duro.
It docked at Port of Veracruz
on the 18th.
Carlos Reyes' company.
The one and only.
If you need Matt home,
I can get him out
at 0600 tomorrow.
I'll have a plane
to Washington
ready for you in an hour.
See you tomorrow, Matt.
Smuggling terrorists seems
pretty short-sighted to me.
Border's gonna tighten
like a vice now.
What happened to the price
of cocaine after 9/11, Ken?
Tight borders
are good for business.
Let's go.
Will you be home by 3:00?
I have to stay late
for the science fair.
Do you want me
to pick you up?
I'll take the bus. Okay.
Let's go.
It's pretty good.
How much they make?
For lookout?
20, 30 a day.
Man, but that's
all they're worth.
But you...
well, shit, you know
both sides of the river.
You got a passport.
Come and go as you please.
Rafa!
Eh.
Fat ass.
What's going on?
Hide the beer.
You can name
your own price, you know.
Hmm?
This is the border.
The Matamoros Cartel
pay people well to work it.
You can, uh...
start making your earn
with me, cousin.
Take it.
It's yours.
So, what do I have to do?
You really ought to invest
in a little sunscreen, Matt.
If you guys would start wars
someplace cloudy,
I wouldn't have to.
DOJ get an ID
on those other suicide bombers?
Not yet. Uh, might want to get on that.
There's proof Reyes Cartel
helped one of them
get to the border, so...
we know enough
to move forward.
Mr. Secretary...
Matt Graver.
Have a seat.
What do you think is
the most valuable commodity
that cartels move
across our borders?
20 years ago, cocaine.
Uh, today I'd have to say
it'd be people.
It's a resource they don't
have to cultivate or process
and if they don't
make it across,
they can pay to cross again
at three times
the price of a kilo.
How would you define terrorism,
Mr. Graver?
I think that's your job, sir.
The current definition is
"Any individual or group
that uses violence
to achieve a political goal."
The administration
believes that
the drug cartels
now fit that definition.
Next week, the president's
adding drug cartels
to the list
of terrorist organizations.
You can understand
how that will
expand our ability
to combat them.
The cartel territories
are fairly stable
at the moment,
but as we learned in Iraq,
striking your enemy is
a whole hell of a lot easier
if they're fighting
each other.
I'll do whatever you need.
Just point the way.
Do you have any thoughts?
I mean, I wouldn't take out
a cartel leader.
Turn one cartel into 50.
Besides, killing kings doesn't
start wars, it ends them.
That's our concern.
Mm-hmm.
You have a location on Reyes?
No, but the family's
under surveillance.
Is he in contact with them?
Not to our knowledge,
but we assume yes.
- Any kids?
- Two.
What's the age
of the youngest?
Sixteen.
Sixteen?
Yeah, if you want to
start a war...
kidnap a prince.
King will start it for you.
You did this sort of thing
in the Middle East.
Hmm.
You think those tactics
will work here?
If you want it to, sir.
Boots on the ground, you're
gonna hire on the outside.
And the same goes
for your supply train
and for air support.
And I don't need
to remind you
what happens if they figure out
that it's us.
Just to be clear,
you want to see
this thing through,
I'm gonna have to get...
dirty.
Dirty is exactly why
you're here.
What do you need?
Everything.
Drones with
attack capability...
You have Black Hawks, right? Mm-hmm.
I want two of those.
I need logistics,
communications equipment
compatible with a SOCOM JCU.
First phase,
I need a strike team,
two snipers,
I need a demolition team...
Are you going to Ukraine?
I got Russians on the payroll,
brother.
Don't put me
in that position.
Where's the coup?
It's an extraction...
for starters.
How much can I know?
Brother, you don't
want to know.
Well, I don't need specifics,
but I have to know
where they're going.
Mexico.
You gotta be
fucking kidding me.
It's not the government.
It's cartel.
Treasury cutting the checks?
Eh, under a company in Brazil
called Rio Verde.
If it's constant action,
I'm ten mil a month
in payroll and supplies.
At least.
I want 150 over cost
and immunity.
Done.
Congratulations, you can afford
your own hockey team now.
You'll be easy to shop for
at Christmas.
I don't celebrate Christmas.
Well, I bet you will
this year.
What'd they do?
Doesn't matter.
No rules this time.
I'm turning you loose.
How loose?
Carlos Reyes.
How's that for loose?
It's your chance
to get even for your family.
You're gonna help us
start a war.
With who?
Everyone.
Aah! Aah...
Aah!
Adios.
This would have been a lot
easier taking her in the house.
Could get real sloppy
on the street.
Sloppy's good.
Sloppy makes it look like
the cartel did it.
All right,
let's go.
She started it.
Miss Reyes?
She called me a narco
whore and slapped me, so I hit her.
What would you do?
You.
Go to the nurse.
No, you're not
going anywhere.
Sit.
Now what am I going
to do with you?
She deserved
what she got.
It's not your place to do it.
Fine.
You beat the shit out of her.
I should expel you.
Do it.
That's what I thought.
How we looking?
Got eyes on the prize?
Roger.
Prize is in the tail vehicle.
No!
No! No! No!
Where we going? Go straight to the plane.
Don't worry about the vehicle.
We'll take care of it.
All right.
All right, you're
gonna drive that to the mall.
Keys are in the gas flap.
You just leave them there.
All right. Then you go see
what's waiting for you.
Where you got us? Building 5, sir.
You're gonna take a left.
I know where it is.
Now walk me through
what I'm watching here.
This is a map of Mexico
on a hundred-mile grids.
And you took
the subject here.
Speculation is Reyes
has a family residence
somewhere near Monterrey.
Has the Mexican police
responded yet?
Yeah, local, state and federal
police are all there now.
Satellite cannot
pick up cell chatter.
Okay. Yeah, we can lock coordinates
to the cell
and snag the phone number,
but we can't hear the call.
Give me a satellite feed
of the house in Mexico City.
Yeah, you got it.
What we're hoping for is
a call from this location
to start a trail.
Any family
members in the house?
No, just staff.
Teenage girl with
her own 30-room mansion.
I wish I was a teenage girl.
Pull up the incident site.
It looks
like you popped them all.
No, we only engaged one.
One died in the crash, and
the other two we tied and left.
That's a pretty big risk.
Why do that?
Just to see what they'd do.
Back it up.
Show me earlier.
A minute just after we left.Yeah.
Keep going.
All right, there, good.
We have new audio
coming in on the black phone.
Copy that.
Call is not coming
from the house,
it's coming from that fucker
right there.
Give me a live feed
and find him.
On it.
Phone!
Lock in on it.
All right, locking now.
Data link up. There's the king.
There it is.
Start tracking.
Come on.
Tracking on two.
Stand by. We got three.
Por favor.
Get down! Police! Get down!
Hands where I can see 'em! Move! Move!
Clear!
We got another one here!
A-Are you okay?
Are we clear?
All clear!
It's okay.
Let's go. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Am I in Texas?
Yeah, we are.
What do you want us
to call you?
Isabel.
I need to ask you
a question.
Did they hurt you?
What happened here?
I got in a fight at school.
So when do I get
to go back home?
Well, we still need
to work through some things
to make sure we understand
all the circumstances
surrounding
your abduction, okay?
But you're safe.
So hang in there, we're gonna
get you home very soon.
Alicia will look after you.
And if you need anything,
just ask her.
We put the girl in the middle
of Matamoros territory,
and Reyes will start
the fireworks.
What's a good spot
where we can leave her?
We'll hold her in a federal
police depot in Méndez.
We're deep enough
in Matamoros land
that they'll have
to fight their way out
if they come looking for her.
Where do I say you found her?
Oh, say we raided a safe house
in Brownsville
and found her there.
Matamoros Cartel is
very strong in this area.
Reyes will have trouble
getting his men through.
Ah, they'll let
his men through.
Getting back out
will be their problem.
When would you
bring her across?
Well, now that
we got the cartels
at each other's throats,
the sooner the better.
Secret won't keep long.
Uh, there's no secrets
in Mexico.
Why do you think
I'm driving armor?
Can you get me cleared
for that?
Will do.
Federal police will meet you
at the border with an escort.
Thanks.
Still amazes me.
The appetite of this place.
Yeah, well,
welcome to America.
You all right?
What the fuck?!
Hey! Why don't you
keep your fucking eyes peeled?
Ah, you can't even tell
they're gangbangers anymore.
I've got a problem.
Either be home before dawn
or my dad will get mad.
Oh, get the fuck out, dude, no.
No, no, no.
You got a new daddy now.
All right?
When you meet him,
act like a fucking man.
You ready to be a man,
right?
All right, yes, dude.
All right.
Just wait here till
I come get you, all right?
Come on.
No. ¿No?
Sí.
How you feeling?
I'd feel better
if someone actually told me
what was going on.
We're turning you over
to the Mexican Army.
They'll arrange to take you
back to your father.
Let's go.
I'm gonna need you
to put this on.
Load up!
Loading up! Heads up!
I have seven Mexican police vehicles
located at the border
checkpoint waiting.
They're moving and forming up
in your configuration
at this time.
It's a nice day
for a drive, huh?
Ah, beautiful day.
Blue skies,
large-caliber weapons.
I love getting out
of the office.
Air, how are we looking?
Clear on both sides.
You see no vehicles?
Nothing but desert.
You're clear.
What's your field of view?
Ten miles in every direction.
Mexico Feds said
that the road would be clear.
Looks like they're
keeping their word.
All right, copy that.
Why weren't we stopped
at the border?
'Cause I'm special.
I thought you were policemen.
You're soldiers.
You know, we saved you...
why don't you just sit back
and be grateful.
Oscar-One, paved road ends
half a mile ahead.
Wait, what?
Paved road ends
in half a klick.
Road isn't paved ahead.
You got your thermal?
Yeah, in my bag
in the back; you gotta take the wheel.
All right.
Got it.
Oh, shit.
Nothing's ever easy.
I got it.
Shit.
I got no vis.
This fucker's speeding up.
Well, he's not stupid.
Stay on his ass.
Dirt roads make me nervous.
Air, I'm blind here.
Road's clear.
No vehicles, no movement,
left or right.
All right, anything?
Shit. Oscar-One,
incoming on your right.
Air, I see nothing. Contact right.
I don't see anything.
All down! Down!
Stuck! I'm stuck!
Aw, come on!
West side, hundred meters!
Take him out!
Roger that. Heads down!
Heads down!
We're stuck. We're stuck.
Go! Go, go!
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Clear!
Clear.
Drop your weapon!
Them, over there. Sir!
Spread out!
Put 'em down, guys!
Easy, easy.
- !Abajo!
- Ayuda.
Easy, guys, easy.
Down. Down.! Ayuda!
Fuck!
Shit.
Fuckin' Mexican police
shot me?
You all right?
Oh, shit.
I'm good.
It caught the plate.
All right. We clear?
Sir! We have police vehicles
approaching from the south.
Five klicks out.
All right, load up!
Come on, load up!
Where is she?
New mission!
Gather round! New mission!
Uh... no time for that.
Head north. I'll find her.
Okay. Go.
All right, we got company
three klicks out,
coming from the south.
Grab that Humvee,
pull this thing out.
Go! Now! Now!
Come on, guys! Now!
Go, go! Let's go!
Let's go! Move it!
Take this.
All right?
Send me a signal
when you get to the border,
we'll come and get you.
All right?
Let's go, let's go!
Let's move it!
All right,
everyone in their vehicles!
Air, we need a medivac
from rally point alpha.
Contact 47th med at Laughlin.
Roger that, Oscar-One.
Be advised,
you have police vehicles
approaching your six
in a Code 3.
Oh, that's great.
Police approaching
our six fast.
Air, we need a lane clear
at the border.
No bullshit.
Anybody gets in our way,
we drive right through them.
Border coming up fast.
Border.
!Oye!
Isabel?
No!
Get in.
Who kidnapped me?
Your father
has a lot of enemies.
And you're one of them?
Yes, I am.
You're gonna need stitches.
Yeah. Lucky for me,
I'll still need
them tomorrow.
Miss Sunshine on your six.
Hi. Fuckin' Mondays, huh?
Can we go somewhere
that's private?
All right.
Can you give me a sec?
Ma'am.
My source is
with her right now.
She'll be back in an hour.
That's not what
I'm talking about.
It was a green on blue,
Cynthia.
There was no other option.
You wanted Afghanistan,
now you got it.
This isn't Afghanistan.
This is our fucking neighbor!
There are 54 million Americans
with relatives there,
Mm-hmm. and they're all sitting around
watching footage
of dead Mexican police
on Fox News. The police were the ambush.
Oh, yeah, okay. We had no choice.
All... They attacked us.
Doesn't matter.
POTUS doesn't have
the stomach for this.
He shut us down.
What did you say? We're shut down.
I did my fuckin' job.
You do yours.
You sit that
fuckin' coward down,
and you explain to him...
this is how we win.
He's not worried
about winning.
He's worried about
being fucking impeached,
because you killed
two dozen Mexican police.
Who worked for Reyes.
Spin it. Do your job.
This only strengthens
our position.
We don't have a position,
Matt.
Because we're not supposed
to fucking be there.
Your objective was to start
a war with Mexican cartels,
not with
the Mexican government.
You know what?
This-this is why
nothing ever changes.
You think change
is the goal? Really?
You've been doing this too long
to believe that.
Sí.
Why didn't you hold her
someplace in Mexico?
We don't have the
infrastructure for that, sir.
Mission security
would be almost impossible.
Was this your mission? No, sir.
Then why are you answering?
Mr. Graver?
We don't have the
infrastructure for that, sir.
Mission security
would be almost impossible.
And this girl was witness to
all aspects of the mission,
correct? No, she was shielded
from the kidnapping.
What about the 25
Mexican police officers
that were killed,
on foreign soil,
all of which she witnessed?
The ones who attacked us?
Yes, sir.
Where is she?
I have a source
bringing her to the border.
Do we have an exact location?
That question is for you, Mr. Forsing.
We don't know
her whereabouts, sir,
but he has a beacon...
he'll activate it
as soon as he gets close
to the border.
If they can make it
Which is a chance
we cannot take.
Cynthia.
Yes, sir?
You handle it from here.
We can't risk her falling
into the wrong hands.
When the beacon's activated,
your team takes them.
You understand?
Clean the scene.
When I say clean, gentlemen,
I mean spotless.
Your operative included.
Do you know...
how hard he was to make?
I could throw a stick
across the river
and hit 50 grieving fathers.
Make another one.
Can't do that.
Well, look who doesn't have
the stomach for it now.
Oh, who are you
to question me
after all the shit
that I've eaten for you?
We ID'd
the other bombers, Matt.
They're U.S. citizens.
They're from New Jersey.
Doesn't change anything.
It changes
the fucking narrative!
Hey.
You got the girl?
She's with me now, yeah.
They want me to cut ties.
You got to get rid of her.
I can't do that.
What are you telling me?
Not this one.
Help me get her across,
and we can decide
what to do with her.
Uh-uh. Don't put me
in that situation.
If they're cutting ties,
you're already in that situation.
If she stays here,
she'll be killed.
Help me get her across.
I can't help you do that.
You gotta do
what you gotta do.
I'll figure it out.
Good luck.
I got to get you north.
See, the flashing light
is you.
All right? That red line,
that's your path.
Okay. Don't get that wet.
Keep it safe for a bit.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
They're sheep.
Treat them like it.
!Rápido!
!Vámonos!
Follow the trail to the road.
Your ride's waiting.
It's okay.
Come on.
Show me a job that pays better
and I'll do it.
Where are you headed, baby?
Get me to the
grocery store on Trenton.
I can walk from there.
Why does a soldier know
sign language?
My daughter was deaf.
I know who you are.
You're the attorney
whose family they killed.
Not "they."
My father.
A man who worked for him.
Why?
To send a message.
Now you hunt them...
so you won't be a message.
I will always be a message.
Only now,
the message is different.
Is the border hard to cross?
It could be...
for Isabel Reyes.
From now on,
your name is Carina.
Signal was activated at 1939,
heading northeast of Reynosa.
I'm sending another team
to finish this.
No. I'll do it.
'Cause if I don't, he'll
probably come and kill you.
Oh...
There's interference on the road.
Are the vehicles unmarked
or police? Unmarked.
ETA to target?
25 minutes.
No.
No?
Huh?
No! No!
No! No! No!
No!
That's him. ETA?
15 minutes.
Get us there in ten...
I can't have the girl talk.
Hang on back there.
Gonna get bumpy.
José.
No!
Glad we didn't
have to do that.
What about the girl?
Two minutes out.
Matt?
Base, what's subject's
exact location inside the car?
Subject is back seat,
right side
behind the passenger.
Prize is passenger side,
second seat, green Expedition.
Rules of engagement?
Fuck it all.
Wipe it clean.
Stand up! Stand up!
What are you doing?
Matt!
You're fucking us!
She said spotless. Fuck 'em all.
She'll go
into witness protection.
Sit down.
So you wanna be a sicario.
Let's talk about your future.