- Norvel.
- Good evening, Mr. Costello.
This one's
for you, Frank.
Mr. Costello!
I'm calling an ambulance.
I should've been
paying more attention
instead of taking
bows at the Copa.
♪ Then that elevator
Starts its ride ♪
- ♪ Down and down I go ♪
- ♪ Round and round I go ♪
♪ Like a leaf
Caught in a tide ♪
♪ I should stay away
But what can I do? ♪
Till I got
shot in the head,
I don't think people even
realized I was a rackets guy.
I didn't carry a gun. I had
no bodyguards. I took cabs.
I was married to the
same woman for 38 years.
And whenever I was
mentioned in the papers
for some charity
or political thing,
I was usually referred to
as a professional gambler.
A Damon Runyon type of guy.
Guys and Dolls and all
that sort of stuff.
They're on the last song.
Good.
But then years
later, my best friend,
he betrayed me.
Vito, the show's almost over.
Vito and me,
we grew up together.
You wouldn't know
it, but back then
we were very good
friends and very close.
And we quit our regular
school the ninth grade,
not because we were dumb, but
because we were ambitious.
And the Alto Knights Social Club
was where we hung out.
It was our home.
We weren't gonna go dig
ditches like our fathers
and live upstairs in
a cold-water tenement
for the rest of our
lives. No, sir, not us.
We lived in America. America
was the land of opportunity.
Yankee Doodle
Dandy and all that.
But when Lucky
got into politics,
everything changed.
Especially after Tammany
saw those immigrants
who never bothered to vote,
that they were
election day gold.
Vito and I just told
everybody in Italian,
"Vote for the donkey."
I remember one
time telling Vito,
"Hey, maybe we can open
a restaurant or a bar.
What do you think?" He
said, "Nah. Not interested."
- Gotta consider this.
- Listen...
- I'm not joking.
- I take out. I don't put in.
And that was the
first time I realized,
"We don't think the same."
Take a bow.
At first
I wasn't too sure
about taking bows
and all that stuff.
It wasn't for me.
After a while, I
gotta say, I liked it.
Commissioner!
Right here. Right here!
Mr. Hawley, as head
of the Fifth Avenue
Businessmen's Association,
how do you find working
with Frank Costello?
All I know is that
I would hope to have
Frank Costello's support
in every one of
our charity events.
You go ahead with Gene and Lois,
I'll meet youse
at the restaurant.
I gotta do some stuff
at the apartment.
Okay. Honey, don't...
don't be long.
It was a lovely affair,
and I've never met so many
judges in all my life.
I won't be long.
It's not like they're
a barrel of monkeys.
You'll be all right.
Sometimes I would
forget I wasn't running
a regular
billion-dollar business.
In fact, I was even thinking
of getting out, but...
I didn't see this coming.
Doctor
Roberts, call extension 16.
Doctor Roberts, please
call extension 16.
Mr. Costello,
you're a lucky man.
The bullet pierced your scalp
just behind your right ear,
and then instead of
penetrating your skull,
it miraculously curved
round the back of your head
until exiting near
your left ear.
You'll have headaches and
be forgetful for a few days,
but you should be fine.
Uh, thanks, Doc.
I didn't want you to come here.
I don't always do what you want.
I know, I know...
You heard him. I'm gonna
be fine, it's all right.
What happens now?
Nothing.
I got the message.
That's it.
I'm done. I'm done.
You're done?
I know what to do.
What does... What
does that mean?
I don't understand
what you're saying.
Go home. I'll see
you at home, okay?
Okay, baby.
All right.
Orderlies,
please report to
the business lounge.
Could orderlies please report
to the business lounge?
Come on. Inside.
Mr. Costello, I'm
Detective Salerno.
This is Detective Jim Mullins.
You must have seen who shot you.
Called out your name, Frank.
Okay, yeah, no. He did, you're
right. But I turned around.
And when I turned around,
I was shot and I went down.
I hit the floor, and when I...
By the time I saw who it was,
the guy was out the door.
What happened?
You walked away.
All you had to do was
that, and you walked away.
No. That's not what happened.
Then what did happen?
All you had to do
was finish him off.
You're supposed to finish
what you started doing.
That's what you're
supposed to do. Vincent.
I did finish. I
was two feet away.
The fucking bullet
bounced off his head.
You know this isn't over.
These guys are gonna
come back for you.
You know that, right?
Well, I don't know...
I don't have enemies,
as far as I know.
I got a pretty
good... I know that
- you might not believe me.
- I wish I could say that.
You had to use a fucking
pop gun. A peashooter.
- What's the matter with you?
- I didn't wanna make noise.
Noise? It's a fucking gun.
What are you talking about?
- But I was close to him.
- It's a fucking gun.
It's supposed to make noise.
Are you stupid or what?
I yelled out his
name to be sure.
Called his name? So what?
What does that mean?
What's this, Frank?
- What is that? You just put...
- This is dated just last week.
It says, "Gross casino wins.
Less markers. $434,000."
- That's a lot of money.
- Frank, you have a casino?
Where's the casino?
Is it in Las Vegas?
I don't know what you're
talking about or what that is.
...shoot somebody in the head,
you'd think that they're dead.
You don't think
they're dead. You shot oogatz.
You see them go down? Does
that mean they're dead? No.
You gotta go see
if they're dead.
You gotta shoot 'em
again, again, again.
You shoot and you
ask questions later,
- but you make sure he's dead.
- I thought he was dead.
He's not dead. He's not dead.
Guess what. He's not dead.
I mean, I didn't know it was
legal for you guys to just...
Without a warrant...
Just go and pick something
out of my pocket like that.
You didn't see I picked
it up off the floor?
- Must've fell on the floor.
- I didn't see that.
- Frank...
- Is that what happened?
...you might as well
tell us what it is.
What's going on here, Frank?
You know and I know
you know who did this.
If you guys know, then
go after those people
because I don't
know who they are.
It was co... It was
coming out of his head.
It's supposed to
come out of his head.
When you shoot a person in
the head, you think he's dead.
Gotta shoot 'em again.
- Come on.
- Fuck.
Well, obviously, we
need a witness, right?
You're the victim. You
were shot in the head.
Frank, you had to see him.
All we need is a name, Frank.
The elevator door was gonna...
was gonna open, and I...
There was a lot of blood.
How did I know what
was gonna happen?
You gotta get outta here
now. You gotta take off.
Get lost for a while.
You know what to do.
Make yourself scarce.
Fellas, I would
like to help you,
but I cannot do that
because I don't know who...
I didn't see anything.
I didn't see who it
w... I saw a blur.
I just don't have any more
informa... I'm sorry, you know?
I don't know what to tell you.
You don't want me to
go to the hospital?
- Come on. Come on.
- Shoot him again?
Stop being a fucking jerk.
I can't believe I
just heard him say
that he fucking wants to
shoot him now at the hospital.
What's the matter with this kid?
What, we gotta give him a
fucking bazooka next time?
- I don't understand.
- Who cares?
He did all that practice.
Who gives a fuck?
He was practicing upstate
doing all this shit.
He was telling me, "I'm
practicing, shooting..."
The fuck? You
didn't do nothing.
I mean, I'd like to call
my lawyer if I could.
Yeah, go
ahead. Be my guest.
All right.
Frank Costello, the city's
reputed rackets boss
and a political powerhouse,
known around town as
"the Prime Minister"
of the underworld...
- How did it go wrong?
- ...survived a murder attempt
as he entered his luxury
Central Park West apartment.
Police say the gunman, who
used a .32 caliber revolver,
is in his mid-twenties and
fled in a sedan with a driver.
Police are concerned
that the botched attempt
on Costello's life
could be a sign of rivalry
in gangland circles.
We know there's trouble
between your client
and Vito Genovese.
Frank, there's been
rumors about it for years.
Let me tell you
something, boys and girls.
I'm here at Lindy's,
and this isn't something
that you can brush off with
cheesecake and blintzes.
Gentlemen, need I remind you
that Mr. Costello is
the victim in this case?
He's the one that
was shot, all right?
So unless you're charging
the victim with the crime,
I think we're finished.
Hey, Frank,
who do you think did it?
I can tell
you there's great concern
among officials that the
Costello shooting could lead
to the kind of bloody mob war
this city hasn't seen in years.
Hey, Frank!
I know
it's got City Hall
and the police commissioner
at 240 Centre Street
plenty worried.
This is Victor Riesel.
Mr. Costello!
Right here. Frank!
Frank! Frank, right here.
Wait for me.
Frank, do me a favor.
No comment, huh?
What you gotta say, Frank?
Hey, hey, hey.
Back up. Hey, hey.
We have no comment at
this time. No comment.
Please respect
Mr. Costello's privacy
while he recovers from
his injuries, all right?
Come on, boys. Give us
a night off, all right?
Let's take off.
What good's
it gonna do now?
A lot.
It'll get us dinner
in Rome. Hmm?
I just, I... You
know... I wanna...
- We gotta come back anyway.
- Why? Why?
- Because I s...
- No, it's just you and me.
That was our deal.
We are our own family.
We could live anywhere.
You're right, I know. But
I gotta finish this here.
Gotta finish what's going on.
I have to deal with it.
I gotta... I gotta...
I gotta figure out
what I'm gonna do.
You promised me. We
were our own family.
And you, me, the dogs, we
can... we can live anywhere.
We're gonna do that.
I decided, after this, I'm done.
But I gotta deal
with this stuff.
I gotta make sure everything
is okay before we go,
and then we're out. I'm
out, that's it. Done. Over.
But now, I'm worried.
I gotta finish this.
We might not be
that lucky again.
If it
wasn't for Bobbie,
I probably would've never
left the neighborhood.
Nobody ever left
the neighborhood.
It's where we all felt
safe. Comfortable.
We looked out for each other.
It was Bobbie who showed me
there was more to the city
than just Downtown, the club
and everything down there.
All those memories.
We picked a neutral
turf for the wedding
since her mother
and father thought
their 17-year-old daughter,
Loretta Geigerman,
should not marry an
Italian stickup man.
And my mother and father,
they couldn't figure out
why I wasn't marrying
a nice Italian girl
instead of this Jewish
wiseass girl, you know.
Why do you walk
around with that all the time?
I wish you wouldn't carry a gun.
You know, if they catch
you, it's five years.
Nobody is gonna catch me.
I caught you.
Yeah, well, that's
'cause I kissed you.
And I do not kiss cops.
I got picked up
on a gun charge
right after the wedding.
I spent the rest of
my honeymoon in jail.
I never carried a gun again.
Tammany judge got me 11
months on Welfare Island.
And I got a dorm with a guy
who helped fix
the 1919 World Series.
He said everybody in the country
could drink all they wanted,
but nobody was
supposed to sell it.
I couldn't believe this law.
For me, Prohibition
was the new frontier.
God bless America.
♪ Any bootlegger Sure
is a pal of mine ♪
Prohibition was a law
that nobody wanted to obey
and nobody wanted to enforce,
and that suited me fine.
When the doctor
said having a baby
would endanger Bobbie's life,
my business became my family.
I spent Prohibition
turning politicians
and cops into partners.
I turned speakeasies
into supper clubs
and crap games into casinos.
I provided the best
imported Scotch available
to the city's upper classes.
Vito became the top boss when
Lucky went to prison in 1937.
Unfortunately, Vito got
involved in a double homicide,
so he turned
everything over to me.
And he decided to skip
out of the country.
That was his way of
avoiding the grand jury,
so we threw him a
bon-voyage party
on the boat before he
sailed off to Italy.
And so then I was, suddenly,
the boss of bosses.
At his going-away
party, he told everybody
he was leaving me in
charge till he got back
because he knew...
he knew he could trust me
and I wouldn't try
to steal from him.
And he was right.
I would never do that.
But World War II happened,
and he got stuck
over there for years.
By the time he got back,
the whole world had changed.
Mr. Genovese.
Over the course of your life,
including the years when you
were a fugitive overseas,
every witness against you has
either died or disappeared.
And more recently, last week,
a witness under the protective
custody of this court died
after drinking a cup of coffee
with enough arsenic
to kill eight horses.
I cannot speak for a jury,
but I would gladly condemn
you to the electric chair.
If I could.
Case dismissed.
Vito.
Hey. Welcome home.
When Vito beat the
double homicide,
the bosses gave him a
party at the Alto Knights.
They were all there.
Even Richie Boiardo,
the New York-Jersey
boss, was there.
Boiardo was like the umpire
for the New York bosses.
Everybody liked him.
Joe Bonanno from the Bronx.
Tommy Lucchese from Queens.
Joe Profaci from Brooklyn.
Albert Anastasia, who ran
the Brooklyn waterfront,
even though the newspapers said
he ran Murder, Incorporated.
And there was Tony Bender,
Vito's closest confidant,
friend, consigliere, whatever.
In that crowd,
including Richie Boy,
Albert was the
best friend I had.
Welcome home, Vito.
Where's Frank? Frank not here?
- Who? No, he's not here.
- He ain't here.
He don't come around too much.
What happened?
He's supposed to be
here. He's the boss.
He's supposed to be here, right?
Think he should
be here, yeah. But...
He doesn't wanna
attract too much heat.
Vito had been gone
a long time. Too long.
He expected to take
over his old spot again
as the boss of bosses,
but the commission
ruled against it.
That's over 60 top bosses
from all around the country
who enjoyed 15 years
of peace, prosperity,
friendly politicians,
with me at the top.
And they didn't want no changes.
Especially after it got around
that Vito was dealing
drugs in Italy.
Two murder raps, and
you're walking home.
- Huh?
- Two murder raps.
You beat the both of them.
I mean, between us, he should
have fucking been here...
Of course, of course.
But tomorrow you go
and meet with him.
I gotta beg him for stuff
that's already mines.
- You don't.
- That's what I'm...
There comes a time
when you gotta use
a little bit of diplomacy.
You know what I mean?
Just be nice. Firm, but nice.
Yeah, I know, right.
Bullshit. Yeah. I mean,
with all these fucking
judges and all that shit.
I mean, those judges, they
gave me fucking nothing.
Oogatz. They gave me fucking
ooga... They gave me nothing.
Vito, you beat it without him.
You didn't need him. Fuck him.
Will you listen to me?
He gave me nothing.
- Nothing.
- I know he... You're right.
Proud cocksucker, you.
I know, I know. You're right.
I come back, he don't
show no respect.
- He'd be here, but with me.
- Of course he should be here.
He's afraid of cops. He's
afraid of taking a pinch.
His wife has got
him by the balls.
He knows I'm here. He
should've been here.
Bad move. They should have
been here. Absolutely.
For me and
Vito to have this talk,
I figured, "Let's go to
Dora's Candy Store. Why not?"
It's a place we knew as kids.
We hung out there all the time.
Had all kinds of
things going on.
It would help.
But I also knew
Vito, and I also knew
that if he didn't
get what he wanted,
he would try to take it.
Sorry I couldn't be there
for your thing at the club.
I thought it was better
if I wasn't there.
I didn't wanna draw attention.
It was nice. It was good to
see everybody all home...
- It's all right. Don't worry.
- Must've been.
- It was nice.
- Yeah, nice.
No, I'm glad you had
a good time. So...
So what do you think?
What do you want to do?
First of all, I'm thinking,
"Give me everything that
I lost while I was away."
Vito, you've been gone a long
time. Everything's changed.
- It ain't the same.
- I know. I understand.
Look, you did good by everybody.
God bless you. You made a lot
of money for a lot of people.
Didn't include me, but that's
okay. What am I gonna do?
- Well, that's why we're here.
- Yeah, that's why we're here.
That's why I gotta start
looking for something
to get me back to where I was
like the old days 'cause...
You gave me Downtown and
the West Side, that's good.
But that ain't enough. It
ain't doing it. I need more.
You know, when I left
I gave you everything.
And so, we gotta work that out.
Otherwise I gotta look
for something else
- to get me back where I was.
- Well, I'm hoping I...
I'm hoping that you're not
thinking what I'm thinking,
because that wouldn't
be good for anybody.
There were some people that
are looking to go that way.
These people I'm talking
to. And they're looking...
I know who you're talking
to. With those fellas,
you're looking for trouble,
I gotta be honest with you.
Right now, we're
doing very nicely
with what we got. Right now.
Let me just... Let's
work something out.
Let me just think about this.
Let me come up with something.
Something that would be better
for you, better for everybody.
You understand?
Let's try that first.
Let's not jump into anything.
Let's try to be
smart about this.
Just give me a little
time. I'll find a way.
But if you go that way,
you're gonna create problems
for a lot of people.
They're gonna get hurt.
That, I will guarantee you.
That, we have to watch out for.
All right. Well, the
people who I'm talking to,
they ain't against it.
They got no problem with
it. They're very interested.
- That means something to me.
- They're okay with it,
but it's not okay if
you're okay with it.
There's gonna be a big problem.
No, no. No, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
Go.
Frank, listen.
With Scotch, that didn't
stop you from selling.
It was supply and demand.
Nobody knows this
better than you.
Supply and demand.
They demand, we supply.
- It's the same thing.
- It ain't the same. Come on.
Nah, it ain't the same.
There's more money in it.
There's a lot more money in it.
In the old days,
a truck full of Scotch
got you a $50 fine.
The cops would drive you home
after you paid
them a little bit.
This... You get pinched
with an ounce of that stuff,
you can get 20 to life.
What are you talking
about? It's not the same.
And they know what's
going on in Turkey.
They know what's
going on in Marseille
with the Corsicans, and Palermo.
They know, and they've got
a list of over 115 names.
You can't be on that list.
I don't want you on that
list. You can't be on it.
What, are you... What,
are you a lawyer now?
No, I'm not a lawyer, but
I listen to the lawyers.
And they advise me
in their own way
what I can do, what I cannot do.
And that is something I
cannot do. It's a no-no.
It's a no-no.
This sfogliatella.
This sfogliatella,
it's like it's been here
for a hundred years.
All right, let's
talk about it later.
That's good, Benny.
Hey, who's that? Huh?
It's Anna Viggio.
She has the Zebra Club. That
joint over on 8th Street.
You mean the lesbian-gay joint?
- The after-hour joint?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
She stole it from her
husband during their divorce.
It was during the
war. You were away.
Who bought this?
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna take a walk home.
- Wait. Where you going?
- I'll see you soon.
I wanna say hello.
Hey, Benny.
- Take care of the lady?
- Absolutely.
You're not trying to
rob her or nothing?
- No, sir. I will. Yes.
- Gonna treat her right.
My name is Vito.
I know exactly who you are.
I don't know if that's
good or bad, but...
- I say it's good.
- Good.
What a melon.
You know how to
pick out a melon?
Yeah, no, it's gotta be hard.
If it's soft, it's not good.
You own that club?
The after-hours joint?
- I do.
- Yeah?
- You should come by one night.
- Maybe I will.
You know, I'll come
after you, you know,
make dinner for me
one day. One night.
You'll make it up.
My talk with
Vito at the candy store
fell on deaf
ears. No surprise.
You see, he just
ignored my warnings.
And he just kept making his
business bigger and bigger
and creating more
and more problems.
...come in, they
think they're going
to fucking Macy's or something.
Making signals like he's
fucking buying me ice cream.
You want me to go?
No, no, no. Stay here.
Don't do nothing.
I can't believe you
did this for me!
Oh, my God, this is gorgeous!
One of the
largest dope smuggling rings
of recent years is smashed.
- How do I look?
- Great. Don't run me over.
Seized heroin
and opium is the nucleus
of what would've been a flood
of narcotics worth millions
on the national drug market.
The illicit narcotics were
smuggled into the country
from Red China by
way of Hong Kong.
The thing
got bigger and bigger
just when the feds turned drugs
into public enemy number one.
And I stayed as far away
from him as I could.
To the queen of Queens.
I gave Vito Downtown,
from Greenwich Village
to Wall Street.
It had been running
nice and smooth
for years until he took over.
And then all of a sudden,
I start hearing about wars,
feuds, bodies turning
up in the street.
I didn't wanna be in town.
I spent more time
up in Sands Point.
Oh, what a surprise.
Money in the pocket.
I have a feeling I'm gonna
find more in the other pocket.
Oh, yes.
Honey, honey. One of these
days I'm gonna forget,
and the dry cleaner's
gonna be a rich man.
Hey, I know you. You
won't forget nothing.
I don't understand why you
have to use both pockets.
Because... The big roll...
it ruins the crease.
I use two rolls.
They're smaller.
One's for personal.
One's for business.
You know,
lending money is a great
way to lose your money.
And your friends.
Yeah, well, I got a trick.
Oh, yeah, sure. Just you.
- Another one of your tricks.
- Yeah.
- What I do is I...
- Mm-hmm.
When somebody new wants
to borrow money from me,
I drop another 100 in there.
Another 150, even two.
If they don't tell
me about it...
then I can't trust 'em. I
don't... What good are they?
My God.
- Right?
- You're brilliant.
You should run a bank.
Yeah. I do run a bank.
What happened
to Bobbie and Frank?
They had something to do.
Well, he had something to do.
So, they couldn't
make it, you know.
But now you got me
all to yourself.
- Well, that's good then.
- Right.
Well, maybe we can
do it another time.
Sure. Sure, yeah.
Though Frank told me he
had some business thing
he had to do and...
Bobbie, yeah, well...
Something, I don't
know, so... It's okay.
Do you like his wife?
His wife... Bobbie's nice. You
know, she's a very nice lady.
She's a little... different
type of person that...
She ain't like you.
- What does that mean?
- No, she's like...
She's a... She's
Jewish, she's...
Look, it's easy for me
to say what I think...
is going on between them,
but I... I know why...
I have a feeling why he
canceled. I know why.
You look disappointed.
I was a little disappointed
because Frank and I are old,
old friends and... So...
How long are you guys friends?
Long time. Long,
long, long time.
- Childhood?
- Huh?
- Since we were kids, yeah.
- Child...
Done a lot of crazy
things together.
You were probably
like a little monster
when you were a kid.
Well, you know...
- I was a...
- Tyrant.
Frank is a more reasonable
guy in a certain way.
He likes to be a little more
cautious in what he does,
and, to his benefit,
that's a good thing.
You know, he'll try and work
something out with people.
Me, I'm looking at it
like, "Do this or that."
- And that's it for me.
- Right.
I'm done. We're gone. We're
moving forward. Period.
But you're more...
"fly off the handle"?
Uh, can be, can be.
No filter when you speak?
He's... He changed ever
since he was with her.
But that happens, you know,
with people, and he's...
He don't come down
as much down here,
Downtown, so much, so...
sometimes forgets where
he comes from and what...
So, she keeps him
on that other side,
- which is, you know, not...
- Right.
You know what? I'm
glad he didn't come.
- Let's order a drink...
- Sure.
- ...and something to eat.
- I would love a martini.
Maybe she'll calm him down.
What are you talking
about? They're the same.
He's marrying himself.
Tonight's
guest is the head
of the new Federal
Bureau of Narcotics,
Commissioner Harry Anslinger.
It's a pleasure to be here, Vic.
Let me start by saying
that this country is
asleep at the switch
when it comes to the
growing drug menace
coming in from Europe.
The recent arrest of New York
drug kingpin Big John Ormento
by Commissioner Anslinger and
his drug enforcement agents
is just the beginning
of the fight
against an ever-increasing
drug menace.
Commissioner
Anslinger is...
- Tony.
- ...one of the very few...
- Here.
- Right.
...to take this
problem seriously.
We have to clean up our
city. We have to clean up...
Who's listening to this garbage?
Turn this fucking stuff
off. Turn that off.
- I got it.
- Yeah, change the station.
These hool...
There are always
guys looking to get ahead
by doing what they
think the boss wants.
And then they find
out they're wrong.
- Hey. How are ya?
- How are you doing?
Mr. Riesel, can I
have your autograph?
No, no, no. I can't, I can't.
Mr. Riesel, are you okay?
Victor, what happened?
And they always,
of course, bring heat.
Today, Victor
Riesel was released
from a New York hospital.
Doctors said that the sulfuric
acid had permanently blinded
the nationally respected
crime-fighting columnist.
Authorities are still
hunting for the suspect
who threw the acid
in Riesel's face.
Vito didn't
like no actions taken
without his authorization.
Otherwise, there
could be a problem.
Vito was born, really,
in a small town on the
side of Mount Vesuvius.
So what else could I tell you?
How do you warn somebody
who grew up on the
side of a volcano?
They're immune to warnings.
- What?
- He's here.
He's got the whole
neighborhood, he comes here.
Don't look. Don't look.
Don't look. Don't.
Don't. Don't, don't. Don't
make it obvious, come on.
- He lives here, Vito.
- I know. I see him.
I know. I see
him all the time.
I see him a little too much.
But what don't look right?
The guy has always
come here to eat.
He's not doing...
He's not doing
anything purposely.
What does he think?
He can just walk around and
act like nothing happened?
You got divorced. That's...
That's it. You're
not together anymore.
He saw we were here.
He walked in. He should've
turned around and walked out.
If we'd walked in,
he's already here,
that's something else.
But we were here first.
That don't look right.
- Come on. It's nothing.
- Hold on. Here he comes.
Hey.
- See you.
- Yeah.
- You want me to talk to him?
- Nah. No. Don't talk to him.
No, don't talk to him.
- Why not? I'll go.
- Don't talk to him.
- No, no, no.
- Vito.
I think you should let
it go. Just let it go.
I did let it go.
Forgot about it already.
Well, you don't
gotta worry about me.
What you talking about?
Gone. It's gone already.
Poof.
I'd look good in a
mink coat, honey.
Mm-hmm.
You'd look good in
a shower curtain.
Hey, Silvio.
- How are you?
- Hey.
I wanna talk with you for
a minute. Come downstairs.
We'll go to Marcuccio.
I'll buy you a drink.
We have somebody in common now.
- Wanna ask you some questions.
- Sure.
You cocksucking...
You wanna make me do that, you
fucking... Oh, no, no, huh?
You don't know to walk
out, you motherfucker?
You don't know to walk out?
...go around my wife.
You think you can do it
in front of me and
everybody else?
...walk around the fucking
neighborhood like that?
You make me look like
a fucking scumbag?
She's with me now, you
understand? With me.
Do you wanna walk along
the fucking neighborhood
and make me look like some
fucking piece of shit?
She's married to me! To me!
To me, to me, to me, to me!
The second guy was
some poor bastard
who went up there
for fresh air and...
well, was unlucky.
Everybody knew what happened.
The priests knew. Cops knew.
The whole neighborhood
knew. Everybody knew.
What are you gonna do?
What are you gonna say?
Between Anna and the feds,
nothing got better.
In the years after Vito
got rid of Anna's husband,
nothing was the same.
I'm standing out here like a
crazy woman with Frankie Boy.
You are such a
disappointment to me.
I thought you were my friend.
Fucking alienated in
the business. You...
This should never
happen to anybody.
Yeah... I know that you know.
And you and Frank are probably
having a good laugh
on my expense.
She can't call ten times a day.
Tomorrow, I'll
talk. But not now.
I know what to do.
To make matters worse,
Frankie Boy let Anna know
that Vito was skimming
money off the top.
That was a decision
that Frankie Boy
would come to regret.
You son of a bitch, Vito.
I knew you'd be here
taking my money.
Is this what you've
been doing, Vito?
I'm not taking everything.
I'm taking what comes to me.
For your what? Your
fucking whores?
Look at me when I talk to you.
Why don't you try respecting me?
Please, relax.
- Calm down.
- How's that?
- You're making a scene.
You mind your business
too. How's that?
- Mind your business.
- Okay. Anna, look at me.
You think I'm afraid of you?
- My fucking money.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- That's my fucking money.
- Come on. Hey. Hey.
Give me my money.
You son of a bitch. I'm
taking you to court.
- Anna. Hey, take it easy.
- I'm not lying!
The hell are
we gonna do about her?
This woman's crazy.
- You have nothing! It's mine!
- Anna, relax. Relax.
All right.
- Just breathe, Anna.
- He's a greedy fuck.
What's he doing?
Looks like he's
calming her down.
Calming her down?
"Calming her down"?
That don't look like
"calming her down" to me.
What do you think he's doing?
- He's calming her down.
- I don't know. I'm asking you.
Calming her down? That's
"calming her down"?
The guy's trying to help
us out here with her.
- It doesn't look to me...
- She's off her rocker.
I know that she's crazy,
but look at the...
Look how he's...
I think you're making
a big thing out of nothing.
I don't...
The guy is just trying to
help us out, that's all.
That ain't the way you
calm somebody down.
Just because
we're separated...
Anna.
...he wants to kick
me out of my own club.
Do you hear me?
This son of a bitch
motherfucker that he is.
He's fucking with
the wrong person.
I caught him in my fucking club
with his greedy, fat
fucking sausage fingers
in my register, taking my money.
- Anna? Anna...
- Let me tell you something.
Anna, I... I gotta go.
I'm gonna get more
than what he stole...
- That was Anna again.
- Yeah.
She is losing her mind, and
she is driving me crazy.
You have got to call Vito.
- You've got to talk to Vito.
- I can't talk to him.
You have to talk to him.
She just said that
she's threatening
to take him to court,
and she will do it.
I'm telling you, we
gotta stay out of it.
Let them work it out.
I'm sorry. I know.
It's too much.
It'll make it worse
if I call him.
Uh, don't bet on it.
Honey, I'm telling you
it would make it worse.
Just let it go for
now. Let it go.
Had I known
what was coming down the pipe
with Vito and Anna,
I would've spoken up more.
I would've said something.
But with Vito, he's
just too bullheaded.
You can't change his mind.
Vito, you'll be there.
What's my
wife got to do...
What are you talking
to her now for?
Are you a marriage counselor?
Vito, she calls
Bobbie ten times a day.
What are we supposed to
do? Not answer the phone?
Not do nothing?
What can we do?
That, I'm sorry about.
But listen, she's...
she's okay. She's excited.
Well, I mean, she's nervous.
What are you gonna do?
It's nothing. It's fine.
This man took
over my business,
and he is trying to destroy me.
He says he's broke. He's not.
He is a millionaire
many times over.
He gets thousands.
Thousands in tax-free
money every week.
I had 24-carat gold
and platinum dishes.
My silverware was the
best that money can buy.
Every weekend we
would have parties.
Twenty-five to 30
people would show up.
We would hire entertainers
from New York.
I had 30 gowns upstairs
in my walk-in closet.
So, no matter what he says,
believe me, Your Honor,
he's got the money.
He's got after-hour clubs
in Greenwich Village.
He's got dog tracks in Virginia.
Who has a dog track?
He gets paper bags filled
with money delivered to him.
Every week.
And believe me, Your
Honor, I know. I saw it.
And let me tell you something,
as crazy as this sounds,
I still love him.
I know.
I sound crazy.
But if he wanted me
back, I'd go back today.
That's the truth.
I even reached out to his
good friend Frank Costello,
who is a very important
man in this city.
And he has a lot of
influence with my husband.
What happened?
Frank spoke to him,
and-and even that didn't work.
So, you know, I
don't what to say.
He didn't even listen
to Frank Costello,
and they know each other
since they're kids.
He didn't even listen to Frank.
How is this possible?
I can't believe she
mentioned your name in court.
If he just gave her the money,
they wouldn't even
be in court. I...
If I gave 'em the
money, it would be good.
- But I couldn't, God forbid.
- It's not about the money.
He treated her like
a piece of garbage.
That's what this is about.
She's a moron. He's a maniac.
And now you're on the
cover of the paper.
Just gotta weather the storm.
Judge, I have to
admit, this woman is a puzzle.
Big puzzle.
She lived with me as my wife,
and then she puts a knife
into me, Your Honor.
She testifies all around
that I'm a gangster.
That's when all my
troubles started.
I-I'm a homebody.
A devoted husband.
She says it herself.
I was shocked at my
wife's foul language.
In my opinion,
she's a sick woman
who's going through
a change of life
when she flew the coop.
I don't think she knew
what she was doing
or saying, Your Honor.
Were you unfaithful?
Honestly, Judge, look
at me. You see a Romeo?
Huh?
You've
been described as,
"The King of the Rackets."
- That's ridiculous.
- That you're a millionaire.
I wish.
Nice thought, Your
Honor, but wrong again.
My only income's as manager of
the Colonial Trading Company
on Washington Street.
We pick up scrap paper
from Manhattan offices.
I have my taxes.
I can prove it.
Every single word
that is coming out of
this man's mouth right now
is a complete lie.
Why don't you do us a
favor? Keep your mouth shut.
It'd be better.
- She's not in her right mind.
- I think you're crazy.
- Nah. Yeah, well, I'm crazy.
- You're crazy.
You're the actor.
You're acting right now for
this whole goddamn court.
- And they all know it.
- Ma'am.
- The best actor in the world.
- Please control yourself.
Better than Clark Gable.
He's sitting right here.
And I am brokenhearted
that I even gotta be here
begging for my money.
This is my hard-earned
money. Okay?
And he tried to take over
my whole entire business.
Can you collect yourself please?
That's what he does.
He gets his hands on everything.
- Right? That's what you do?
- Take a moment...
- Get your hands on everything.
- ...to collect yourself.
And then it becomes yours.
I don't know what
to say, Your Honor.
She's not in her
right mind, this lady.
He gives all his
money to the puttanes.
That's where they go, to
the dirty little whores.
That's where they
go. That's why...
Maybe you are broke.
- Ma'am.
- Maybe you are broke, Vito.
Because maybe you gave...
...all your money
to the whores.
Mrs. Genovese. Ma'am.
- Collect yourself.
- I don't know what to say.
This is now a circus
right now, with you.
You're a clown. Yeah?
You're not a gangster,
you're a clown.
You're a disappointment.
Vito invited
the local press...
Yeah, this is unbelievable.
He invited the local press
to a little house he bought
in Freehold, New Jersey,
to show the court he was
a regular working stiff.
Relax. Yeah, what'd
you guys expect?
A bunch of guys
with machine guns
all over the place?
You watch too many movies.
You listen to the cops too much.
I hope you guys are hungry.
I gotta make sure youse
all leave here very happy.
If you're not happy,
I'm not happy,
and then I'm gonna
get in trouble.
So you gotta write
nice things about me.
Your wife testified that you
were head of the lottery.
- The numbers racket?
- Yeah.
According to her
and everybody else,
I must be a man
with, like, 12 heads.
Besides the lottery, they
say I'm the head of this,
I'm the head of that...
I'm the head of everything.
But you know what? You
write what you want.
Couple of sausages for you.
After we eat, do
whatever youse want.
Give me the third degree.
Whatever youse want.
Hang on. Look at my closet.
I got five suits,
five pairs of shoes.
I haven't bought a new suit
in, I don't know, five years.
Yeah. Sorry, it's
a little dusty.
What'd you think?
I put it there yesterday
just to fool youse? Huh?
Come on. Look at my mansion
with the plasterboard walls.
Look at where I sleep.
That's where I sleep.
You think I'd be worried if
I'm so close to the window.
If there's a problem.
Worried about somebody come
and shoot me, huh? Nah.
I got nothing to worry about.
The bed's here, the
window's there. So what?
If I had something to hide,
I wouldn't have let
youse in the door.
Give me some credit. Come on.
We'll go in the other
rooms. Have a drink.
Vito got some
positive attention
in the newspapers
until the judge ruled
in Anna's favor.
She received the alimony and
control of the Zebra Club.
My Lord, that got
him fucking crazy.
He went nuts.
♪ Picture you upon my knee ♪
♪ Just tea for two
And two for tea ♪
♪ Me for you ♪
♪ You for me alone ♪
♪ Nobody near us To
see us or hear us ♪
♪ No friends or relations
Or weekend vacations ♪
♪ We won't have it known
We own a telephone, dear ♪
♪ Day will break
And you will awake ♪
♪ And I will bake A
little sugar cake ♪
♪ For me to take To
all the boys to see ♪
♪ We will raise a family ♪
♪ Can't you see How
happy we would be? ♪
Within a few months,
the repercussions of Anna
mentioning my association
with Vito in court proved
to be a disaster for me.
The headline identifies him
as quote, "Gambler
Frank Costello."
And even quotes him asking,
"What do they think
I am? Superman?"
Well, we don't
think he's Superman.
And in the light of
mob violence today
and the growing drug menace,
these hearings are to determine
how a man like Frank Costello,
a professional gambler
who has been convicted
of offenses ranging from assault
to carrying a loaded gun,
could still have enough
political connections
to nominate mayors,
judges and city officials,
leaving our cities vulnerable
to municipal corruption.
His name is even mentioned
as close confidant
of mobster Vito Genovese
in a family court case.
I think you
look good, Frank.
Looks, uh... You look regal.
Anyways, this is all, uh,
just political posturing.
Kefauver's running
for president.
He needs publicity.
He wants to get it
on your coattails.
That's a close picture.
I was worried you were
gonna look heavy. Kinda fat.
But you look good.
- No double chin.
- Oh, well, I...
Huh? No doub...
Well, you know...
I don't want your...
- Thanks for the compliment.
- Listen, you look regal.
- Huh?
- You look like royalty.
Yeah. Royalty.
So what does that
mean? What do you mean?
- What do you think?
- Easy. We go to court.
You plead the Fifth.
We go to lunch.
So just the Fifth. That's
what you're saying?
I've got a problem with that.
We should talk about it.
I'll pay, Frank. All
right? I'll buy you lunch.
That's... That's a
very tempting offer
in your new fancy office
that I helped to pay for.
But now we gotta keep
paying the rent, Frank,
so I need you to stay in check.
Yeah, yeah, I know. I
wanna keep you there.
I wanna keep you there, as...
As long as you keep
me out of trouble,
I can keep you there.
...of our program.
The appearance of our
mystery celebrity.
And since our experts over here
would recognize our
famous guest on sight,
we've provided them
with blindfolds.
Are all those blindfolds
in place, panel?
- Aye aye.
- Yeah!
Will you come
in, mystery challenger,
and sign in, please?
Now, you come over
here and sit down next to me.
Panel, as you know,
in the case of our
mystery celebrity,
we dispense with
the usual amenities
and get right down to
the general questioning.
Uh, let's begin the general
questioning with Miss Francis.
Are you in the
entertainment business?
No.
No. That's one down
- and nine to go.
- What? No?
Is that okay? That a senator
goes on a... on a game show?
Uh, I wanna see him talk
about his political pals
on the payroll
back in Tennessee.
Or the deputy sheriffs
who work as valet parkers
at the casinos on
their days off.
Let him talk about that.
You know so much.
You should have
your own hearings.
Yeah.
If I did, I wouldn't
be on What's My Line?
Are you in, uh,
federal politics?
Yes.
Are you at
present mixed up
in a very famous investigation?
Yes.
Uh, are you
on the right side
of this investigation?
- I hope so.
- Oh, that voice.
Are you
Senator Kefauver?
Yes. That's right.
I respectfully
decline to answer...
...your questions, on
the grounds that...
...my answer may tend
to incriminate me.
I respectfully decline to answer
on the grounds that my answer
may tend to incriminate...
...might tend to
incriminate me.
...my answer may tend
to incriminate me.
I respectfully decline to answer
on the grounds that my answer
may tend to incriminate me.
Chief Counsel Halley will
continue the questioning.
Mr. Profaci, are
you the president
of the Bella Mia
Olive Oil company
on 79th Street in Bensonhurst,
Brooklyn, New York City?
I refuse to answer
on the grounds that my answers
might tend to incriminate me.
Mr. Profaci, I'm asking
about your job title.
I refuse to answer
on the grounds that my answers
might tend to incriminate me.
You're listed as such
in the telephone book.
I refuse to answer on
the grounds that...
The phone book. At least
you can answer that.
I refuse to answer
on the grounds that my answers
might tend to incriminate me.
Okay, Mr. Profaci, let's
just... keep it simple. Okay?
How old are you?
I respectfully refuse to
answer on the grounds...
How can you
refuse to answer?
I'm asking about
your date of birth.
One thing can lead to another.
- Can you believe this?
- I can't.
I can't do that.
I can't do it.
Well, you got to.
Everybody's taking the Fifth.
Well, if I take
the Fifth, then...
who's gonna call
me back? Nobody.
There's certain
people I know that...
They're gonna be too afraid.
They won't take the chance.
Once I take the Fifth,
certain people are not
gonna wanna call me anymore.
They don't wanna be associated.
'Cause everybody knows only
guilty people take the Fifth.
You know that.
What do you want me to
tell the committee, Frank?
Tell 'em to save their
subpoena, George.
I'll testify voluntarily.
No. As your lawyer, I have to
advise against you testifying.
I'll admit I'm an ex-bootlegger.
I'll admit I did 11
months on a gun charge.
A misdemeanor. It was
over 30 years ago.
I mean, today I'm a
professional gambler.
I'm in real estate.
I give to charities.
- I pay my taxes.
- Yeah. I know.
What are they gonna
ask? That's all I know.
This isn't Tammany Hall, Frank.
This is a panel
of United States senators
up there. All right?
And they didn't all go on
What's My Line? last week.
They're all a bunch of
politicians, George.
Stuff a couple of
dollars in their pocket,
they go away, you know?
It's just how much.
Two dollars, ten dollars, 50
dollars, thousand dollars.
It's the same
thing. They want...
You can pay them
off in a second.
All right.
I'll just tell 'em
I know nothing.
Ladies
and gentlemen,
while this is the nation's
first televised
congressional hearing,
Mr. Costello has
agreed to appear
and testify voluntarily.
Therefore, to
secure his privacy,
the live television broadcast
cameras will refrain
from photographing
Mr. Costello's face
during his testimony.
Mr. Halley.
- Is it?
- It's live.
Have you ever been
known by any name
other than "Frank Costello"?
Like, "Francesco Castiglia"?
Castiglia was a family name.
My mother's name was Saverio.
Fucking uses his hands.
They're showing the kind
of cigarettes he smokes.
What's this, a
cigarette commercial?
You know, a lot of
foreign-born people,
when they came to America,
they used the family name.
When I was growing up,
I might've used it.
You're not using
the English language
when you say, "Might
have used them."
"Might have" means
nothing grammatically.
Well, I'm sorry, Mr. Halley.
I'm not a college man like you.
You were
a bootlegger.
- Correct?
- Yes, I was.
Just about every
person in this country
who took a drink
during those times
was in business with me.
Take the fucking
Fifth, you fucking...
F-Frank.
What's the fucking
matter with him?
I believe you're acquainted
with a man named John Ormento.
I am acquainted with him, yes.
Are you aware
that John Ormento was
recently convicted
of a narcotics conspiracy
and is facing life in prison?
I haven't paid that
much attention.
Talking about things he
shouldn't be talking about.
Have you paid attention
to the growing danger
of narcotics in this country?
Where are you go... What,
are you fucking stunad?
What's the matter with you?
Fucking crazy.
- He getting me all excited.
- I know.
Take the
Fifth. Take the Fifth!
I've paid
enough attention to know
that it's a low and filthy
business that trades in misery
and that we should
rid ourselves of it.
Coming out against drugs is
very noble, Mr. Costello.
Upstanding citizen.
Mr. Legitimate.
Get the fuck outta here.
But how
do we rid ourselves
of that other social vice?
The one in which
you are involved?
Illegal gambling.
Well, to do
that, Mr. Halley,
you'd have to burn
all the tracks
and shoot all the horses.
You may think this is
funny, Mr. Costello,
but the two great enemies
within our ranks today are
criminals and Communists.
Oh, another thieving bastard.
Another fucking...
They're the same thing.
The same bunch of
fucking crooks.
- Let me ask you, Mr. Costello.
- All thieves.
Why did you even want to
be an American citizen?
Why?
Well, 'cause I
love this country.
Why'd you wanna become
an American citizen?
Yeah. Yeah.
But you were born here
15 generations ago.
Didn't their grandfathers,
their great-grandfathers,
their great-great-great-great
grandfathers...
They were robbing
way before we ever...
They robbed everybody.
Now they get all
high and mighty.
From the time you
became a citizen,
what have you done
for this country?
I paid my tax.
Can you remember
meeting Mayor William
O'Dwyer at your apartment
with some judges and the
leaders of Tammany Hall?
- Uh-oh, here we go.
- Okay, O'Dwyer.
O'Dwyer.
Oh, Frank, I can't believe this.
This would have
been during the war.
I've had a lot of
people at the apartment.
When Mayor
O'Dwyer was still
the Brooklyn district attorney.
When he was prosecuting
Albert Anastasia
of Murder, Incorporated.
Was he at your apartment
during that period?
They got him. They got him.
I'm sorry.
Counselor, can I have
a glass of water?
- I have a throat infection.
- Go right ahead, sir.
You've got a fucking
throat infection?
You've got a big fucking
mouth. And you're stuck.
You don't know what the
fuck to do with yourself.
We simply want
to know, Mr. Costello,
how many times Mayor O'Dwyer
was at your apartment
while he was still the
Brooklyn district attorney.
Was it once? Twice? Ten times?
Most importantly,
why was he there?
He can't get out
of this. He can't get out.
Shut up, you stool
pigeon bastard.
He can't get out of that.
Were the
meetings at your apartment
to get O'Dwyer Tammany's
support for mayor
and to get him to
stop his prosecution
of Albert Anastasia and
Murder, Incorporated?
Yes or no?
You don't know what the
fuck to do with yourself.
What the fuck are
you doing? The Fifth!
He's in the crapper now.
What are you gonna
do? He's right.
They got him.
You opened up the door, and
they're fucking storming in.
These fucking
Protestant bastards.
Yeah, you
don't have to answer.
Uh, Mr. Chairman, since my
client volunteered to testify,
uh, could he return tomorrow
to better answer all
of your questions?
No.
Mr. Chairman, in
order to get at the truth,
we need this witness to
answer these questions now
while he is still under oath
and unable to refresh his memory
with other potential witnesses.
The witness will continue.
How many times did you meet
O'Dwyer at your apartment?
Mr. Chairman, I
testified voluntarily.
I would appreciate it if
I could come back tomorrow
when I'm feeling better.
You don't get to choose.
You don't get to
choose. He's right.
Who volunteers?
Cheech has lost
his fucking mind!
No, you shouldn't
be fucking there.
You should be taking the Fifth.
Take the fucking Fifth!
What's the matter
with you? Frank, jeez.
Frank, what is the
fucking matter with you?
Am I a defendant?
No.
Is this a court of law?
Am I under arrest?
You are not.
Well, then, I'm walking out.
Walk. Good.
Now finally he walks.
Do not walk out on a
congressional hearing.
That is contempt of Congress.
You are risking arrest.
- Hey, Frank!
- Mr. Costello!
I tell you, there's something
to think about in America.
I wanna make
sure that you...
- Choke, you fuck.
- He walked.
Well,
he had to walk.
They were gonna ask him about
what'd he do with O'Dwyer.
He had to walk out.
It's the politics. What
Frank did for Albert.
Of course they're after that.
Whatever he did should
stay in this fucking room,
not on television.
You know, O'Dwyer was sending
everybody to the chair.
- Yeah.
- Remember?
And Albert was next.
But before the trial
was gonna begin,
O'Dwyer, he quits the
DA to run for mayor.
Out of nowhere, right?
- Joey, right?
- Come on.
Who's kidding who?
O'Dwyer's an ex-cop.
He's got no money,
no connections.
He's got nothing.
Now all of a sudden
he's running for mayor
with Tammany Hall
backing him up. Come on.
And that was
Frank who set him up.
Vito, they're looking to find
out his political connection.
They want to know if
this is what they want.
- This is what they're after.
- I see that.
Especially after
Reles went out the window.
Because O'Dwyer had Reles
thrown out the window,
next thing you know,
Frank's taking care of him.
You remember he went out
the sixth-story window?
While he's being
watched around the clock
by O'Dwyer's own cops.
Now, you can... What does
that tell youse, right?
He threw Abe Reles
out the window
because O'Dwyer was
helping out Frank, right?
And the cops
said... the cops said,
"Reles tried to escape."
Who climbs out of a
sixth-story window
with a five-foot
bedsheet?
- I mean...
- That's right.
Right. You... Right.
You believe that bullshit?
O'Dwyer? I didn't
believe nothing
until O'Dwyer got
sworn in as mayor.
What does
that tell you, Vito?
- He saved Albert's ass.
- Yeah.
So what do you
think it tells me?
Frank's got a lot of pull,
politically, you know?
I'm telling you.
If he could fix that
thing for Albert,
what does that tell you?
- All right.
- Frank's got muscle.
What does that tell you
about Cheech's
political connections?
That's the point.
Got a mayor
elected, for Christ's sakes.
One of the
downsides of the hearings
is that they exposed
Anastasia's connection
and allegiance to me.
And knowing Vito,
hmm, that's a no-no.
He's not gonna like that.
["Money"
I was
heading to a sit-down
with Vito at the Waldorf.
And my frustrations with
him was at a boiling point.
I mean, I did 14 months
for contempt of Congress.
None of that would've
ever come about
without Anna mentioning
this close relationship
that me and Vito had at
the family court hearing.
I was a mobster once again in
the minds of many. Too many.
Now, all Vito had to
do was pay her off.
That's all he had
to do. End of story.
And Vito's downtown
brutal tactics
were causing all kinds
of problems for us.
Not to mention his continual
involvement in the drug thing,
which I feared was about
to blow up in our faces
and take us all down.
I was angry. I was
frustrated with him,
and I needed to stop him doing
these fucking crazy things.
So, what's up?
Well, where do I start?
With the feds looking
to put you away...
This is what I'm here
for? Why I'm here? Huh?
To talk about this?
I warned you about them.
Look what's happened.
I was very patient
the last time.
I talked to you about that.
What'd you do? Nothing.
Where'd it get me?
You are gonna take us all down.
How simple do I gotta make it?
I waited for you.
I waited for you to get
me back where I was.
To straighten me
out the right way.
What'd you do? Nothing.
- Nothing.
- All right.
You made me look like some
kind of fucking morto di fame.
What the fuck? Frank.
Vito. Vito, it's just
a matter of time.
You're going down a
very dangerous road,
and you know that.
And we ain't been down
dangerous roads before?
All of a sudden, we can't
go down dangerous roads?
This is a road that
I'm not going down,
because you're gonna
take us all down.
This is not the way.
You know that it's
just a matter of time.
You're gonna get pinched.
You got away with
two murders already.
They're looking to get
you. They're gonna get you.
They will get you.
You know that.
You didn't wanna listen to
me. You went your own way.
But you gotta know this
is gonna fucking blow up.
Let's remember something. I
put you where you are today.
It's because of
me. Because of me.
And if I were you,
I would okay this
because this is too big.
I gotta tell you, it's too big.
Nobody wants to get pinched,
but that's the risk you take.
- Me? I take that risk.
- But you're not where I am.
You're not where I am.
And I'm not okaying this, and...
You-You can't keep this
up. They're onto you.
How many times do
I gotta say that?
It's just
a matter of time.
You got those two
murders already.
That was the risk you took.
Look where it got you.
You gave it to me.
That was your risk
that you took.
You went on the lam to
Italy. For a long time.
That's why you're
not where I am.
Because you're out of control.
You're a loose cannon.
You're a fucking drunken cowboy.
- What are you doing?
- Mr. Legitimate.
Mr. Good Citizen.
Mr. Fundraiser.
With all that bullshit
good citizen stuff.
You think they ain't
gonna get you too? Huh?
You wanna be involved in
charities and all that stuff?
That's very nice, Cheech.
But don't forget,
you're a racketeer,
you're a gangster. Come on.
What are we talking about?
You don't wanna be
involved with junk
because of the
time you might get?
You're worried about
getting caught?
You already got caught.
You didn't wanna take the
Fifth, and what happened?
You got 18 months.
- Eighteen months.
- Fourteen.
Yeah. Fourteen,
18, same thing.
And what did we get? Nothing.
We took the Fifth and
kept our mouths shut.
And that's why they created
the Fifth for people like us.
And now, I bet you're gonna
be a legitimate citizen
like these fucking
racketeer senators
on those fucking committees.
You wanna be like them? Come
on. You ain't like them.
They're strange people.
They're... They're... They're...
They're from another planet.
And they own this
fucking country.
They're bigger gangsters
than we ever could be,
and you know that.
And you got this
throat infection?
What's with this throat
infection, huh?
What's all that about, huh?
You tried to talk your
way out of something
you can never talk
your way out of.
All of a sudden you want
to be half in, half out,
half a racketeer.
You can't have it both ways.
You're either in or you're out.
And whether you're
half in or half out,
that don't mean you ain't
gonna get caught the same way
I could get caught
or I could go down.
It's the same thing.
Come on. Don't be naive.
We don't control this,
somebody else does.
And then where the fuck are we?
Way down the ladder.
And I'm telling you,
that can't happen.
You know that.
It can't happen.
Vito, Vito, Vito, listen to me
because this is
a death sentence.
It's a big, big mistake.
Look, you do what you want.
You want to be a diplomat?
That's your business.
Me? I'm a gangster.
I'm a racketeer. That's it.
That's it. That's the life.
We had
reached a blockade.
I could see that
there was no way
I was ever gonna change
Vito's mind ever. Ever.
But the fact that he
would try to kill me?
Never, never did
that enter my mind.
I take
out. I don't put in.
I take out. I don't put in.
This one's
for you, Frank.
Louis Prima
and Keely Smith, everybody!
...gotta do some
stuff at the apartment.
...seen who shot you.
He was standing right there.
What happens now?
I got the message.
You want company?
Oh, yeah. Look what happened.
It's Mandy.
- Mandy surprised me.
- Yeah.
He made them from leftover
mink from the shop.
- Very nice. Yeah.
- Aren't they gorgeous? Okay.
Very thoughtful. You
want me to take them?
Yeah. Take 'em
for a little walk.
- All right.
- Do you want me to come?
No, they'll be fine.
We won't be long.
It's a little chilly out,
but they won't take long.
I'm... I'm not talking
about the dogs.
Okay.
Vito knows you wanna quit?
Course he does. That's
all he ever wanted.
That's it. Don't
worry about it.
Good.
'Cause that's what
I've wanted for years.
I know, I know, I
know. It's okay.
Be safe.
Come on.
Come on,
already. Come on.
All right, you ready?
I'm opening the
door. Let's go.
Let's go, come on.
As I was walking
through the park,
I realized a weight was
lifted off my shoulders.
I sent Richie Boy
to talk with Vito
to tell him I was stepping away.
That's it. I'm out.
And the commission,
they can sort out the
problems with Vito.
Me? I'm just gonna relax.
Travel and enjoy the remaining
years of my life with Bobbie.
Look what she does.
She makes me put
these coats on 'em.
- They're adorable.
- 'Cause they're cold.
- This guy.
- Yeah.
- That's a... Well...
They got a better
life than we do.
Believe it.
No arguments.
So what did he say?
Vito doesn't believe you.
I mean, it's ridiculous.
I don't know why he
wouldn't believe me.
Well... I mean, I know him.
I know what you're
saying, of course.
This is what... This is
the problem with this guy.
He came home. He
doesn't trust you.
He took a shot at you
without authorization.
What's gonna stop him from
taking another shot at you
without authorization?
You gotta convince him
that you really wanna quit.
Yeah, yeah. But...
You know what?
Tell him to make the
kid turn himself in.
Huh?
Tell Vito to make
Vincent turn himself in.
- Are you serious?
- I'm serious.
You know there's a
manhunt out for him.
So what?
He turns himself in,
I swear he's not the
person who shot me.
What are they gonna do?
I'm their main witness.
That's it. Case closed.
'Cause that's about
as solid as it can be.
I mean, I don't finger the kid.
That's it. He walks.
Everybody's...
Everybody's okay.
Kid goes home. Vito
takes over, finally.
I'm outta here. I'm
retired. That's it.
That's it.
Take that back to them.
And make sure that
Vito makes sure
that the kid brings a
bondsman with him too,
besides his lawyer,
and that the cops know when
and where exactly
they're gonna meet
so there's no fuck-up.
Okay, I'll bring it to
him and get back to you.
All right.
It's a nice day.
Little chilly. It's
too cold for the dogs.
Dogs got the life.
Look at... Here.
Put 'em in coats.
I'm afraid I'm gonna get robbed.
I'm walking in the park,
somebody gonna steal the...
...not only the coats,
but the dogs too.
She'll kill me. I'll
never be able to go home.
Oh, God.
That's all Bobbie
needs for me to do.
It's these damn dogs.
Everything is them.
- Yeah. Listen...
- You know.
They're our children.
- Look at that dog.
- Yeah.
Okay, good.
- Hey, Cheech.
- Hey.
- Hey. Yeah.
Let me see this.
Look what that
animal did to you.
- What are these?
- Some flowers.
Those are for you.
- For me?
- Sure.
That's so nice of you.
Gee. Al.
- So you're walking away?
- Yep.
You okayed the kid coming back?
Yep. Yeah.
You know, for me,
Albert, it's...
I don't want no more surprises.
Jesus Christ, Frank.
You can't walk away.
It's over. I don't...
I gotta...
Can't be over. What
he did was wrong.
I know it was wrong.
But so what? Sit down.
It does matter.
He went against
the rules. Okay?
I mean, without the rules,
it's just cowboys and
Indians out there.
The rules aren't around anymore.
It's different now.
It's a different time.
Maybe it's different for
you. Not different for me.
For me, it still matters
what that cocksucker did.
Let me take him out.
Problem solved. Then
back to nice and orderly.
Your way of doing business.
Look. Look...
Nothing happened.
I didn't get
killed. He missed.
I'm here, I'm talking.
It's all right. It's
all right. It...
I don't want to get killed
for something that I
don't want no more.
What are you talking about?
If anybody's gonna get
killed, it's not gonna be you.
No. I don't want
nobody killed.
Come on.
I don't want nobody killed.
Okay?
Okay.
Listen, you take care of
that lump on your head.
All right.
I'll take care of
everything else.
And until I get this
straightened out,
start carrying a piece.
Thanks
for the flowers.
I'll see you out.
- Hi.
- That was Albert?
Yeah, he just came by to see me.
Say hello, see how
I'm doing. That's all.
He brought flowers.
That was nice of him.
- Are you all right?
- Everything's fine.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
Please,
Albert. Before we start,
I know you're asking questions.
It's been discussed.
What are you talking about?
What's
done is done.
It's being considered
as an internal thing
within their own family.
It's for Frank and
Vito to decide.
And nobody else.
The man went against
his own boss.
Frank's only the boss
because Vito gave it to him.
You remember that, Albert.
It's not like Vito wasn't
the boss before Frank.
Right?
Plus, Richie says Frank agreed
to walk away on his own.
- Right?
- You gotta respect that.
Yeah, well, Frank
agreed to too much.
Jesus Christ. After
what happened,
I shouldn't even have
to ask for an okay.
But it's none of our business.
You're getting involved
where it's not necessary.
It's for their own
family to decide.
Not to me.
To me, it's black-and-white.
The man took a shot
at his own boss.
- That's a death sentence.
- Albert. Please.
Nobody died here.
Nobody has to rush
into anything.
If Vito doesn't know what
he fucking did was wrong,
then Vito doesn't
know a goddamn thing.
- Come on. Come on.
- Albert.
Hey, just stop.
- Be calm, all right?
- Calm?
And what, are you all stupid?
You don't nip this in the bud,
who's to say one of your
own won't come after you?
You let him get away with this,
it's a green light
for everybody.
Enough. Enough.
We already voted.
Richie said Frank himself
voted with the three of us.
That's it.
The four of us against
the one of you.
That's the rules.
- If you want your rules.
- Yeah?
And nobody's made a move
on a boss until last week.
Until last week!
Somebody made a move on a boss!
Tell me I'm wrong.
Go ahead, come on. Tell me.
Tell me. Tell me I'm wrong.
After what he did, I
don't even need an okay.
You make a move on a boss,
it's an open contract.
And every one of you know it.
You...
Albert, get
back here. Get back here.
Where
are you going?
Can you believe
this is a big hit?
- Times are changing.
- Yeah.
You've been sitting in
front of this TV all day.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah. I'm just... I'm
practicing early retirement.
I wish.
We
interrupt this broadcast
with a special news bulletin.
Vincent Gigante, the
28-year-old fugitive gunman
wanted for questioning
in connection
with last month's botched
assassination attempt
of New York's alleged
crime boss Frank Costello,
has turned himself in.
We now return you to your
regularly scheduled program.
You knew.
I hoped.
He'll be in charge?
Well, that's the point.
You trust him?
This is everything
he's ever wanted.
Well, he's gotten
everything he wanted before.
Yeah, well...
that was love.
This is business.
Mr. Keith, I'm pointing
directly to the defendant.
A Mr. Vincent Gigante.
Is that the man you encountered
the day Mr. Costello was shot?
I-I can't say for sure.
You identified him to
the police that night.
Yeah, but he looks
different now.
Are you having difficulty
identifying the defendant?
Yes, that's right.
Is it true that you are
legally blind in the right eye
and severely impaired
in the other?
- One or two?
- Two.
That's what my doctor said.
May I respectfully offer
Mr. Keith's ophthalmologist
report to the court?
- One or two?
- Two.
Can you at least
admit someone shot you?
Yes.
- He tried to take your life.
- Yes.
He called out your name.
Yes.
You were approximately
six feet away from him.
Then how could you
not have seen him?
My head was turned.
We find the
defendant, Vincent Gigante,
not guilty on all charges.
We'd like to thank the
jurors for your service.
The jury is dismissed.
I don't know what to say, Frank.
- Thank you.
- Okay, kid. Don't worry.
You're a good man,
Frank. Thank you.
- You shook his hand.
- So what?
He tried to ki... He
tried to kill you, Frank.
He's just a messenger,
George. Come on.
Hey.
- He did the right thing, huh?
- Hey, come here. Come here.
Vincent, what
are you talking about?
Did what right? What right?
"Did the right thing."
What are you talking about?
He did the right
thing for himself.
What are you talking
about? "The right thing."
Yeah, sure, but I'm still...
I'm outside, you know.
You're outside.
You're walking. You're
still walking around.
You know who else is
still walking around? Huh?
Who else? Huh? Huh?
Keep your mouth shut.
Who else is still
walking around, huh?
Yeah, all right.
With Vinny free,
my retirement looked good.
If only I could
keep Albert quiet
until Vito got picked
up for trafficking.
We have
plenty of coffee
for anyone who wants a refill.
We're gonna be in
the other room.
Let's go on in.
So, I'm gonna need a favor.
Anything.
Not that.
What?
I need you to go somewhere.
Me?
Yeah, sure, just me.
And where am I supposed to go?
- Cuba.
- What are you talking about?
The feds are onto Vito
with the narcotics thing,
so there's gonna
be a grand jury.
You're gonna be on
that witness list.
Goddamn it.
Goddamn it, I knew it.
I told you that fucking peddler
was gonna fuck things
up for everybody.
You know about
Albert going to Cuba?
- Yeah, that's what I hear.
- Yeah.
Why's he going there?
You didn't hear?
You didn't know?
Nah.
I...
Everybody knew. I
just assumed you knew.
Well, why's he going to Cuba?
That's why you gotta be away.
No extradition. No subpoena.
No grand jury. Nothing
where there's...
The only place is Havana.
You're serious?
You can do everything down there
the way you do it over here.
There's gonna be no
problem with that.
That can be worked out.
You want me to move
all the way to Cuba?
It's a 35-minute
plane ride from Miami.
Hey, it's nothing. It's...
The important thing is that
you're out of the country.
You're a million miles
from the grand jury.
You understand?
Frank's getting
him out of the way
as an offering to you.
Well, to let you know
that he's giving
away his protection.
And what happens to you if
I'm all the way down there?
Me? I'm... I'm gonna retire.
I am retired. I'm
outta here. I'm gone.
I told you before that
it's... That's what it is.
I'm gonna go to Rome.
Have a nice dinner right
after I turn it over to him.
Yeah, well, why's he
sending him down there?
Well, where's he gonna send him?
I don't know. Why there?
Why-Why not Brazil?
Why not someplace further away
like where there's
an ocean between us?
Why's he sending him so close?
Well, Cuba's a nice place.
You never thought that Cuba
was more than just that?
- There's gambling down there.
- Yeah.
You never thought it might
be that? The gambling?
I mean, that's what I think.
He's up to something.
When he's getting indicted,
you're gonna be in Havana.
Uh-huh.
You're gonna be away
from all of this.
All right. Commission
is gonna be looking
for somebody to take over.
You know what I mean?
I told 'em you are the
best person for this.
Somebody like you who'll
play by the rules.
You do the right thing.
You're away in Havana,
you do your own business.
Low-key. Stay out of trouble.
You show them what
you're capable of.
I...
I proposed you.
You understand?
I vouched for you.
When do you want me to go?
Soon as you can.
He's looking to fuck
me. I'm telling you.
I don't know. I don't
see it that way.
He's looking to make me
look like a morto di fame.
- I know this guy.
- No. I don't think so.
I know Frank the way
you don't know him.
I know Frank. He's
up to something.
Tony...
There's something going on.
Okay, you can help.
You can help. Go ahead.
- Okay.
- How you doing, sir?
Hey, zingarella. Come here.
I'll be back soon, okay?
Make sure you take
care of your mother.
- Easy.
- Help her out. Okay, good.
All right, sweetheart.
I'm not gonna be too long.
- I'll see you, okay?
- I love you.
- Make sure they wrap that up.
- I will.
- Wrap it good.
- All right.
...batter's box.
Slightly open stance.
The outfield pulls
around the left for him.
The check to the runner,
the delivery, outside
with a curveball.
Ball one.
We gotta go.
So, the Milwaukee
fans who came here to cheer
are waiting now with
a little concern
as Bob Buhl has a little
trouble finding that plate.
Mantle with a big lead,
throw back to second.
The ball gets by Schoendienst
and goes out to center field.
As Mantle goes to get
up, Schoendienst spills
and the throw is to second
as Berra comes over.
He's safe, and
Mantle's safe at third.
Schoendienst calls for time.
The throw was on
the right-field side
of second base,
and as Schoendienst
went for the throw,
he was not able to...
Give me an hour.
Take your time.
There's no rush.
And it will be an
error charged to the pitcher,
allowing Mickey
Mantle to get to third
and Berra to get to first.
...to try and shut the door.
Infield drawn-in for the Braves.
Here's the 1-1 delivery.
Swings and hits a fly ball
deep into left-center field.
He falls down,
he drops the ball.
And here comes Mickey
Mantle in to score.
Aaron fell down...
Good.
Thank you, honey.
They're so good. Thank you.
And the fans are
oohing and aahing now
as what looked
like sure disaster
for the Braves recovered,
and a run comes home.
So it's a 2-nothing ball
game. New York leading.
The outfield straightaway.
Deep in the right
side of the infield
is Schoendienst and Adcock.
Pitch, slow grounder
to the right side.
Coming over for it is
Buhl. It's rolling. Foul.
Simpson and Buhl sort of
had a semi-collision in...
You're gonna
love our new house.
You're gonna be so happy.
Good boy.
Look
at your sister.
Covington in
left, Aaron in center,
Hazle in right.
Mathews at third,
Logan at short.
Schoendienst at second,
Adcock at first.
Look to the runner, the pitch.
Swung on, a bouncer
back to second.
Going over is Schoendienst.
He knocks the ball down.
Here comes Berra to the plate,
and the throw is coming in.
Thank you. Here...
I'll put them here.
...for New York.
As Harry Simpson
hits a high bouncer
back to the mound,
out over second base.
Schoendienst knocked it down.
Made a good play on the ball,
but not able to make a throw.
And coming home is Yogi Berra.
So, Simpson drives in a...
...swinging
that lumber.
Here's the 1-1 pitch to him.
All right.
All right, yeah.
I'll let you know
as soon as I hear anything.
What is it?
Albert.
He's gone. He's gone.
Oh, my God. What happened?
He listened to me.
Trusted what I said.
And he thought he was okay.
You can't blame yourself
for what other people do.
I gotta blame myself
for what I did.
Should I call Elsa?
Yeah, yeah. Just tell her...
Tell her I gotta figure
this out, and...
and get ready to
go to her mother's
in Toronto with the kids,
uh, right after the funeral.
I knew with Albert gone,
staying alive was a long shot.
But with Vito, I also knew
that a long shot was usually
the only shot you got.
So, I was gonna take it.
So I needed a plan.
But the big question
was, "What plan?"
I needed to find a
way to take Vito out,
but without it
coming back to me.
He loved you. He loved you.
We'll go in here.
Yeah, it's best
nobody overhears us.
Uh, good place
to be.
Nobody's listening.
So I gotta...
I don't know.
I should've seen it coming.
I don't know what...
What did
you expect from him?
A lot of people are afraid.
What they say, in front
of him or behind his back.
- You know Vito doesn't care.
- Yeah.
- He don't care about anything.
- I care.
'Cause I don't get out until
he gets in, so that's...
You're my main
concern right now.
Uh, it's like we're
back where we started.
Back on the street.
Back where we...
The whole thing.
Frank, he never left the street.
He's always been in the street.
Yeah.
He's got no class,
that guy. Please.
It's like we're...
Nobody learns anything.
Stomping around
like we're about to be extinct
dinosaurs...
We never even know when
we're dying. This is...
Anybody that goes against Vito,
he'll start a war.
He'll go against 'em.
You gotta do something.
Anything.
It's not your fault.
Who could have thought?
Who could have imagined?
- Never.
- In... In broad daylight.
In a barbershop. Who would
have thought of that?
Nobody.
- But you have to be brave.
- Okay.
- Right? You're brave.
- Yeah.
You've gotta be
brave for the kids.
You know what I wanna do? I
wanna whistle everybody in.
- What?
- I wanna have a... a meeting.
- We had it at my place.
- I know.
- They didn't go for it.
- Nah. That was the five of us.
I'm talking about everybody.
I'm talking about a
national commission.
There hasn't been a
commission meeting
in 30 years since Lucky.
Yeah, I know, I know. I know.
That's why I think
Vito might go for it.
'Cause he always
wants to do something
the way Lucky did it.
And this way, when
we have this meeting,
I turn it all over to him
in front of everybody.
I couldn't take it back
even if I wanted to.
Plus, you know,
once he's got it,
we have to do whatever he says.
- I know that.
- He's the boss.
And you know what
I'm talking about.
Rich, I know that.
But it's, for me,
what I have to do.
So all I'm saying...
I need you to set it up.
Would you do that?
Where do you wanna do it?
What about Joe
Barbara? He's a...
How's he doing?
Is he all right?
Barbara?
He's okay, Joe, he
had a heart thing.
But he's got a farm upstate.
Way upstate. Almost by Canada.
And he's got all
farms around him.
It's peaceful. It's quiet.
It's a perfect place.
Well, all right.
All right. Let's set that up.
- I'll set it up. Right there.
- Hopefully, if we can.
But I told you, everybody's
gotta listen to him.
I know.
He's gonna be the boss.
Even me, Frank.
You know what I'm talking about.
I didn't wanna
tell Richie Boy anything
because it was better for him
if he didn't know anything.
The less he knew, the better.
I bite my tongue. And
my wife, she shops.
She does this, she does
that. She plans every minute.
I like the Giants too.
I'm not always gonna bet on
the Giants is what I'm saying.
No people. Where's
all the people?
Back home, I go outside, I...
I see people. I talk to 'em.
Lot of trees.
Beautiful trees, but...
no people.
Okay. Oka... Yes.
Okay.
It's the doorman again.
He says that
Richie's been waiting
for so long that the
cops want him to leave.
All right. Well, tell
him I'll be right down.
Are you sure you have to go?
Yeah, I have to.
You'll only have
Richie with you.
That's all right.
It could be a trap.
Nah, nah. It's too
late for traps, honey.
I'm gonna be fine. You'll
see. It's all right.
Come on. What, are you...
What, are you nuts?
Course he's up to something.
I don't understand.
- This is different this time.
- What, did you forget?
He stole from me before.
He was my friend. He
knifed me in the back.
You say, "How could he
be up to something"?
That's all in the past.
This is different.
He takes
people for suckers.
He didn't take
you for a sucker.
He takes people
for suckers. Tony.
In-In all the time
since he's been shot,
what has he done? Tell me.
Nothing. That's
what he's done.
What does that tell you?
Nevertheless, I just want
you to watch him. That's all.
What's he gonna do?
How do I know what
he's gonna do...
He'll do something.
That, I know.
He thinks around
corners, this guy.
Just watch him.
I'm telling you, he's
not gonna try anything.
Well...
How do you know
what he's gonna do?
Me? What the hell do
I know? I don't know.
Well, yeah. How do you know?
You just said you
knew. I just heard you.
You ain't been talking to
him or nothing like that?
- Huh?
- You had no contact with him?
- I ain't been near the prick.
- With Frank?
All I'm saying is that,
without Albert,
he's got no bullets.
You'll have the upper hand.
We drive up, he kisses the ring,
you're the boss.
You're in charge.
And then, Vito, we do
whatever the fuck we want.
Yeah, that...
Well, that's...
We're gonna be late.
Oh.
Look. It's Palmyra.
- Huh.
- Palmyra?
- What about "Palmera"?
- "Palmyra."
"Palmyra."
"Palmera." Whatever.
- Palmyra, New York. It's...
- What happened?
What are you talking about?
It's where the
Mormons come from.
The Mormons are from Utah.
Everybody knows that.
They own Utah.
- Where do you get this stuff?
- Don't you know that?
No, I'm telling you. Palmyra.
Nah, nah, nah.
That's where they got started.
It's where the Mormons
found their gold bible.
It was buried up here.
That's how they started
the whole fucking religion.
All right, let me
get this straight.
The Mormons, they dug up
a gold bible in "Palmera,"
and then they stopped digging,
and then they moved the
covered wagons out to Utah
and started a religion in
the middle of the desert?
Ye... That's how they started
the whole fucking religion.
That's what
you're saying?
- That's what I know.
- That's what you know.
Well, you don't know nothing.
If somebody digs up a gold bible
in Palmyra or anywheres else,
they're gonna stay right there
and keep on digging, right?
- Right.
- Wouldn't you?
- Yeah, Vito...
- I know I would. Right?
Vito's right.
Keep looking for
more gold bibles.
Vito, nobody
gives a shit.
I'm trying
to be logical here.
Who's gonna leave a place
after they just
dug up a gold bible
and move all the way to the
middle of the fucking desert?
Who? Name me somebody
who's gonna do that.
Huh?
Well, I wouldn't. I wouldn't.
- Name me somebody.
- I'd stay there.
- Keep digging.
- Who, you? Me? Who?
- I don't know, the Mormons.
Never knows what
he's talking about.
Who's gonna do that?
You know what? I'm
gonna tell you who.
The same dumb motherfucker
who fucked up the only
thing he ever had to do
in his whole fucking life.
And now he's forcing
me, making me,
to have to lower myself
in front of that rat cocksucker
and beg for what's already mine.
Whoa, whoa.
- Tony. Tony, make him stop.
- Hey, Vito, Vito.
Stop. I'm gonna
bang into somebody.
You're gonna get
us all killed here.
You fucked it up.
Fuck the Mormons.
You're telling me about
gold bibles and Palmyra?
Shut the fuck up about bibles.
Learn how to shoot
straight, you dumb fuck.
Fucking bibles.
You had one fucking
bullet, you fucking missed.
Bang, bang. Bang, bang, bang.
Huh?
One, two, three,
four, five. Six.
Can you count?
The elevator door
was gonna open.
So what? So what? Somebody's
in there, bang, bang.
There you go.
What are we talking
about with you?
Jesus Christ.
Nobody gives a fuck
about the Mormons.
I'll give you fucking Palmyra,
you fucking knucklehead.
- Say something smart for once.
- Exactly.
Where do you get your
information from?
- Ma told me.
- "Ma told me."
It's stupid. I'm sure your
mother didn't tell you that.
She did tell me.
Forget about the
fucking Mormons.
Just get us over there.
Get us the fuck outta here.
We're driving to a
summit. It's your summit.
Relax. Enjoy it.
Everybody all right?
- Gentlemen, my wife Vickie.
- Hi. Hey.
We're so glad you could be here.
What a beautiful spread.
- That is Joseph Junior.
- Big son.
This is Ducks over here.
Say hello to Ducks.
- Hi.
- Hey, heard a lot about youse.
Help
yourself to the food.
There's so much
there. Eat it up.
Yeah. It looks
great. Great. Thank you.
Florida?
Miami?
When are you
gonna invite us down?
Whenever you want.
This guy
never invites us.
There's Tommy over
here. My wife Vickie.
Joe Barbara
was the biggest
booze distributor
upstate New York.
For years I was keeping
the State Liquor Authority
off his back.
It wouldn't take too much
just to send a bunch of nosy
state troopers down there
snooping around,
messing everything up.
So State Tax said they
wanted notification
of any activity, right?
Yeah. I know we all got
the Liquor Authority alert.
I counted 20 cars
going in McFall.
Big cars. Big trunks.
Could have been
Canadian contraband
in every one of 'em.
We've gotten several
anonymous tips
that untaxed liquors might be
coming down to Barbara's place
from Canada.
Yeah. Maybe you're
right about that.
I'm gonna go up McFall.
I'm gonna get some
plate numbers.
Cover me.
There's a place over
there. Let's get a coffee.
You had coffee not
too long ago, Frank.
Nah, let's get another coffee.
We'll stretch our
legs, take our time.
- We're never gonna get there.
- We're gonna get there.
We don't have to
be there on time.
If you say so.
- It's okay.
- Okay.
Slow, slow.
There it is. Route
17. Turn here.
I see it, I see it.
I'm not fucking blind.
Don't get him started.
Just make the turn.
I don't wanna
be there for too long.
- Are you serious?
- I told youse.
In and out. Hello,
goodbye. That's it.
I crown him. Then we're gone.
- Party's for you and him.
- I know him.
I don't want him to even
think I'm hanging around.
It's true.
The more you hang around
and start talking to people,
he's gonna think
you're up to something.
Exactly. Exactly.
You know, youse
grew up together.
Youse were kids together.
- You stole together.
- Yeah.
And now you come to this age,
and there's animosity
towards each other?
You know, we were... we did
so many things together.
When youse were kids,
it was different.
You know, you
trusted each other.
But now you're grown men,
and he doesn't trust you.
- He's dangerous.
- Yeah, I know.
This guy's a psychopath.
Yeah, and you gotta
watch what you say.
You gotta watch who
you shake hands with.
you kiss on the cheek.
He thinks it's a
conspiracy against him.
That's the problem
with those kinda guys.
You know, what
they're paranoid about
are exactly the
things that they do.
And that... Because they do it,
they think everybody
else will do it.
And those are the
ones you gotta watch.
Mm-hmm. You're right.
There it
is. McFall Road.
It's about time. I
thought we missed it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Slow down. Slow down.
Where are you going?
Not too fast. Not too
fast. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Not up the hill.
What are you doing?
You're gonna get stuck.
And how do I get out of the car
while at an angle over
here? What are you doing?
Back it down. Back it down.
Stop the car, we
get out and we walk.
Put it right
here. That's good.
I'll get
the door for you.
How do you fucking park?
What's the matter with you?
Vito.
- Hey.
- You look terrific.
- Good to see you.
My wife Vickie.
Joseph Junior.
Hey, Joe. Nice to meet you.
It's all fieldstone.
In the basement,
we got pine knots.
- The living room...
- What do you got?
Pine knots.
- Knotty pine.
- Knotty pine, that's right.
What, did you lose your mind?
The living room's 1,600
square feet all by itself.
Nice.
He insisted on pine paneling.
Yeah, wood. I get it.
Hey, Joseph, did you
check for the mud?
Yeah, Pa.
Go out back.
I don't want anybody
getting stuck in the mud.
I know. It's dry.
I checked this morning myself.
Good. Now, go check it
again. Go make sure.
I gotta do everything myself
around here, Vito. I'm sorry.
You're right.
It's the only way.
Ed, we received another
tip on contraband
coming down from New
York from Canada.
We traced the call
to a phone booth
in a bar in Detroit.
Caller's unknown.
10-4.
["Who's Your Little Who-Zis!"
Carl, Carl.
You're always hiding.
Come on, come on.
You're too big to hide.
You can't hide no more.
As payback
for setting up
the barbershop hit on Albert,
Gambino was made the new
boss of Albert's family.
Things are the way they're
supposed to be now.
- Where's Frank?
- He'll be here.
He said he didn't wanna
get here too early.
He said, uh, he didn't wanna
get in the way of anything.
You know Frank.
He said, "This
should be your day."
Always the diplomat.
Yeah.
This is your day.
We're so
happy for you, Vito.
Cops!
- What's going on?
- Pa, cops!
- What cops? Where?
- Wait, what is...
In the field where
you're parked.
They're taking down plates.
What are you talking about?
- I just saw them.
- No!
We were
taught as young kids,
as soon as you heard the word
"cops," you started running.
They spotted me.
They're gonna take off.
I don't know what the hell
they're running away for.
They must be up to something.
Let's get some
patrol cars up here.
Get their license
and registration.
10-4, uh,
I'll meet you over there
on Route 17 and McFall.
I am
putting on my party hat.
- Come on. Come on.
- All right.
- You gonna be okay?
- Yeah.
Damn it, Joey.
Go, you fat bastard.
You soft
fucking thing. Come on.
- Open the door. Come on.
- I-I can't find the keys.
- Let's go. Use your brains.
- You making me nervous.
Calm down.
Listen, you got a piece
on you, get rid of it.
- What are you doing? Come on.
- I don't understand.
Get it out of the car.
Must
be some accident.
Must be an accident.
Get rid of it. Throw
it out and let's go.
- Shit.
- Get it out of the mud!
It's not moving.
That's the
second car passed us.
Hold on. Yeah, let's hold on.
Look. "Apple Farms." Pull
off. Let's get some apples.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
Besides it's the fall,
it's the apple season.
They got some of the best
McIntosh and Granny Smith
apples in the world up here.
Come on, pull over.
I didn't know you were a farmer.
License and
registration, please.
What's going on, Officer?
Somebody rob a bank?
You guys all been
up to Mr. Barbara's?
What are you doing up there?
You know, we don't have to
answer that question. I mean...
But there's no problem.
I mean, Joe's been sick,
and we've come to wish
him a speedy recovery.
- That's all.
- Yeah.
- We're gonna be late.
- No.
I don't want to be late,
Frank. You want to be late.
Rich, you can't be
late. It's my party.
You're my guest.
You can't be late.
It's only fucking apples.
You want some?
Just hurry up, please.
These are good.
I'm gonna need to see some
identification. Please.
Thought you'd never ask.
Any of you guys
got police records?
The only question I'll
answer is how tall I am.
- How tall are you?
- 6'2".
Your license
says you're 5'8".
Okay. Lock me up.
Follow the officer's
instructions.
- Hi, sir.
- How you doin'?
Pull around the corner.
Hey! Hey, stop!
We're at the road, look.
There's a road. Come on.
Okay.
Maybe we could get
a cab or something.
Yeah. Wave a taxi,
Joe.
Okay? All right?
- Oh, son of a...
- We're pinched.
- Figlio di sega puttana.
- What is this?
Jesus Christ.
Hold it right there.
- What's the problem, Officer?
- We're hunters. We're hunters.
Frank, what's going on here?
Look at this. They
got the roads blocked.
- Yeah.
- Something happened over here.
Well, let's get through this.
We take our time.
Slow we go, slow
we go, you know?
Look.
- Mother of God, Frank, look.
- Yeah, yeah.
All the bosses.
What's going on, Frank?
My God, Frank.
There's Frank Zito and Joey Ida
from Philadelphia.
There's Nick Civella.
Santo Trafficante. Came
all the way from Havana.
Thinks
around corners, this guy.
Thinks around
corners, this guy.
Frank, what's happening here?
I don't know.
I wonder what's
going on. Yeah.
- Frank, thank God.
- Look at this.
They're not stopping us.
Look at this.
I don't believe this.
Thank God we were late, Frank.
I don't know, Frank.
Something don't seem right.
Frank...
what did you do?
Ed, I'm putting through
Sergeant Salerno.
NYPD Special Services.
10-4.
Yeah, great work, Sarge.
Uh, what does it look
like you got up there?
We don't know yet.
We don't even know why they
tried to take off on us.
They were
running all over the field.
Mobsters from all
over the country.
But I got 63 positive IDs.
Yeah, yeah. Great work.
But do you happen to have, um,
a Frank Costello on that list?
- Frank Costello, the big shot?
- That's the one.
- Wow.
- He's the boss of bosses.
He has to be there.
He was probably
running this meeting.
There is no way he's not there.
Uh, sorry. No
good. No Costello.
Sarge, you
gotta be kidding me.
He has to be up there somewhere.
Maybe he's using another name?
- What was that name?
- Castiglia.
Castiglia. Or a Frank Saverio?
He's gotta be there.
He's the boss of all of them.
Uh...
Sorry. No Castiglia,
and no Saverio.
- Do you need anything else?
- Doesn't make sense.
They figured it out pretty soon.
With all the licenses
and registrations
the troopers took,
they finally figured out
that the Mafia was a
nationwide crime organization.
Up to that time,
J. Edgar Hoover, FBI chief,
denied that organized
crime was nationwide.
But because of the
Apalachin thing,
all of a sudden everybody knew.
It was all over the papers.
So now he had to acknowledge it.
So he began to
prosecute everybody.
Like a bunch of dominoes, it
brought the whole thing down.
And I was very careful.
I left no fingerprints.
In fact, the only secret
today that remains unanswered
is how a bunch of uneducated
juvenile delinquent immigrants,
who didn't even speak
English when they got here,
managed to put together
a multi-billion dollar
national syndicate
without the cops or
politicians knowing about it.
Well, wait, the cops
and politicians,
of course they
did know about it.
We just paid 'em to
not know about it.
Let's go. Come on.
Vito got
to swank around
as the boss of bosses
for a couple of months
before the feds scooped him up.
Vito got 16 years
for the importation and
distribution of narcotics.
With so much publicity, nobody
got away scot-free. Nobody.
Today, except for some dribs
and drabs, it's all over.
Vito left Vincent in charge.
But by then, the poor guy had
to walk around in a bathrobe
pretending to be nuts
just to get outta
there... the legal thing.
Because he was
gonna get indicted.
It was unbelievable.
The...
That stupid bathrobe act
worked for about ten years
until he finally got
picked up, then sent away.
And then he just died in prison.
Even I ended up doing some time.
Stuff to do with income tax.
At one point I was
sent to Atlanta
where Vito was doing
his time for drugs.
Everybody knew what
had gone on between us.
And the warden didn't
want any wars breaking out
while the two of us
were there, so...
He was afraid some
hotheads might think
we were all still at war
and might make trouble.
Well,
it was nothing.
We were even in Atlanta
prison together.
Here we are, two old
guys sitting in a cell.
Just to keep the warden happy.
Vito knew I brought it all down
by calling for the
meeting up in Apalachin.
But by then, what's
the difference?
It was all over.
What could one do?
We talked about growing
up. About the old days.
It was nice.
I'm glad we got to talk.
Vito died in 1969.
In Springfield, Missouri,
Federal Prison Hospital.
Congestive heart failure.
And by the way,
when Anna died, she was
buried in Vito's mausoleum.
I guess Anna really
did love Vito.
Hard to believe, but
I guess it's true.
And Bobbie...
she got me one of these, uh...
This one. Slide projector.
But mostly, I enjoy
hanging around the house.
I breed roses. They're nice.
They're cheaper than horses,
and they smell better.
Next thing I know, Bobbie
enters me into a contest.
And I won first prize.
Or maybe she paid somebody off.
What do I know?
Bobbie was right.
Hey, I'm glad I
went. It was nice.
They were just flower people.
Didn't even know who I was.
And even if they did,
they sort of didn't care.
Yeah.
I mean, by the time we got here,
they had already killed
most of the Indians,
dug up the gold,
sucked up all the oil.
And for us, all that was left
was thirsty Americans,
crooked cops and politicians.
But we made the most of it.
It's a different
time now. It's...
And the Alto Knights?
Well, the Alto Knights...
Life goes on.
That's it.